<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 10:16:40 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 10:16:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.46</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week has been workshop planning and doing, and I’ve bloody loved it. Put me in front of a team and let me facilitate the session and I’m the happiest. 
Also, to top off a great week, my wife also appeared inside many newspapers these (and it’s been a heck of a week for news), showcasing her fantastic business she has worked so hard to go, from scratch and on her own. Cue the proud feelings and look of awe. The article appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesun.co.uk/money/22301224/savvy-mum-250000-5-sewing-machines/&quot;&gt;The Sun&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.express.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/1768186/side-hustle-success-money-making-business&quot;&gt;Daily Express&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leeds-live.co.uk/news/leeds-news/leeds-mum-two-grew-250000-26887972&quot;&gt;Leeds Live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We planned what we needed to deliver during alpha, and it was pretty intense, whilst it always feels an uphill challenge, I have been here so many times that it’s almost a script at this point. I tend to use the framework of the CDDO assessment as a guide and use that to keep the team keen, and the work honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led a UCD-led workshop around the as-is user experience, including risks, opportunities, and pain points, which was a first for many team members!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, I enjoy Mural, so getting back into mapping, strategising and facilitating is my thing.
I feel a full grip on the project, I might not need to know everything (and I am ok with that), but I know what needs doing when it needs doing and what it’ll end up being, which ensures I stay a lot more focused and also ensures the team that they will see value from the UCD team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Doing workshops remotely is a challenge, it’s certainly doable, but it isn’t accessible to all - a huge challenge to ensure everyone is heard, can even attend or just feels comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiredness, this week has been heavy in regards to workload - not all weeks are the same, but this one is heavy on the UCD team (as alpha should be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding time to do things outside of work, has owned me this week (not a huge issue), but my windowsill won’t paint its-self!
I am working on a project that might need to use maps, but finding good findings on maps is proving to be a tricky task, whilst we know they are drenched in accessibility issues, there isn’t much written about what is done/being done, so if you do know - shout me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Running through the first workshop face to face (in Birmingham) with the team and evaluating what we did, I am looking forward to doing the outputs and getting the future documents shaped (including doing a How Might We session with the pain points, risks etc gained from this week’s workshop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is not the first time I’ve read this article, but as a team (led by the brilliant Tom) we ran a How might we session, and if you need guidance on how we did this - look no further than this brilliant post by Ben Holliday.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/leading-service-design/asking-the-right-questions-to-frame-the-problem-4df95a317983&quot;&gt;Asking the right questions to frame the problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My film intake has halved whilst I’m in full-on work and dad mode (kids holidays last week!), but I am looking forward to working through my list of films, and maybe putting a web page live listing films and my short take reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/09/weeknotes-no46.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/06/09/weeknotes-no46.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.45</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The weather is sparkling, everyone’s mood is 100% brilliant and the BBQs are fully in motion.
Work is busy, deep in thought, deep in workshop planning and deep in reading documentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s get onto what the week was like, sharpies and Post it’s at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The sun is out, I’m averaging a bbq a day and spending evenings either in the garden or out and about locally surrounded by cows, sheep, green hills and just niceness&lt;br /&gt;
Did I mention I love Alpha, it really gives me a chance to build relationships and shape the team in their understanding AND value of UCD-led workshops, but more importantly, it allows me to throw outputs out there that people can use, rip apart and improve and get under-the-skin of the project - I am just a facilitator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the team has just been a joy, a really enjoyable experience. We’ve cheered each other on, asked questions, joined up working and given feedback to one another and it’s just worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have mentioned this before, but the community here at Defra is much different to other places, its a little smaller than what I’ve worked in, but a lot more togetherness and understanding of challenges AND there isn’t a lot of sugar coating issues/problems that we all know exist in the public sector (it’s the same everywhere!), and I just feel sharing wins and struggles and failures is the way forward and whilst doing that, cheering people on as they express this is amazing - a healthy COP (Community of Practice) experience and one that I always attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Knowing where to start, this is always tricky. Often it’s easiest to just start doing a handful of things to just get the ball rolling, and this project has been no different.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve run off in directions and realised, hold up - this is silo working and I’m not doing the best I can do with that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kickstarting the workshops, owning the problem and facilitating the team to be the best with outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it - a ton of workshopping and leading design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 08:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/weeknotes-no45.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/weeknotes-no45.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.44</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alpha has officially arrived for the team, what does this look like as an interaction designer?&lt;br /&gt; 
It means a lot of conversations with SMEs and my besties - the BA. Chewing their ear off, asking and asking and asking, and sometimes (all the time) listening.&lt;br /&gt;
Working closely with the design team (and wider), we are shaping something pretty special which should allow us to breeze through alpha with answers, solutions, experiments, failures and successes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s get onto what the week was like, sharpies and Post it’s at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The design team arrived! Working with my old pal Tom Adams (content designer) and the equally brilliant Zoe Popperwell (user researcher).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work starts this week, the project officially started Alpha and mural boards a-plenty have kicked off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this phase, I am leading the User Experience board, showcasing the journey from start to end (and what’s outside of this), including points of feelings, touchpoints and risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding my place has been interesting, I am always the quiet one when I first join (which if you have worked with me, you know doesn’t last) - but I find this time to understand, sit back and see the lay of the land and work out who I need to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting things in order, I know what needs to be done for the GDS assessment and using that as fuel to help shape what answers we need to find out, and finding the correct avenue of output to showcase this, again - it’s about finding out what stakeholders and team need to get things moving in the direction that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Showcasing outputs, I love it when the team sees the value of work done and can see why I am quiet (for now).
Structure, it’s always a bit wonky at the start - finding correct times for stand up and ensuring all attendance on meetings etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allowing my voice to be heard more, now I understand my place, reason and work needed, there ain’t no stopping me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m a huge Doom fan, the game is one of the best things I’ve ever played, and still is playable after all these 105 years it’s been around.&lt;br /&gt;
This documentary “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5wAo54DHDY0&amp;amp;t=4824s&quot;&gt;MyHouse.WAD - Inside Doom’s Most Terrifying Mod&lt;/a&gt;” was an incredible insight into a mad mad, game-breaking mod. &lt;br /&gt;
Watch it, it’s longgggg, but worth it if you did this kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am always on the ear-out for new things to listen to, learn and binge - my design collection of podcasts is extremely low - in fact, it’s almost zero. Please help me, I’ll take interviews, hot topics, hot takes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 08:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/22/weeknotes-no44.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/05/22/weeknotes-no44.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.43</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A short week, but plenty of learning to happen still whilst I wait for my other designers to on board and get their accounts all set up.&lt;br /&gt;
Shaping work is my priority this week, digesting the project from its inception to its current position and listening to everyone who is linked to the project to gain as much information as possible as quickly as possible.
My notes look like I’ve drank far too much coffee (I maybe have) but I always break the project down into chewable sections like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project breakdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem / What do we know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals:&lt;br /&gt;
- For digital&lt;br /&gt;
- For alpha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Findings from the discovery report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Functionality Requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing ideas (ideas feed from the discovery outputs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions for the wider team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s get onto what the week was like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The support from my line manager - Chris Hawker is great. The fact I can talk openly and not feel worried, and ask for help at any time at all is amazing, feeling really happy, settled and excited to be here.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve started to shape a mural board, that I probably won’t share - but it has scribbles from a mad IxD who is trying to gather as much data as possible from all the docs and make sense, I love the investigation part and understanding the why, when and how we tackle(d) the problem.&lt;br /&gt;
A show and tell showing what has happened and what is coming for my project was a great highlight, the project has plans, and it has a timeline that feels realistic and do-able, whilst I’m sure it will hit bumps in the road and possibly change and be challenged it is certainly on the right track.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing case studies for my past 2 projects (HMRC and NHS), I am so happy I kept notes during the project and screen grabs of things I can share, so keep an eye out for these!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to land myself 3 games for my dusty PS3:&lt;br /&gt;
Alien Colonial Marines (nowhere near as bad as people say, Assassins Creed - Blag Flag and the ultimate time robber - Red Dead Redemption, a really strong line-up and only cost about 4 quid overall!&lt;br /&gt;
#CES-FTW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Writing case studies is tough, providing information whilst not making the project sound as tough/toxic as it was. I do not want to alienate the place of work to provide a bad reputation which could lead to good designers not joining, it’s a toss-up between honest reporting and just keeping the case study purposely concentrated on the project. If people want to ask me about my experience with my places of work - please get in touch, more than happy to chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that isn’t discussed much is sorting out how to get paid when contracting, the spaghetti junction of dealing with your recruitment agency and umbrella company can be a minefield, but… I think I’m all settled. My tip: speak directly to your umbrella company and if possible, stick to the same one (I have recommendations)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to ex-colleagues from previous places of work is a little unsettling at the moment, people are having tough times out there, and whilst I am not their line manager, I still keep in touch and try to coach as much as possible, reminding people that “they are not their job” is an educational piece, and also “you do not control the output of the team” when you are pushing upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Launching a case study (I hope), I want to share the work we did at HMRC, I am so proud of what we ended up with and how, as a team, we worked together and got to a strong solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention it’s my birthday on Saturday? Strangely, I forgot you keep adding a 1 on after you reached 40, I just want to keep pretending I’m a 40-year-old man who collects retro games and consoles, plays games and listens to Screamo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For a while, I’ve been looking to eat better food and have been cooking things from scratch. Cooking is my go-to, to get away from digital and burn a couple of things (including fingers), but I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@EthanChlebowski&quot; title=&quot;watch Ethan on youtube&quot;&gt;Ethan Chlebowski&lt;/a&gt; a great help when shaping meals like salads, lunches etc, and he tends to cook on a budget too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week is retro heaven, but also retro gaming hell. I stumbled across a podcast that revisits old spectrum games (and by the looks of other platforms more recently), and the episode I’m linking to is &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/2TX7qxaVmLd14gNfDCIUny?si=ddfe6ed8d0d74d54&quot;&gt;Horace Goes Skiing&lt;/a&gt;, it turns out.. as in most cases when talking about the wonderful Spectrum - the game isn’t as great as my memory serves up. Damn it! If you remember the Spectrum and loved it (why the hell wouldn’t you love it), this podcast is a beauty!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 08:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/weeknotes-no43.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/weeknotes-no43.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.42</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a heck of a rollercoaster over the past 4 weeks, I went on leave (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Crs0k9qIel4/&quot; title=&quot;a link to my one photo of us in cape verde in Instagram&quot;&gt;hi Cape Verde&lt;/a&gt;) being informed my contract was 100% going to be renewed (spoiler.. nope), I then returned to find no renewal and suddenly contractless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Solle, out of the blue suddenly got in touch and upon returning from holiday, I found myself in a great chat and signing up for a really exciting opportunity with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-environment-food-rural-affairs&quot; title=&quot;a link to the GOV.UK page showing DEFRA&quot;&gt;Defra&lt;/a&gt; in a whirlwind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The onboarding at Defra is next level, it is completely stress-free. I have found myself with time to look around the intranet, and the project notes, all whilst setting up my accounts using “the other” (if you have worked within public sector.. you’ll know this adventure only too well) computer provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning about the new project I am on, it’s a really interesting assignment where I am leading the interaction design solution(s) within the alpha phase, and personally already learning about the climate effect and how that impacts investigations and reporting things like floods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The welcome at Defra was amazing, the community feels healthy and supportive and… it helps I’ve managed to work with a handful of them before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Usual things, nerves joining a new team, finding my place etc, slowly getting used to it though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After not working for 4 weeks, managing my coffee intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Getting deep into the discovery findings and working out what was found, what we could look at and start planning and prepping (even this early) a possible story for the user needs in regards to the alpha assessments that always seem to catch teams out (from my past experience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have a list of films that I want to watch (if you have any - &lt;a href=&quot;/contact.html&quot; title=&quot;link to my contact page to send me film recommendations&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!), all provided by my most film-obsessed friends who I know only deal in good 8/10 at least films. This week’s big one was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0042041/&quot; title=&quot;IMDB link to the film White Heat&quot;&gt;White Heat (1949)&lt;/a&gt;, James Cagney at his best, and his character at his worst. Worth a watch for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Revisted a band I have long loved, but not listened to for a while - Incubus. Great memories of going to see them at gigs and it’s still amazing that they are still going, handful of brilliant albums but &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/1rQZbncicoXyB64DqoH7OY&quot; title=&quot;Spotify link to Incubus Morning view album&quot;&gt;Morning View&lt;/a&gt; is an absolute banger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/09/weeknotes-no42.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/05/09/weeknotes-no42.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.41</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So it turns out my contract is in the midst of getting renewed or not, which I wasnt expecting, a different vibe, where im making sure things are working and left in great shape and hopefully a better service than when I found it!&lt;br /&gt;
If you are requiring an contract IxD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/contact.html&quot; title=&quot;get in touch and see if we can work together&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week has involved a lot of talking, answering design reasoning at speed - the kind of pressure I like!&lt;br /&gt;
Answering queries from the helpdesk, those on the frontline picking up calls from users who are either stuck and confused, or just annoyed - this feedback is crucial and worth a ton, but this isnt me saying this is the best way to get feedback (far from it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not knowing about my actual honest contract length, it feels a situation I should not really find myself in after initially being told I was in work till August, but here I am - currently contractless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensuring the prototype is up to date, working and something that the next designer could use (if replaced), whilst the prototype is now in great shape - it’s just a shame it’s going this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I find myself with some time off now (unexpectantly), to plan my next project whilst also going on holiday so it’s not all doom and gloom!&lt;br /&gt;
BUT the doom and gloom could mean that I will be decorating my daughters bedroom and I-aint-no-DIY-lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I haven’t really seen much of Corey Feldman since the epic 80s/90s, but this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GTlGthr4mi0&quot; title=&quot;Corey Feldman interview by Mayim Bialik&quot;&gt;interview by Mayim Bialik&lt;/a&gt; is fantastic, and a side i’ve not seen really seen much off from Corey, certainly worth a watch and thoroughly interesting at how life can be cruel, but also how you could look at things and talk around forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;
I really respected Corey, when asked about him bringing his children up and the presenters praising him, he stops and praises his wife for playing a part too. That’s worth a shout out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, it’s either football or crime, this week it’s crime and the one that is hugely in the news - &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/19YkTRbToUh2IIKMgtG7rG?si=802cf571b9e94c55&quot; title=&quot;The Murdaugh Murders podcast on the True Crime Obsessed&quot;&gt;The Murdaugh Murders&lt;/a&gt;, from the fantastic, amazingly funny and always-worth-a-listen True Crime Obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A playlist I always return to, it’s got pure 90’s classic on, an ever &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/1MXsGYMs84cQmaUtvfmb7e?si=dc72d42138be4d53&quot;&gt;growing playlist&lt;/a&gt; that is richly inspired by watching TOTP2 on an evening whilst eating a burger.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/31/weeknotes-no41.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/31/weeknotes-no41.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.40</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week has seen a lot of interesting news happening around consultancies that I was very close to joining or have friends who work there, a lot of people looking for new roles, so if you require a designer or dev etc, look no further than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/14217012/&quot; title=&quot;AND Digital&apos;s linkedin page for hiring&quot;&gt;LinkedIn group AND Digital&lt;/a&gt; set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Prep, prep, prep - I’m a huge fan of planning before you do the work, so knowing what’s coming down the line (thanks to a roadmap), I can plan alongside the DM and BA what to expect in 1-2-3 etc weeks/months and prep that Figma board already.&lt;br /&gt;
Just doing the work, it’s been busy but creatively busy - solving problems with design solutions that the team have rallied around and supported, it’s a lot of presenting work for the sell-in, but it’s really giving me satisfaction knowing I can do this, and do it well (modest boast there of course..), which is great for any designer’s self-esteem after tricky projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still awaiting confirmation I’m staying at HMRC, it’s now running close to my end date!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week I made a couple of silly oversights which pushed back some work by only a day - these mistakes are continually annoying to me and I’m sure I’m not alone as a designer striving for perfection, most of the time it’s just an oversight - things like I’ve copied and pasted incorrectly content or just not closed a blinking bracket so the page is out of whack, nothing massive - but the team is fully accepting of these, but it’s tough to not be your tough critic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retro-fixing prototypes, as I prep work, I also prep my prototype structure, how to present scenarios and provide an avenue for feedback, but the prototype I have inherited isn’t quite as robust for purpose, so it’s taken a while to get it into a shape that I can amend and showcase work (whilst allowing users to use it freely and roam around and break things), but it’s a work in progress that I can’t overdo (time is money, money is time and its the taxpayers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have two ideation workshops planned, which is always exciting when it’s discovery work, and this is my area of gold!&lt;br /&gt;
Working closely with the developers in the team to finalise and check everything is ready for the MVP launch. It’s crunch time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not technically on youtube (but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yp_5pDOa-o0&quot; title=&quot;the trailer of Heaven&apos;s Gate: the cult of cults&quot;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt; is), but I am a huge fan of documentaries about Cults, and I finally got around to watching Heaven’s Gate: The Cult of Cults. After listening to podcasts surrounding this, the documentary delivered and so much more. A really interesting watch, certainly worth your time if it sounds like your cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m sure many might of listened to this, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/6n2LPFNEnLv32clMsC7z8A?si=a3542fa73d664ee3 &quot; title=&quot;Spotify link to The Diary of a CEO podcast&quot;&gt;Simon Sinek appearance on the Diary of a CEO&lt;/a&gt; was really interesting, I often take plenty away from this podcast and this one gave me plenty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Spotify did a stunner this week, it recommended a banging playlist called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/37i9dQZF1DX4osfY3zybD2?si=03509b7e95d143d3&quot;&gt;Retro running&lt;/a&gt;”, it’s full of incredible bangers from the 80s and 90s.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/weeknotes-no40.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/weeknotes-no40.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.39</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a great week, people have been in touch, commenting how my week-notes were useful and clearer which will do me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading meetings, design work and being in the thick of things have brought back my design-mojo, and mentoring again is such a fulfilling thing that I must insist we all do it, whatever level, whatever job - always pass it on.&lt;br /&gt;
We also had a midweek stop off in Manchester for some cocktails, pies and friends - yes please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, check out this week’s podcast recommendation - it’s a good’un!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catching up with past directs (people I line-managed in the past) was a great highlight, being asked for advice still feels great and knowing I can provide this from experience feels like my worry of losing and missing line-management duties is a thing of the past.&lt;br /&gt;
Was asked to plan an ideation session, which, as a refresher allowed me to re-read past case studies and this one in imparticular around running &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/designsystem-2022.html&quot; title=&quot;read my discovery for DWP design system&quot;&gt;discovery for the DWP design system&lt;/a&gt; (I will be re-writing this case study as my tone of voice doesn’t sit right with me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Met my dearest friends that I use to knock around with in California all those years ago in Manchester as they do a tour of England, Evelyn and Jonathan. Was so much fun, we went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washhousemcr.com/&quot;&gt;The Washhouse&lt;/a&gt; in Manchester, it was cocktail mad (I was the driver so thankful they had a wicked selection of booze-free), what was brilliant was Emma booking the table for 2 hours thinking it did food… but we treated the lovely American’s to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pieminister.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Pie Minister&lt;/a&gt; - the pies of champions. Let us not leave it so soon to catch up with each other next time eh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still waiting for the sign and sealed contract for the extension.. will keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Knowing my time working with a wicked content designer (Richard) is coming to an end this week is always sad, we have made some great strides together and have had a great relationship of challenge, support and growth - pushing each other on and being each others cheerleader when the workload has grown.
Jasper’s sleeping habits.. this little angel child is 2, and still hasn’t quite grasped how sleeping works, I on the other hand am 40 - I know how sleep works and how much I’m not getting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that made me feel a little shaken, was knowing a friend who had a contract (his first) lined up for weeks, suddenly got pulled last minute, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7041350908844068865/&quot;&gt;posted it on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; - If you know anyone who needs a Developer, get in touch with Bernard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have Mans Market on Sunday to celebrate Mother’s day, which I can already feel hunger levels for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impending arrival of a Mega Drive, Nintendo Wii, Nintendo GameCube and the original Nintendo NES are all coming pretty soon. All of a sudden my office is going to look packed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A warning - the links below are football heavy.. but hardly any football is discussed!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Certainly worth a watch is the interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=76TUYCuiwzI&amp;amp;t=5715s&quot;&gt;Kevin Ball on the podcast Under the Cosh (youtube link)&lt;/a&gt;, I remember this guy to be a tough player who played hard on the field, but what a great speaker and knowledge of people within the team environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This one is the recommendation this week, I demand you listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0vtGdp5nMldzCvEG8P1AU8?si=65ac8fb0bed546b9&quot;&gt;The High Performance Podcast with Ryan Mason(Spotify link)&lt;/a&gt;, who, now an ex-footballer who left it all due to a very bad injury to become the youngest manager in the Premier League, a shared experience of ups and downs and incredible drive to succeed in trying circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last week I recommended tracks that were easy listening, this week I’m going all in, volume 11 screamo, get your ears ready:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2mizO0RNubPdTJqmrmMhfi?si=7072783712df4cbb&quot;&gt;The Ghost Inside - The Outcast (Spotify link)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/20/weeknotes-no39.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/20/weeknotes-no39.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.38</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed on LinkedIn, I have decided to change the format as the previous way was a slog to write up. My team is far too balanced and controlled for there to be much change within what I do each day, whilst the work changes - the structure doesn’t (which I’m a fan of right now).&lt;br /&gt;
So the new layout is hopefully easier to read, easier to write and just more fun in general, and whilst I might drop into days, it just won’t be like before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed future issues around possible assurance needs, and this is where GOOD problems lie, because this team has done the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/service-standard&quot; title=&quot;building a service to the service standard&quot;&gt;build-by-the-book&lt;/a&gt; - gathering all the needed paperwork to present to whoever needs it, is going to be a doddle. Teams - do your work, and do it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the above, I always revert to Vicky&apos;s fantastic post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vickyteinaki.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-service-standard&quot; title=&quot;read Vicky&apos;s brilliant the history of the service standard&quot;&gt;the history of the service standard&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vickytnz&quot;&gt;Vicky&lt;/a&gt; is an absolute A* designer / colleague / pal, she has included a link to a very useful Mural board too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my design recommendations were presented and accepted by the core and wider team and have been put into “Dev-ready”, which was supported by the brilliant design team in preparation for the presentation, this means we are making more (user-led) improvements to an important service that will help millions of people, all fueled by user research, design system patterns and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the call that my contract was extended till the end of August, which is great as I’m enjoying the work and challenges that come with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leading design meetings every Monday is a test, not because the team is challenging, but a test in regards to my prioritising what needs to be done - effort vs value. I am very comfortable presenting and Monday has almost become “the Mikey show”.&lt;br /&gt;
I have a need to write a case study for my past project at NHS, but it’s not as easy, not because I have a bad memory but mostly because it was just a tough project.. but keep an eye out for that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mansmarkets.com/&quot;&gt;Mans Market&lt;/a&gt; on Mother’s day! FOOOOOOOD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have iteration v2 coming up, and I’m gifted the reigns on it to lead - which means I’m a trusted team member now which is amazing and I cant wait to start doing what I do best, bringing the team under one roof (be it Figma) and start ideation sessions and finding great solutions to great problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it wouldn’t be weeknotes without a retro update - I’m also excited for my SNES to arrive this week.. just need to start buying games for it AND hot off the press… a Mega Drive - WOO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To describe this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@yx98&quot; title=&quot;check out YX&apos;s youtube channel&quot;&gt;artist’s youtube&lt;/a&gt; would not be fair in a short comment, just go and watch a handful of YX’s videos. His songs are next level too - really recommend Last Ride, Out her Space, Good Things, and Mad, he’s up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/2Fv2ioUtRdjP2i5ilLcDPs?si=LtVmnlDgRLmv12jdbHEFlg&quot; title=&quot;check out YX&apos;s music&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; if thats your thing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no38.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no38.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.37</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Realised I hadn’t told anyone that I was doing week-notes, that’s how rusty I am at this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a good week, really enjoyed the week’s challenges around work, I even had time and permission to have a go at experiments, which is an amazing thing.&lt;br /&gt;
On a personal level, it’s my sons birthday this week - he’s a brilliant, bright and funny “little Mikey”, unfortunately for his mother and sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Best day of the week? &lt;br /&gt;
Working through the alignment issues between live and prototype, this isn’t the developers have raced ahead, it’s more around we have made decisions but the prototype doesn’t align to these, which means I’m digging through a lot of brains, or confluence to match things up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Slogging through updating the prototype still, I decided to build the MVP solution, and remove any other noise or future ideas we have had, so we can send it out to stakeholders and know they are only seeing what we are delivering (we’ve all been here right?) and this is being appreciated by teams far and wide! But this also means going through the prototype from door to door, bits I’ve never seen before and bits I need to fix.. cue a design crit corner on Figma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
People are still liking and reaching out to my post on LinkedIn about my leaving and starting at HMRC, which is cool and always feels great to be supported and asked if I’m available - never stop as one day I might be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This prototyping lark is a blast, earphones in and head-down - trying to make sense of some interesting decisions made in the past. Whilst I do not disagree with many - I am using this MVP build to showcase why decisions were made and challenge some of the more interesting ones.
I forgot how much I use to do prototyping and my HTML/CSS experience, so it’s been fantastic to dust down my brain in this space and feel like I know what I’m doing, all whilst keeping the team in the loop of some issues I find and making design decisions on amongst the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Started to plan and see what’s on the 3-6 month horizon for this project, I’m thinking around scale (always) and possible internal or external assessments and all the other fun stuff that comes with launching a service (especially one was important and big as this one) - I actually cannot wait for this, this project has ticked all the right boxes in regards following GDS standards, doing the right things and working for the user AND business correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also - this is the day before my son’s 2nd birthday party, never hoovered so much in my downtime ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I found the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=he6Nq2lWLJ0&amp;amp;t=1s&quot; title=&quot;Jason Lee interviews David Baddiel&quot;&gt; conversation between Jason Lee (ex-Nottingham Forest football player) and David Baddiel (ex-host of Fantasy Football)&lt;/a&gt; a really interesting and insightful conversation, I recall the show and its sketches about Jason Lee and seeing Jason speaking to David on a normal, calm level when he could have reacted so differently was empowering and such impact.
&lt;br /&gt;An insightful, intelligent discussion around race.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/03/weeknotes-no37.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/03/weeknotes-no37.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
