<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 15:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 15:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.38</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a great week, people have been in touch, commenting how my week-notes were useful and clearer which will do me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading meetings, design work and being in the thick of things have brought back my design-mojo, and mentoring again is such a fulfilling thing that I must insist we all do it, whatever level, whatever job - always pass it on.&lt;br /&gt;
We also had a midweek stop off in Manchester for some cocktails, pies and friends - yes please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, check out this week’s podcast recommendation - it’s a good’un!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catching up with past directs (people I line-managed in the past) was a great highlight, being asked for advice still feels great and knowing I can provide this from experience feels like my worry of losing and missing line-management duties is a thing of the past.&lt;br /&gt;
Was asked to plan an ideation session, which, as a refresher allowed me to re-read past case studies and this one in imparticular around running &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/designsystem-2022.html&quot; title=&quot;read my discovery for DWP design system&quot;&gt;discovery for the DWP design system&lt;/a&gt; (I will be re-writing this case study as my tone of voice doesn’t sit right with me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Met my dearest friends that I use to knock around with in California all those years ago in Manchester as they do a tour of England, Evelyn and Jonathan. Was so much fun, we went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washhousemcr.com/&quot;&gt;The Washhouse&lt;/a&gt; in Manchester, it was cocktail mad (I was the driver so thankful they had a wicked selection of booze-free), what was brilliant was Emma booking the table for 2 hours thinking it did food… but we treated the lovely American’s to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pieminister.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Pie Minister&lt;/a&gt; - the pies of champions. Let us not leave it so soon to catch up with each other next time eh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still waiting for the sign and sealed contract for the extension.. will keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Knowing my time working with a wicked content designer (Richard) is coming to an end this week is always sad, we have made some great strides together and have had a great relationship of challenge, support and growth - pushing each other on and being each others cheerleader when the workload has grown.
Jasper’s sleeping habits.. this little angel child is 2, and still hasn’t quite grasped how sleeping works, I on the other hand am 40 - I know how sleep works and how much I’m not getting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that made me feel a little shaken, was knowing a friend who had a contract (his first) lined up for weeks, suddenly got pulled last minute, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7041350908844068865/&quot;&gt;posted it on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; - If you know anyone who needs a Developer, get in touch with Bernard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have Mans Market on Sunday to celebrate Mother’s day, which I can already feel hunger levels for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impending arrival of a Mega Drive, Nintendo Wii, Nintendo GameCube and the original Nintendo NES are all coming pretty soon. All of a sudden my office is going to look packed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A warning - the links below are football heavy.. but hardly any football is discussed!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Certainly worth a watch is the interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=76TUYCuiwzI&amp;amp;t=5715s&quot;&gt;Kevin Ball on the podcast Under the Cosh (youtube link)&lt;/a&gt;, I remember this guy to be a tough player who played hard on the field, but what a great speaker and knowledge of people within the team environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This one is the recommendation this week, I demand you listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0vtGdp5nMldzCvEG8P1AU8?si=65ac8fb0bed546b9&quot;&gt;The High Performance Podcast with Ryan Mason(Spotify link)&lt;/a&gt;, who, now an ex-footballer who left it all due to a very bad injury to become the youngest manager in the Premier League, a shared experience of ups and downs and incredible drive to succeed in trying circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last week I recommended tracks that were easy listening, this week I’m going all in, volume 11 screamo, get your ears ready:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2mizO0RNubPdTJqmrmMhfi?si=7072783712df4cbb&quot;&gt;The Ghost Inside - The Outcast (Spotify link)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no39.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no39.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.38</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed on LinkedIn, I have decided to change the format as the previous way was a slog to write up. My team is far too balanced and controlled for there to be much change within what I do each day, whilst the work changes - the structure doesn’t (which I’m a fan of right now).&lt;br /&gt;
So the new layout is hopefully easier to read, easier to write and just more fun in general, and whilst I might drop into days, it just won’t be like before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed future issues around possible assurance needs, and this is where GOOD problems lie, because this team has done the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/service-standard&quot; title=&quot;building a service to the service standard&quot;&gt;build-by-the-book&lt;/a&gt; - gathering all the needed paperwork to present to whoever needs it, is going to be a doddle. Teams - do your work, and do it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the above, I always revert to Vicky&apos;s fantastic post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vickyteinaki.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-service-standard&quot; title=&quot;read Vicky&apos;s brilliant the history of the service standard&quot;&gt;the history of the service standard&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vickytnz&quot;&gt;Vicky&lt;/a&gt; is an absolute A* designer / colleague / pal, she has included a link to a very useful Mural board too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my design recommendations were presented and accepted by the core and wider team and have been put into “Dev-ready”, which was supported by the brilliant design team in preparation for the presentation, this means we are making more (user-led) improvements to an important service that will help millions of people, all fueled by user research, design system patterns and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the call that my contract was extended till the end of August, which is great as I’m enjoying the work and challenges that come with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leading design meetings every Monday is a test, not because the team is challenging, but a test in regards to my prioritising what needs to be done - effort vs value. I am very comfortable presenting and Monday has almost become “the Mikey show”.&lt;br /&gt;
I have a need to write a case study for my past project at NHS, but it’s not as easy, not because I have a bad memory but mostly because it was just a tough project.. but keep an eye out for that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mansmarkets.com/&quot;&gt;Mans Market&lt;/a&gt; on Mother’s day! FOOOOOOOD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have iteration v2 coming up, and I’m gifted the reigns on it to lead - which means I’m a trusted team member now which is amazing and I cant wait to start doing what I do best, bringing the team under one roof (be it Figma) and start ideation sessions and finding great solutions to great problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it wouldn’t be weeknotes without a retro update - I’m also excited for my SNES to arrive this week.. just need to start buying games for it AND hot off the press… a Mega Drive - WOO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To describe this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@yx98&quot; title=&quot;check out YX&apos;s youtube channel&quot;&gt;artist’s youtube&lt;/a&gt; would not be fair in a short comment, just go and watch a handful of YX’s videos. His songs are next level too - really recommend Last Ride, Out her Space, Good Things, and Mad, he’s up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/2Fv2ioUtRdjP2i5ilLcDPs?si=LtVmnlDgRLmv12jdbHEFlg&quot; title=&quot;check out YX&apos;s music&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; if thats your thing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no38.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/13/weeknotes-no38.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.37</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Realised I hadn’t told anyone that I was doing week-notes, that’s how rusty I am at this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a good week, really enjoyed the week’s challenges around work, I even had time and permission to have a go at experiments, which is an amazing thing.&lt;br /&gt;
On a personal level, it’s my sons birthday this week - he’s a brilliant, bright and funny “little Mikey”, unfortunately for his mother and sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Best day of the week? &lt;br /&gt;
Working through the alignment issues between live and prototype, this isn’t the developers have raced ahead, it’s more around we have made decisions but the prototype doesn’t align to these, which means I’m digging through a lot of brains, or confluence to match things up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Slogging through updating the prototype still, I decided to build the MVP solution, and remove any other noise or future ideas we have had, so we can send it out to stakeholders and know they are only seeing what we are delivering (we’ve all been here right?) and this is being appreciated by teams far and wide! But this also means going through the prototype from door to door, bits I’ve never seen before and bits I need to fix.. cue a design crit corner on Figma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
People are still liking and reaching out to my post on LinkedIn about my leaving and starting at HMRC, which is cool and always feels great to be supported and asked if I’m available - never stop as one day I might be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This prototyping lark is a blast, earphones in and head-down - trying to make sense of some interesting decisions made in the past. Whilst I do not disagree with many - I am using this MVP build to showcase why decisions were made and challenge some of the more interesting ones.
I forgot how much I use to do prototyping and my HTML/CSS experience, so it’s been fantastic to dust down my brain in this space and feel like I know what I’m doing, all whilst keeping the team in the loop of some issues I find and making design decisions on amongst the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Started to plan and see what’s on the 3-6 month horizon for this project, I’m thinking around scale (always) and possible internal or external assessments and all the other fun stuff that comes with launching a service (especially one was important and big as this one) - I actually cannot wait for this, this project has ticked all the right boxes in regards following GDS standards, doing the right things and working for the user AND business correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also - this is the day before my son’s 2nd birthday party, never hoovered so much in my downtime ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I found the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=he6Nq2lWLJ0&amp;amp;t=1s&quot; title=&quot;Jason Lee interviews David Baddiel&quot;&gt; conversation between Jason Lee (ex-Nottingham Forest football player) and David Baddiel (ex-host of Fantasy Football)&lt;/a&gt; a really interesting and insightful conversation, I recall the show and its sketches about Jason Lee and seeing Jason speaking to David on a normal, calm level when he could have reacted so differently was empowering and such impact.
&lt;br /&gt;An insightful, intelligent discussion around race.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/03/weeknotes-no37.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/03/weeknotes-no37.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.36</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Presented my findings to the team around design issues that I’m finding on the prototype that may come stuck later on, I made a very simple user journey map showing scenarios and outputs and, simply highlighted any issues around lack of consistency or breaking away from the design system. This is the kind of team where you can do this simply and openly without any pausing and as normal, I open the floor to team discussion where we highlight what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pancake day - do I need to write anything more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One of my favourite days of the week, this day is saved for Replenishment, where we discuss what to work on next, this is an hour and 25-minute meeting, which works brilliantly. We discuss tickets (that are written out properly) and update quickly where we are etc, for example, I am working through some grade-A accessibility issues with the service at the moment (fed from the DAC report), and knowing we are doing the good work and the right work feels really good. As a side note, the service does not have many issues at all, so a lot of our fixes are “nice to haves” which is a one-off from my experience, as with anything accessible, everything should be a must-have.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I also may have bought a Sega Mega Drive today…*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am rebuilding the prototype to showcase the MVP, the actual thing we are realising in the wild soon - I know this is urgently needed as I am always wary of stakeholders seeing future work that we are in the process of playing with / seeing what fits, they might expect it all when we are only delivering 40% of it.&lt;br /&gt;
This has been more of a challenge than expected, due to some inline styles and absolute links found, but luckily I’m old-hat at this and nothing surprises me with quickly built/throw-away prototypes, but I am adding hygienic factors to the prototype to ensure we can add and build at speed cleanly going forward.&lt;br /&gt;
Also allows me to add more scenarios to the prototype for user research (we never user test, or test the user) if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why am I just finding out about &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamboard.google.com/&quot; title=&quot;use Google&apos;s digital whiteboard that lets you collaborate in real time&quot;&gt;jamboard&lt;/a&gt;? It’s great for a quick presentation (of which I do a lot) and allows people to add post-its on the page with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am unsure who shared this link, but it’s been saved in my tabs to read later, so I’m sharing to see if its useful for others:
An article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/How-to-test-a-prototype-with-users-dfdc55e5a5124c1aa21720989a582a60&quot; title=&quot;How to test a prototype with users&quot;&gt;How to test a prototype with users&lt;/a&gt;, whilst I know most of this, its a great reminder and something really powerful to share with any mentees - also the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wearecast.notion.site/Definition-Programme-8d1533f41dff45209f3685f4e364d483&quot; title=&quot;defination program with loads of useful learnings&quot;&gt;full program&lt;/a&gt; is pretty good too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Turns out the Mega Drive didnt come as it was broken unfortunately. GUTTED.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/28/weeknotes-no36.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/28/weeknotes-no36.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.35</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a brilliant weekend, I’ve always promised myself when I had the time and the space I would start collecting retro consoles, one’s I loved from my youth (don’t ask my age) and this weekend, I decided it was time. I bought my first console - the beautiful Atari 2600 Woody edition. &lt;br /&gt;
In mint condition from a brilliant seller, I couldn’t be happier to start with this one, and already building a great catalogue of games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/atari-2600-wood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a photo of my lovely atari 2600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe this team has it right, every Monday we have an exclusive Design-the-week planning session, and all and everyone in the core team is invited - but design is the table, it’s a discussion about design tickets only which is accepted, controlled and never sways away from it. The developers, BAs, QAs etc all have a chance to discuss user needs, and it just damn works.&lt;br /&gt;
Half term has begun as well, so I’m sharing my desk whilst Robyn plays an absolute banging game Stardew Valley, we both play this game as it’s local co-op. It’s one of our favourite games to play and both of us can get deep into the life of a farmer, whilst I’m growing parsnips, Robyn feeds the cows - this is exactly what I thought being 40 would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The best day of the week, as it’s half term I went to Bradford’s Science and Media museum with the kids, whilst leaving Emma at work - unlucky! It was a great day with just me and the kids, we built spaceships, made space badges and ate sandwiches, it’s the best of the best. &lt;br /&gt;
6 floors were a bit heavy though, unsure my legs could have taken a 7th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Started to do a design crit of the service, which was warmly welcomed by the team. Unfortunately, it turns out many pages are using inline styles, moving away from anything existing within the Design system, many reasons why this is usually a no-no, but the main one here is around accessibility and consistency, we need to start using tried and tested patterns due to the level of people that will be using this service and why they are using the service. With this in mind, my challenge now is to undo the current patterns in place and find suitable ones that are purposeful and relevant for the transaction.&lt;br /&gt;
I also received feedback today, which was great - to know I’m working to a high level and it’s appreciated is the ego boast that I required after a tough 8 months, so very thankful for the feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Due to the above feedback, I noticed we have a page or two within the journey that catered more for business needs than user needs. I am a designer who is happy to work with and for both, and enjoy combining both needs into one happy tied-up solution - but this felt like it leaned far too much to the business. &lt;br /&gt;
Presenting this back to the wider team is always the challenge that I love, and one I love to do to challenge the current thinking, it’s not about whether I’m right or they are right - it’s about what is best served the user and the business in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The change to contracting means I can do more at home, and this means I can take days off to look after my kids and surprise them on random day outs - today was taking my daughter to the cinema to watch Epic Tails and overdose us both on popcorn. Whilst the film wasn’t all that wonderful - we had fun, and I never want to see popcorn at least for a week, then that evening we went out and ate at Yo Sushi (goodbye savings) and it was epic, the kids love sushi and the randomness of whatever we’ve ordered coming to our table via a plate on a carousel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you are into the retro scene as much as I am, I couldn’t recommend the brilliant &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/slopesgameroom?lang=en&quot; title=&quot;follow slopes on twitter&quot;&gt;DJ Slopes&lt;/a&gt; documentary doing the rounds on youtube right now about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8BgAarlzVD4&quot; title=&quot;watch the entire history of the Amico product launch or no launch&quot;&gt;failed Amico launch&lt;/a&gt; and the drama surrounding it, it’s 4 hours of “what the fuck” moments and how to not do product launches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/17/weeknotes-no35.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/17/weeknotes-no35.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.34</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new week, and I think I can say I’m officially onboarded now.
I’ve spoken to so many recruiters over the past week or so, it’s been a great ego boost. Friends from the old days have also got in touch, and the support for my change into contracting has been amazing, and people like Gavin Elliott especially have been the nudge and cheerleading that I needed. Thanks Gav, you’re a good egg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Prototype day and design planning, the structure is still blowing my mind!
Presented my work to a room of developers, QA’s, BA’s and designers for a crit, the first one since I joined and it went well, with lots of healthy questions and feedback.&lt;br /&gt;
I mean.. this means work for me to do - but a room full of clever people is more effective than mine, and my job is to facilitate the best solution, in the shortest amount of time for the least money to give the user and the business what they need to do their daily tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Design catch-up with the team, I am starting to own the design direction regarding interaction design and the general design system components used and accessibility.&lt;br /&gt;
On the side, I am also adding new content to Bobbin and Bumble which is so much fun, we have new products launching soon which I’m delighted with - Emma has worked her socks off to get these to launch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am sure you are all aware, but have a go on &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/chat&quot; title=&quot;click to view chatGPT&quot;&gt;chatGPT&lt;/a&gt; and ask it a question, and try different scenarios - it’s such a powerful, interesting concept.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/13/weeknotes-no34.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/13/weeknotes-no34.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.33</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally missed a couple of days’ updates, so let’s start fresh &lt;em&gt;insert smack head emoji here&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
This contract feels so different to the previous months, I don’t feel dread when 9 am or sometimes 8 am comes around, I feel a surge of excitement and challenge (in a good way) and am energised by the team. The challenges so far are usual run-of-the-mill expected things and I would describe the team as being in control of the problem space AND the solution space.  &lt;br /&gt;
As a bonus, I’m sleeping better, nicer, having time to think and enjoying life instead of letting work ruin/run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sun is shining, coffee is flowing (if you need recommendations, look no further than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taylorsofharrogate.co.uk/house-blends/lazy-sunday&quot; title=&quot;a link to taylors sunday blend coffee&quot;&gt;Taylor’s Sunday blend &lt;/a&gt;)
Today, we met as a design and talked ONLY design tickets and the forthcoming work - this is so refreshing and it’s a welcome discussion when developers, BAs, and QAs discuss user needs and the design team just let it flow. I mentioned challenges in the header of this post, this 100% isn’t a challenge, it’s a breath of fresh air and I’m all for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working closely with the excellent design team (content designer and a User researcher) on part of the journey around verifying your ID (using phone, email or HMRC app) and updating the prototype. Busy morning, lots to take in and plenty of understanding and “ahh” moments coming from me, grateful I’m sat on my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote a handful of LinkedIn recommendations for those nearest and dearest, suddenly a well-worth task that, in a time when people are job searching gives them a boost and knows that others out there are helping out (if you have any outstanding, please write one - including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelcattell/&quot; title=&quot;link to my Linkedin profile&quot;&gt;one for me!&lt;/a&gt;).
Also during my lunch hour, had another run at using ChatGPT, it’s such a powerful “thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The set-up on this team is next level, this morning was refinement - where.. if I ever doubted that they trusted the interaction designer, today was the day it was wiped out - they asked me all the right questions, hung on my words of experience and listened and agreed to my points of view - LOVE IT!&lt;br /&gt;
We also have a lot of DAC items in our backlog, that, due to my experience on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/designsystem-2022.html&quot; title=&quot;linking to my DWP design system case study&quot;&gt;design system team&lt;/a&gt; I can easily work on (I know the backlog of the Gov design system like the back of my hand), I also know from previous experience that sometimes the DAC reports are always 100% correct - mostly around comments to the design system (one example would be making all labels for input boxes as bold and bigger, which varies between each service).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Managed to work a ton of tickets yesterday, all centered around my bread and butter - accessibility.&lt;br /&gt;
Feels like an interesting clash between what the design system is, and how the design system is being used and understood by its users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is purely 100% reading the DAC report and working on those issues, as mentioned before - some of the reviews are quite interesting, they lean towards more what the design system says to do, in a “look and feel” manner than what’s happening on screen. Interestingly - it’s not correct either, I’ve had many DAC reports and they’ve always differed almost exclusively on one pattern, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.service.gov.uk/components/details/&quot; title=&quot;click here to see the GDS details pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;details pattern&lt;/a&gt; not being able to be read correctly by Dragon (but.. many times it’s been found to be a false report).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I really enjoyed the podcast with Ross Clark / Rylan on the fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/6J4vrilAtR8wEzj9j4PFTu?si=a240f3513e0348df&quot; title=&quot;a spotify link to the High Performance Podcast&quot;&gt;High Performance podcast&lt;/a&gt;. It was really insightful into his life, but also interesting to see little snippets of coping mechanisms. &lt;br /&gt;
“Don’t sweat the small stuff” really landed with me, it’s an old saying that has been used time after time, but I needed to hear this and actually HEAR this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/06/weeknotes-no33.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/06/weeknotes-no33.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.32</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here it is, the long-awaited return of weeknotes (said no one), I cannot believe it has been nearly 2 years since I wrote anything. &lt;br /&gt;
Things have changed a heck of a lot since my last post, I joined Hippo Digital on the 12th January 2022, and left on the 12th January 2023. It was an adventure that I will write about, but first, I have a new journey to go on and look forward to
&lt;strong&gt;life as a contractor (the sequel)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the old and tested fashion, I’ll keep the format the same as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is my first day at HMRC as an Interaction Designer and it was all I wanted it to be, it was easy, nice, warm and structured. A huge hat tip to Sam Manzi for just being amazingly welcoming and just being in control of a situation that is never easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of contracting isn’t a shock or surprise to me anymore, after a year of leading and landing teams into contracting or consulting positions and seeing their anxiety rise due to piss-poor onboarding or more-than-likely lack of preparation from the resource team, I have a couple of quick wins under my belt (which I should write about one day), but not beating myself up and thinking others are expecting me to hit the ground running and know what I’m working on just isn’t real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is a full meet and greet with the team and the wonderful Jean, she reached out almost instantly when I joined and that is a great sign of it being a good place to work.&lt;br /&gt;
The community seems to be a huge thing here, which is exciting as I’ve missed the “help each other out” during design crits and attending one already felt natural, even giving me space to talk about my experience with a problem I had faced previously.
Great day for onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Reading, reading, reading, confluence, confluence and a bit more confluence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today started as a cracking day - woke up, fed the kids and it was my turn to take them to school.. only today was different - I thought it was Wednesday. No big deal - most school days are the same, except Robyn has a booster class at 8:30 am, whilst I’m strolling in at 8:45 am telling Robyn it’s 100% Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;
Being corrected by a 7-year-old is a fresh kick that coffee never provides, and then pushing a pram at the speed of light to get her in the lesson is a vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Forgot to write this one - doh! What a wonderful start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Usually I would place podcasts, blogs and people to link to, but as i’ve just re-started it - feel free to send some over for me to read or listen or do introductions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/25/weeknotes-no32.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/25/weeknotes-no32.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.31</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(for the week of 31st August)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mannnnn a weird weekend, turns out my perfect little dog has diabetes which is tough to handle and was incredibly tough to hear - but then real life kicks in and we just have to accept it and manage it. Tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussed the final amends to the design system re-vamp, really light stuff like content etc, and today I will be sending it out for testing and feedback. Looking forward to this so we can see exactly what’s what - I’ve kept a ton in the loop but we finally have a prototype of sorts to show off that isn’t sketches or conversations.&lt;br /&gt;
A day of admin (again) and doing the small stuff that I’ve not looked at for a while, painful but needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Online training day, decided to help out DWP with the hiring process properly by taking the sifting course (this is where we read cv’s etc) and being on the panel in interviews, that’ll help me get more insight into the process properly and also if needed, help me hone my interview skills for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteered to speak at the Content Community day, having a 15-20minute slot to discuss all things design patterns and content patterns, I’ll be covering off my favourite - contribution but also going for investment from the community into future patterns and seeing if there are blockers to providing feedback (every presentation needs a workshop right?), excited for this one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Today’s work is lead by the presentation to the community, which goes side by side with my work in leading the change of contribution model - we have outlined a skeleton shape to the presentation and now the fun bit, working out the words stuff…&lt;br /&gt;
Collating feedback on the design system from approx 20 people ranging from differing roles within DWP, really excited to see the feedback and amend, we are using and trialling Github discussions still, as there were hints people were nervous about using GitHub issues - but so far people seem to be fluent and fast in using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took some time out today to take the kids swimming midday, was so much fun to break the day up with this and a nice and welcome break from a hectic work week. And also, who doesn’t love dunking their kid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Arranging a gathering of work colleagues finally, this feels good to be seeing people I work with and having a quiet (..yeah right) drink sometime next week, it’s been so long since I’ve been in a public place with a group of people so fingers crossed my social skills are as terrible as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washy week this one, prob my most boring set of week notes tbh, but it’s all the admin/must do work at the moment (I’m sure you don’t want to know all the digging I’m doing in confluence!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mega-mentor.com/&quot;&gt;https://mega-mentor.com/&lt;/a&gt;  - This website doesn’t need an introduction, if you are looking above your level and want a design lead to help motivate, advise and help you on the next step, this is the place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/08/weeknotes-no31.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/09/08/weeknotes-no31.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.30</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(for the week of 23rd August)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A new fresh week at work after a nice weekend of playing with the kids, having a lovely dinner out with my wife and brill nippers and terrible weather!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t, I would recommend you read this &lt;a href=&quot;https://stamanfar.medium.com/just-say-it-3c43a83c1ea9&quot;&gt;brilliant blog post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stamanfar?lang=en&quot;&gt;@stamanfar&lt;/a&gt;, written with such honesty that many of us face sometime in our career - in her words: A blog about flunking, maybe, and new beginnings. This post alone has made me turn up AGAIN and do week notes, it was really impactful and I’m so glad it was written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On other news, I also returned from holiday - a week on a farm is this family best holiday and since lockdown has been here and gone, we’ve holidayed around England a lot and… wow this country has got some beautiful gems that I might have missed in the past but making up for it now!&lt;br /&gt;
A timely break for us all, work has been hectic - both home life (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt;) and work work, but it’s nice to turn the MacBook off, recharge, re-assess thoughts and energize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve been busy updating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.dwp.gov.uk/index&quot;&gt;DWP’s first design system website&lt;/a&gt; over the last week (at the time of writing this is not updated), really feeding off user needs that we collected (first hand) from our users, things around updating them on what we are working on, what’s in the backlog and also providing a clearer understanding of what we are doing and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also be working alongside this launch presenting back to the different communities within DWP to provoke a discussion around contribution to the design system, allowing much more freedom and “chat” around patterns and, I guess - getting them to do the work alongside us (the way it should be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was around fixing issues and bugs that I’ve noticed within the design system site, easy lists (light work to get back into the swing of things).
Then straight onto working on our backlog item (today was &lt;strong&gt;toggle welsh&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;keybar details&lt;/strong&gt;), gathering as much data as possible and speaking to those who have given us information using GitHub discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard work when making patterns is certainly the start - knowing where to start feels different for each pattern depending on what arrives, how it arrives and what the users want first. As we are short in numbers of staff members, it means having to lean into User Research areas and not letting personal opinion kick in (I’ve used the patterns I’m gathering before so forgetting bias is always a tricky thing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have huge questions around how we agree on a pattern and launching it - whilst I certainly don’t want to wait around pleasing everyone, I certainly don’t want to launch something just because I think it is ready - I think its key to have a group of people to ask “Is this what you want/good enough” and if not - tell me why with data.
The afternoon meeting was to support a community-led pattern exploration piece, I’m super excited to see this in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This morning I am trying to be a lot more productive and focused, as the last couple of days / and week has been a rush of getting the work done as quick as possible (due to our deadlines), whilst I’ve enjoyed it a lot, I need to get my focus back now the rush is over. The easiest way to do this is to target THREE things I want to do today, I usually do TWO workpieces and ONE for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping to arrange the workshop the community are running by giving some tips on making it as effective as possible, but remember I shall be taking a back seat here, and letting them work their magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I was invited to speak to the Content Community, centring around gaining a level understanding of the value, purpose and shared vision of the design system, so discussed my presentation with the organiser, and anyone who knows when I do a presentation - I always want to get something from it - selfishly for the project I am on - an interactive presentation, so I’m squeezing in a mini-workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today’s hectic, poor Ralph isn’t too well so taking part of my lunch hour to visit the vets and doing dad duties in the morning with my other boy, he’s 5 months old now and has found out how to wave!&lt;br /&gt;
Also, today is the planned community workshop (which I have to miss due to Ralph) but I know it’s in safe hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ran through content and design ideas with Helen (content designer on the design system) to nail down what we could do even more to improve the process of providing feedback to a pattern/component and also discuss bloody terminal commands!&lt;br /&gt;
I’m pleased and proud of the team as to what we will deliver, it will answer a lot of the questions to user needs and also provide a level of transparency that wasn’t there before, and set us up for a strong future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Work work workkkkkk, loads on with finishing the build and fixing mishaps that we find (of course it’s perfect first time…).&lt;br /&gt;
Tying up a lot of ends that will align parts of entry for the design system is consistent and very much up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ran through the feedback from the workshop yesterday, due to missing it, it was nice to see something happening that was led by want and need and not by must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing really to update but doing admin work, and loads of it 🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How did it get to Friday this fast? Is this the day we launch the new design system? Fingers crossed we are near… but it is at that point of, there could be a bug or content error anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/leading-service-design/asking-the-right-questions-to-frame-the-problem-4df95a317983&quot;&gt;https://designdetails.fm/episodes/292309&lt;/a&gt; - Revisiting Ben’s brilliant post about “asking the right questions to frame the problem”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UkvOlE8qDB0&amp;amp;list=PLMC49V9zeXbGQwEM-my5XLiTWzy4-vf7j&amp;amp;index=67&amp;amp;t=1663s&quot;&gt;Slopes Game Room - KickScammers: The VEGA+ Scandal&lt;/a&gt; - I am massively into retro-gaming, and this documentary about the Spectrum Vega+ has me gripped from start to finish, usual brilliance from Slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/02/weeknotes-no30.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/09/02/weeknotes-no30.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
