<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 23:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 23:29:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Celebrating the wins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself - when did you last celebrate a win?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean your favourite sports team winning, I don’t mean when you decide you’re having a takeaway tonight, I mean when you’ve achieved something, maybe when your squad/team has launched something or when a loved one achieved something special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past couple of years, I’ve noticed a trend, it’s pretty daunting – I don’t see or hear the wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since working alongside my wife - assisting in the web/marketing content of both the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/bobbinandbumblebaby&quot; title=&quot;check bobbin and bumble's shop on etsy&quot;&gt;Etsy shop and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/bobbinandbumblebaby&quot; title=&quot;check bobbin and bumble's website&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, before I got near any work I had to dig into my personal rule book and set some rules.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we joined forces, Emma was aiming for the stars, she wanted success - she’s been doing this since 2015 and she has been very successful - since 2015 (December to be exact), she has run her own company, been a full time mother - she has somehow managed to do all of this in the same 24 hours that I went to work, came home, put my daughter to bed and moan I didn’t have time to watch football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sounds great doesn’t it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really, now our daughter is at school Emma wants more success, she wants her products to rush off the electronic shelves and be sold out in hours instead of days or weeks.
This disappointment could lead to days of un-motivation, lack of great ideas or worse - closing the company down and giving in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did we change? What difference could we make to this process, to the business and to her and my success?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We simply made some rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made goals&lt;br /&gt;
We spelled out the wins&lt;br /&gt;
We called out the failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did we do? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agreeing on mini goals:&lt;br /&gt;
It’s worth reminding yourself - setting goals, especially big goals is all about getting what we want, but if we set goals that are too large we are talking about the far future - you do need to set these, but sometimes you can loose heart if you do not achieve these quickly. Smaller goals, mini goals are easier to set, quicker to land and even better - quicker to learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting goals is great, it helps set out the landscape - expectations, direction and the truth.&lt;br /&gt;
To set goals you need to think about: launch day, 1st week, 2nd week, 1 month, 3 months to 6 months and so on. What do you want to achieve in those?&lt;br /&gt;
Emma and I decided on setting goals for just the launch, 1st week and 1 month - that way we could quickly change direction if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch was the toughest to set - during this process I had to share my learnings and best ways of working - these included being as simple as possible, using the RAG rating system (a personal favourite) and just being open about what we want to achieve or find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as basic as (not in any order):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;agree on logo&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;set launch date&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;research competitors&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finalise designs and export&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;discuss with the manufacturer about processing designs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update all social media accounts with new branding&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used Google sheets so we both could access and amend, this helped Emma keep focus, and work through a list at speed - whilst waiting on one thing she could action the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t discuss too much on how to set goals (that’s potentially another post), but I also set goals to start a habit, like “post to Instagram every day”, “research keywords for &lt;em&gt;insert product&lt;/em&gt; - 1 product per week”, “spend an hour per week reviewing stats on Etsy and website” and finally “celebrate your first sale with a treat!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebrate the wins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeding on from the goals we set - we needed to celebrate the wins, Emma has never done this before (where as I celebrate everything, as I know the knock-on effect of it) - every “done” was a moment, a huge moment for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when she sent her first order to the manufacturer, we celebrated with a meal, this meant a lot of things, it meant she had signed off her designs, she trusted someone with her designs, she was ready to start selling. It didn’t need to be as big as this, but just something to announce “you did this, and you did it well”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I make sure the team celebrates the good, and sometimes the bad. I tend to call out the winners during Retros (however good a Retro is, I don’t always use this to announce people who did good things as its also a moment where we are saying what went wrong with a time limit), so maybe it can be during a stand-up, or the answer to “has anyone got anything else to add?” in another meeting - either way its nice to call someone out and let them know we have noticed their effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dream big and get those small wins.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could write this down on everyone’s desk and remind them of this every hour I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since working with Emma, and doing a lot of back-ground hunting, researching and digging into the data I could get my hands on - I’ve realised that success is not linked to good luck - obviously that can play a part in it, but it’s a lot down to the effort and how well you allocate time - working out what are the quick wins, the big wins and the expensive possible-might-work are key to a successful launch and first couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a learning curve, but having your work planned out with value and then celebrating when completion of the bigger or tricky items has led to keeping us motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, be kind to yourself when you are working - notice when you have a win and celebrate yourself, small wins are all part of the plan for the “big” win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/04/bringing-the-wins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/02/04/bringing-the-wins.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Phew - a mad old week with loads to learn.
The highlight has to be the brilliant New Adventures Conference, it was really THAT good.
I will now go every year, some amazing life and career changing talks that really made me think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A confirmation that our “Service journey” was as correct as it can be up to the point of actually “doing it” with the team who have done a similar service in the past. Really exciting session and always nice to know, as a team we are so far doing so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Meetings, stand-ups and planning is what Mondays are all about.
Drew up the outcomes from the workshop on a massive whitewall to present tomorrow and Wednesday to stakeholders with the BA, led to more questions and more collaboration with the wider team which is my aim of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Workshop all day. Can’t say much more due to the nature of it - sorry!
Bobbin and Bumble news.. i’ve started to dabble into re-designing her site as in coding.. its like 2015 all over again where I use to go knee deep in e-commerce themes (Wordpress, Magento to name a few) - weirdly I bloody loved it and have much more work to go, but it folded back like a bad dream - even remembered how to use Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today was busy.
Had a run through the workshop results with a team working on a similar thing I modelled my project on due to its successes, its research and the goals but most importantly its lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, they agreed it was similar and a really interesting show and share session.&lt;br /&gt;
The morning was Roadmap planning - imagine having a roadmap workshop and it being fun? It was - so healthy disagreements (the good type.. yes there is a good type) where, if I disagreed with a “thing” I was asked to elaborate on it and was heard. Some of my points weren’t agreed with, but being listened to and their points back were enough for me to go “yeh.. you were right and bloody very much right!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The day I’ve been looking forward to for a while, New Adventures Conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say, this was one of the best conferences I’ve ever been too. It was so “up my street”,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two talks that “got me” were &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/akilbenjamin&quot; title=&quot;follow akil on twitter&quot;&gt;@akilbenjamin&lt;/a&gt;’s talk “Clean your studio. Draw on walls. Don’t break things. Radical is close to home.” was a really close-to-home talk.&lt;br /&gt;
From the opening, where Akil discussed personal things, breaking down choices is something I went through last year. This approach has totally changed my view on things, and how I approach certain decision points etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second talk was by the incredible &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elizejackson&quot; title=&quot;follow liz on twitter&quot;&gt;@elizejackson&lt;/a&gt; called “Productivity recreates disability”.&lt;br /&gt;
This talk had me in a spin. Never ever has a talk made me question it all, and been such a “shit let’s change this” moment. I want to thank Liz for that talk, as it will completely change everything, my approach to design and my approach to “thinking about others”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to rewatch it all, tough to concentrate and remember when you’re nodding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also as a bonus, I got to spend the day with designers from DWP, which is always great to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A day to plan out next week, it’s been a busy couple of weeks and I used today to do admin. List down what I need to do, what I wish to do and what I can do to make it easier for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really good day to calm any work-load fears, the PM of the team has offered so much support than is great and I’m a huge supporter of offering help as much as possible and reminding others to not overload - in this case it was up to someone else to remind me as I totally didn’t respect my own limits.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/29/weeknotes-no23.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/29/weeknotes-no23.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.22</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An incredible week following on from last weeks’ stunner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the thing I prepped for last week and it went brilliantly. I managed to overcome past nerves of presenting (who’d of thought prepping in adv would remove nerves?) and the outcomes were wonderful.&lt;br /&gt;
Really loving the teams I am in at the moment, both give me space to learn and grow and provide me with the trust of my own skillset again (I never lost this inner belief, but its nice to be reminded by others).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is the start of a crazy week at work - a 3-day workshop!&lt;br /&gt;
I’m using today to write up the deck and prompt cards to present the design task on Wednesday and to help out on other parts of the workshop.&lt;br /&gt;
Planning the agenda, outputs, things needed and just hanging with a blinking great team.&lt;br /&gt;
If you guys ever read this - this team is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really looking forward to playing a big part in this workshop, it takes me back to my Sky Bet days where I would lead design tasks, either planning out a service/process map or getting into the actual design of a page (crazy 8s etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in the evening, we started to work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble's website&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble’s&lt;/a&gt; new look website.. it needs a little bit of attention and, as I have the odd year or two experience..I’m gonna do it and not rely on using templates that are not really “doing” what we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is the start of the workshop.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s been in planning for a while, and as a team, we were nervous, excited and prepared.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler - we didn’t need to be, it was brilliant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important job of the first day is to get everyone up to speed, whilst working in a friendly environment - accepting all questions, approaches, and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outline of the day is as follows (some is missing due to.. well I can’t share THAT much):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Introductions:&lt;br /&gt;
Round table introduction of each person - name, title, duration on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Scene Setting:&lt;br /&gt;
Why we are here, what we stand for etc&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ice Breaker:&lt;br /&gt;
10-15 min exercise to help the room get to know each other and get talking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our agenda and hopeful outcomes. An interactive ‘What do we want to achieve out of the workshops’:&lt;br /&gt;
Get the room to write on post its - what do they want out of the workshop, then break it down to day one, two and three (make sure you educate the room on the outline of each day without too much info).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Where we are and how we got there:&lt;br /&gt;
Discuss whats gone on before, and where we are (confirming the problem statement etc).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Agile Ways of Working:&lt;br /&gt;
Run through ways of working with the team, who does what and how we might run sprints, or handovers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hypotheses for Design:&lt;br /&gt;
Exersise to work out what do we wish to test after the design task. Tricky to do, so set the room up with examples, or educational piece.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Review and wrap up of day:&lt;br /&gt;
Lightly touch on what happened throughout the day, run through “day 1” post its and confirm we delivered or missed out on certain needs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The day I get to run the “Design task” to the group - this is my first one ran at DWP, so I am a little nervous, but thankfully and a huge thank you to “Voice in the room” (public speaking training), I knew to prep and how to say it - I have run many workshops before, but this one felt like one of my best.&lt;br /&gt;
I had planned out the introduction to the problem/opportunity and then stressed how safe we are as a room (we as a team had bonded enough by then), what we want to achieve at the end, the task, ran through the outcomes then bring it back to see if we did what we needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2’s outline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reflection:&lt;br /&gt;
Speak through what we did yesterday and the day’s plan&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ice Breaker:&lt;br /&gt;
Another ice breaker to get the room moving&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lessons Learnt:&lt;br /&gt;
What have we learned on previous projects that are similar (if any) using out-side-the-team presenters (U.R etc)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hypothesis Review (including dot voting):&lt;br /&gt;
Run through yesterday’s Hypothesis session, after a nights sleep there were questions to ask and different hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Design task:&lt;br /&gt;
As mentioned above, it was all leading to this magical moment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Review:&lt;br /&gt;
Confirm we did what we needed to do, and any outstanding questions before leading into the last day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The final day of the workshop - thankfully, I could sleep for a month!
Today is just a catch up, review and confirm we delivered everything we needed and everyone is ok with where we got as a team and to confirm the next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the easiest day of the week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A very chilled day, I worked through trying to read my notes and coming up with questions to ask from these notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retro in the afternoon and then a well deserved weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bobbin and Bumble update:&lt;br /&gt;
Since joining Emma as a consultant, we’ve managed (as a team) to up traffic and sales quite quickly within 3 months using a multitude of experiences and new learnings.&lt;br /&gt;
Combining her tone-of-voice and personality with SEO techniques, good design practice, general housekeeping, and goal setting - we’ve managed to run a tighter, more focused business approach and so far it has turned out to generate an amazing reaction from amazing customers and supporters.&lt;br /&gt;
I knew her products were good and desirable, it was just about getting it out there better, getting it to the audience clearer and making sure it was presented consistently.&lt;br /&gt;
And also not looking behind at people copying her style of products and presentation of products but looking ahead and seeing what the market is doing and wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rant alert&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One thing that did rile me and has made me more dedicated to making this a success was the amount of envy and attacks from the competition (not all, some have been so supportive and cheer-leading). I have never experienced this in my career, I’ve had people copy my work, even present my work in interviews as their own (Jet2 to name a famous one whilst at Sky Bet), but never call me out or even go to the level of bullying tactics.&lt;br /&gt;
We should be supporting each other, there is enough business out there for all and if you are threatened by a competitor then it’s says more about your own trust in products than someone else’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I can’t stress how great the teams are that I work on, we really are hitting form and the support and trust of each other is so amazing, and inspiring. We cheer and celebrate everything together, and if needed we swarm around a problem and help out. It’s all about helping and learning, not blaming and pointing, and I love that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I learned more about my own wants and direction in my career - I want to do service design things, I want to work with people and I want to support. This has been the busiest week for a long time, and I’m sure it’ll get busier, but it’s incredibly enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Work-load is creeping to a huge amount, I will call this out next week and know it’ll be sorted out as soon as I mention it, it’s always worth knowing when you feel the work-creep and let as many people know as possible, you are no good if you are producing low-end work and feeling rubbish. The team doesn’t want this, and more importantly - you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We did it! As a team we delivered a brilliant workshop, together and totally smashed it!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/weeknotes-no22.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/weeknotes-no22.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.21</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s great to be back in the thick of things.&lt;br /&gt;
What started out to be a slow and tough week (some things annoyed me somewhat), ended up being my best week in DWP as of yet.&lt;br /&gt;
I did things, things I’m good at and things I enjoy doing. I planned a workshop, I worked with a team that pushed me far and I delivered.&lt;br /&gt;
I also get to use past experiences to deliver something that (hopefully) will be an effective use of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First day properly back in the office since 2019 (yikes), and I can officially say I had no idea what is happening!&lt;br /&gt;
It took a while as expected to get the wheels in motion, which was a good job as we are planning a 3-day workshop for next week, and its plenty of work!  This is a new team I have entered since my last notes and it’s in a Service Design role, and its vastly different to my normal day to day role, but it feels nearer to what I think I do best (so far).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my other (original) team, the team is in prep for Discovery, this month is going to be super busy for me - but support is there and will be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using today to just catch up, build relationships and try to remember what happened last year and work out where we are going in the teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early doors meeting to listen to the team that did the project (that we are entering Discovery) before us - they were quite far in it but due to other requirements needed to pause their discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, I had 105 questions in regards to direction, blockers, frustrations and any opportunities we might have since they have done the project and what the original problem statement was. All in all, it was a great meeting and one, the team fully enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared learning and all that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in the afternoon was a session with Andy to run through a possible “new starters” kit. I love working on things that will make a new starters’ life a lot easier and calmer, I know from previous experience when starting new roles that on-boarding can make a job great, and bad onboarding can make you feel a little undervalued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today was the best day. I have recently been asked to step into a Service Design role for one of the teams and today, again I got to see if the shoe fits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far.. so good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels a natural move as Service Design seems to cover a lot of what Interaction Design doesn’t for me, but again its early doors and I haven’t found any struggles (but the team is great on supporting me as I’ve spelled it out there will be more wrongs than rights with my technique to start with).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a whiteboard session planning out the 3-day workshop, we are working with an external partner and we want the days to be totally useful for all. Being the designer of the group and thanks to Sky Bet especially, I have been led a lot of Workshops in the past and provided my tips. &lt;br /&gt;
We set goals, requirements, attendees, agenda, problem/purpose of the day etc - setting these out assisted in planning out the rest of the days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day ended with going home and finishing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/2020/01/09/weeknotes-no20-the-2019-review.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; and working on updating my work page on my site, it is missing a lot of work I’m proud of, so expect an update soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Coffee, earphones, planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is the day I write notes at 100mph - learning as much as possible from phone calls, face to face meetings and asking questions that are pre-planned or off the cuff. I warn everyone pre-meeting that I like to ask questions, and in all honesty, I’ve never faced any issue with this approach as everyone always wants to share their wins, fails and knowledge - knowing it will do the product well as it is passed down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had another whiteboard session to map out the “design task” of the workshop, a lot easier when working with someone from Policy / BA to find the ins-and-outs of the rules, must-haves that we need to include in the users-journey. End of day meeting, we discussed how the workshop will run - the full team is doing a part of each day which is great, hardly any pressure on anyone and sharing the work means we can chip in if anyone has a wobble or gets asked a question they aren’t sure of. &lt;br /&gt;
I shared my Design plan - the rules, task, intro, and timings and it seemed to make sense, if you have ever done a workshop with me previously you’ll know I don’t run a design task “tight”, I allow for a lot of changes and let the room dictate how it could be run - I don’t let it run wild but I also shy away from leading the process or worse.. doing design bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early doors Workshop - this one I’m participating in, not running (grateful for this fact!). It’s a session to work out the service’s initial vision and roadmap. A great session, loads of information sharing, fact-finding, and good outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day is finalising the “deck” for the design-task for next week!
Busy busy week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As mentioned in the opening paragraph, this week was great. It started with my feeling a little dejected due to resource issues, workload and a feeling of aimlessness. &lt;br /&gt;
Then Wednesday happened, I was doing what I had done so well for the past couple of years - sharing, telling, showing, learning and listening to a great team. I led meetings, I listened to meetings and we ended up with a really healthy result - &lt;strong&gt;that is team work. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I know the workload will eventually be too much, but the feeling of working out of my comfort zone is really pushing me to learn more and it feels a good place for my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I was asked last year to step into a Service Design role and accepted the challenge as I have always wondered what the role was, I still haven’t quite found out but so far it feels like something I would love. I’m unsure if I am actually doing it - but whatever it is I’m learning a lot and working a lot more open with members of the wider team, which is always great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week was full of them, the feeling I had on Monday-Tuesday was not great. I’m unsure what instigated it, but I also know it’s more on myself to set the vision for myself, find my own goals and work out what or how I want to gain them. &lt;br /&gt;
Also, Emma’s back went wonky again - so managing her work, her health and our daughter is always a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The stuff I learned working through Discovery is more than I could possibly write - sharing work, stepping back, facilitating meetings, allowing others to lead parts of a workshops and many many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More weeks like this are certainly ordered from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/15/weeknotes-no21.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/15/weeknotes-no21.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.20 - the 2019 review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I last wrote, I used Purdah as a chance to recharge my batteries, read over my past notes and see where I was, where I am and where I wish to go and do a 2019 review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a wild year, (spoiler alert) over the year my daughter turned 4, my wife upped her business to another level, we had an election and I changed jobs and the big one - I GOT A NEW KITCHEN!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At the start of 2019, I started to feel a little lost in my career - feeling “itchy feet” is a strange feeling when you are happy and content, but I felt I wanted to offer more and do more, more than I was currently offering.&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, I felt I was not giving 100% to the job, which I had done so much for, I had run at the job at 100mph giving 100% and really wanted to make a change to the design culture there, learning as much as possible from an incredible manager and sharing even more, looking back at my time at Sky Bet, I did achieved this and would not change a thing, and I feel really proud of my time there, the output of work by the team led to a lot of accolades (getting to number 1 in the App downloads for Sky Sports Super 6 game, gaining more players for Sky Sports Fantasy Football and working on relationships with stakeholders are things I am really proud of).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a note - anyone who is thinking of joining and working at Sky Bet, I recommend the experience and can confirm you will learn so much there and the people are really top notch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May, I decided to leave Sky Bet to move to a place I was very familiar with - DWP (Department for Work and Pensions), citing a change of career direction and to really push my skillset to the limit. I knew the potential of someone like myself working there, and felt if I take everything from Sky Bet to here I could really make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow my weeknotes, you’ll know I found the change of culture and work very tough to dive into, it is a total change of pace - whereas at Sky Bet you work fast and change things at speed, at DWP you need to plan, you need to research, and you need to talk to a much bigger audience (be them stakeholders or users). THIS is the challenge I have always wanted, I want to manage workloads, I want to influence people, I want to present in front of a room that is full of the most intelligent heads in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, I have also changed how I design - I care a lot less about the aesthetic and more about content, the why and how someone will use the page (not in this order). I care about the research (I always have), I care about the cost, and I care about the end user and the end result and more importantly - I care about the service we are putting out, is it the right service?, can it be better?, should we be doing the service? and 1005 other questions, which I am more than happy to voice and challenge with the knowledge that this is a safe approach and the teams I work in not only expect this of me, they welcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bobbin and Bumble launch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This year my wife Emma proudly re-launched her company with new branding and a new name.
Gone is xMimiMakes and welcome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;click here to visit my wife's website Bobbin and Bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt;, this turned out to be more work than we expected due to relaunching the Instagram account (starting from 0), updating and making new sales points (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/bobbinandbumblebaby&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble on etsy&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;click here to visit my wife's website Bobbin and Bumble&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;), and finding manufacturers that would do what Emma needed them to do, and when she needed them to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tough stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also alongside teaching Emma how to use design software, which was actually really easy as she has the ability to just “keep going” on her own and working it out herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daughter Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Watching my daughter grow up into a strong independent person who has her own ideas, sayings and jokes whilst being so eager to learn and listen has been a journey I was not expecting, but one I’ve enjoyed a lot - she has reminded me to be more open about being creative (reading books in silly voices or emphasising certain words actually helped me do more public speaking for example), and obviously she had made my life a hell of a lot more fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 brought on our first parent’s evening - which she did so well on and was labelled a “role-model” to the younger children coming in as she takes care of them, she did her first play (she was a donkey!), she rode her first bike, she reminded me how much she hates football, she still doesn’t know what I do for a job (but neither does her mother), and her favourite film of 2019 was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5117670/&quot; title=&quot;link to peter rabbit film on IMDB&quot;&gt;Peter Rabbit&lt;/a&gt; AND it was the first year she knew properly what Christmas is, and got overly excited on Christmas eve (demanding she goes to sleep as soon as possible before Santa finds her awake).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in store for 2020?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The past 6 months, I have felt very different about my career - my duties changed and the ways of working changed.&lt;br /&gt;
Whereas before, it more user-conversion led and quite an one-directional approach (idea-research-design-launch-next), I am now working in a more “Service Design” role and leaving the side of design that I fell out of love with and this new role feels a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to talk more, share more and work with a lot of differing roles to spread ways-of-working efficiently and effectively - using past techniques that have worked, I also want to know what can we, designers do better to help make relationships and working a lot easier and smoother for all.&lt;br /&gt;
I want to empower designers to make decisions, hard decisions and call out things when they are wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
I want to feel valued, I want design to feel valued and I want people to know enough about design as they can do without feeling overwhelmed or undervalued themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can I do this in a year? Maybe, maybe not - but what better place to do it that here, with the support of many I am going to give it a good go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, the election was a tricky time - due to the services I am currently working on I got to see some of the people directly affected by past and current voting, which in turn did affect me in a way I didn’t expect, but I do believe those that are working on these services are the best and as a team, we will do a great job - it might be a struggle, we might lose people on the way but we will succeed and we will make a great difference to a lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all in all an interesting year compared to 2018 – I’ve learned and changed a lot, seen my family grow and seen a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed your 2019, and if not – let’s make 2020 the best one, however sometimes tough that might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, 2020 I want to get back into giving back, so please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;/contact.html&quot; title=&quot;get in touch&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;, I have a successful past in mentoring many different people, all at differing stages of their career - be it a total fresh start to wanting advice on becoming more senior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/09/weeknotes-no20-the-2019-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/09/weeknotes-no20-the-2019-review.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonky week of WFH and in the office.&lt;br /&gt;
Having your house smashed to bits is not how to prepare for a relaxing Christmas, but hopefully it’ll run so smoothly I wont even realise I’m filing the kettle up from the bathroom tap, washing up in the shower and having sandwiches for each dinner. Barely noticable..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plus points was Monday - worked so well with the wider team, having a U.R. touch point for help, and he’s been great - so helpful.
Working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/robynandmimi/&quot; title=&quot;my wifes instagram account - Robyn and Mimi&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt; has been a huge highlight as well, I’ve shared all I know about managing projects, building emails to writing (hopefully) interesting posts, reminds me of the old days of contracting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Catch ups as normal at work with the wider design team.
Also, working alongside a User Researcher for advice, its been an interesting learning experience working without a User Researcher in the team and filling in the gaps.
Doing a discussion guide, finding out assumptions/questions, getting the team to see what they class as possible issues look for trends in the pile of issues that the users have sent in (using Jira as a base to post these issues to).
I’ve enjoyed this, always great to learn more when possible and the level of support received from the team and business in this resource shortage has been good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, my evenings are taken up working on Emma’s business website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://bobbinandbumble.com&quot; title=&quot;click here to see bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt;, reworking the site to v2 to add more content to the home page, it’s been an interesting journey getting the site live, we’ve had minor issues along the way - which, back in my contracting days I would have caught instantly.. but the rust is showing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH - builders are in!&lt;br /&gt;
Anxiety is on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of loud terrible noises, and pure panic from myself. Ahh - who’s idea was this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finalising the discussion guide in preparation for tomorrow’s run through with the content designer.&lt;br /&gt;
Day of doing the admin jobs, as it’s nice and quiet.. well its nice.. well i’m at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Another WFH day, quiet days like this are perfect for learning - which means for me… reading up on discovery processes from pages such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/agile-delivery/how-the-discovery-phase-works&quot; title=&quot;gov.uk discovery guide&quot;&gt;Gov.UK Discovery guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a while since I was part of the early days of a project (4 years), so it’s great to have a refresher and to share my findings with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Morning stand up, as I’ve been out of the office for two days these are useful so I know what others are up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick chat through on the UR plans for visiting and conducting interviews, and then confirming the discussion guide - just a date and location to decide on now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the project is nearer an end - I’m looking forward to the health check that I have needed to instigate, hopefully it shows everything is running as smoothly as hoped, but also to let them feel listened to and do any fixes that need doing instantly to the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workload has lightened up, allowing me to work on the “community” things that DWP does so well. Speaking to other team members, seeing what I can take from my previous experience working with other design teams and share and just “be in the same room and listen” to how the team is functioning and check for any patterns.&lt;br /&gt;
This is the stuff I love doing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Somehow.. the team is all WFH (including me) - so a morning chat on Slack is needed. You can tell this team is a healthy pack of friends and colleagues by the fact we take turns when talking, wait for the conversation to end, and comment. And proudly - if there is a problem we all swarm around and help, if needed we down tools and assist. It might be one of the friendliest and most helpful teams i’ve ever worked in. It’s amazing and a real joy to spend my working hours with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are soon to go into Discovery, and I’ve given myself the task of lining up some meetings with colleagues who have gone through the discovery “adventure” before, and see what they are doing, done and find out how they found the whys and do the hows and to share to the team the findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sharing issues with London and Manchester shows that as a team - we can really work well together. In our time of need (we are under-resourced in User Researchers at the moment), we could call upon one and he instantly offered his help and understood our situation. He may not be able to do “field work” (being onsite to speak to users), but he can and is assisting us in doing it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Great to work outside of work, and remind myself I can launch a product. Working with my wife on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bobbinandbumble.com&quot; title=&quot;click here to see bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt; has been a highlight - its reminded me of ways to prioritise work, wider thinking, and building emails (that one I would happily forget).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tough to keep motivated sometimes when house / building issues arise, work gets busier, and I also promised to deliver on my wife’s website. Thankfully, I’ve been here before and learned to say no in the past, but its always tough when I have promised on things that NEED to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I read up on onsite SEO, I built emailers, I planned campaigns, I somehow managed a team of builders, I stayed motivated and I managed to keep positive. &lt;br /&gt;Thank god the week is over!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/05/weeknotes-no19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/11/05/weeknotes-no19.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ego or Self Esteem?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use to be ok describing myself as “having a big ego”, it felt it was the right description to share how I felt, and it’s taken a good number of years to realise it’s not ego, it’s self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego has its stigma, who wants an ego? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve all worked in teams where the room is jam packed of egos, all shouting, all pressing, all wanting their point of view to be THE point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ego doesn’t back down though, &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ego doesn’t listen, &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ego can kill other people’s esteem, it can take over a room, it can dictate a room and you become the person everyone doesn’t like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that me? &lt;br /&gt;
Is that you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between ego and self-esteem is tricky to work out, purposely fooling us that both are the same, yet outwardly they are so different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ego is - envy, greed, anger, power, control, loud. &lt;br /&gt;
Self-esteem is - joy, peace, love, kindness, empathy, less powerful. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ego says I know everything. &lt;br /&gt;
Self-esteem wants to learn from everyone. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-esteem wants to grow and not settle, ego drowns in knowing and switching off, why learn when you know it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard the saying “leave your ego at the door”, you certainly can’t make others do this but you can check your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve mentored for the past 10 years, and line managed for vast amounts of my career and I’ve seen that ego has cost so many people opportunities, relationships or job promotions. Ego provides short quick gains but it’s a marathon not a 100m sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combating this mentality is tough, if you can manage to differentiate the two, you can teach it forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I break it down to these two (hopefully simple) points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego is a comparison tool&lt;/strong&gt; - you compare yourself to them and either justifying your growth via someone else’s failure or your ability to get the praise you need.&lt;br /&gt;
Simple comments such as “I launched a business and sold out in days” is a statement you should be proud of, but it’s also a comparison statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-esteem is also a comparison tool, but so different,&lt;/strong&gt; it compares yourself to yourself. It compares you to a previous milestone “this time last year I wanted to start a business, well I did it” or
“I started a business and I can’t believe it compared to where I was last year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is huge and quite obvious. Having a competitive edge against yourself is far easier to track, and it’s 100% honest and more importantly - a lot healthier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself unsure which side you are on - try a day of writing up “what you did” in bullets, and see which points stand out and what the feeling was behind them. Was it a positive “thing” that built up everyone else or yourself, or did it affect others in a negative way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if this post was useful by getting in touch &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikeycattell&quot; title=&quot;follow me on twitter at mikeycattell&quot;&gt;@mikeycattell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 21:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/24/ego-or-self-esteem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/24/ego-or-self-esteem.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.18</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve said this before, but I have really landed on my feet with the team I’m in. Being able to lead on the design, and the bit that excites me the most - lead on how we “do” design is so much fun and where I see my strengths.
Along the way, the team has learned that we all have a “design say”, and you should not be scared of getting involved in designing with me, after all they play a huge part in the overall User Experience of the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has really felt great and handing over my first “big” design piece went so smooth, no shocks, no surprises and certainly no friction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll on next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning stand-up with the rest of the wider team - technology means we can discuss the weeks work with teams from London, Manchester, and obv including us Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thing we never discuss is how many e-learning courses you HAVE to do upon joining a new company. This morning to the afternoon was a complete write-off due to learning about Health and Safety.
E-learning done in flash? YES PLEASE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afternoons on Monday are reserved for show and tells, we managed to show off one of the projects I’ve worked very lightly on. It’s a project I’ve been amongst, seeing it climb heights and hit lows - but the consistency has been a great design team behind it.
A big discussion point from the show and tell was unexpected - a Design System issue, is it up to date? are we using the correct one? do we need to work closer together and get it updated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally believe our design system is a good one, and you can use styles and patterns from either of them (if they work.. they work), but consistency is important and I’m unsure we talk enough about using it in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Worked from home in the morning, i’m sure i’ll look back at today and think this seemed so long ago but.. I will ask this question over and over again:
“WHY IS IT SO HARD TO GET A NEW KITCHEN PUT IN A HOUSE?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to work.. in the afternoon I returned to the office to handover the prototype Izzy and myself have been working on. The meeting involved Product Owner, Business Analysis and a Developer / QA.
Started off with the “why we are doing it”, followed by current implemenation, to a sketch of user-flow and finally showing the world (avoiding at all cost the “real estate tour”), explaining why we did this pattern etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype didn’t surprise anyone due to us all designing the flow, and pages together - so it was a piece of cake. Minor amends to parts of the page needing to be elsewhere (It was a misunderstanding on my part).
Out of this meeting, my actions were:
Finish prototype with minor amends, update Jira ticket and.. job done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how design should be done, i’m sure there will be harder pieces of work but it was a brilliant issue to pick as the teams first design walk-through and really showed the value of team designing, and also letting me “do my thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A busy day finishing off the prototype, which is a lot easier than I ever expected.
Handover to the developers will be a piece of cake too, as they have no surprises coming - they helped design it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handing over the prototype means, discussing (a lot) with the Product Owner and Business Analysis on how to write up tickets, if we can split any user flows up and what outcomes need to be viewed and accounted for.
Lots of Jira stuff, that I always try and hide away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 On leave.
Spent the day with my daughter going pumpkin picking and going to a farm with tons of Halloween activities!
Heck of a muddy day, but a fun fun day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH today, working heavily on the future of the product I am on.
Morning used to dial into the morning stand up with the team - worked really well and reminded me of my Sky Bet days!
Preparation for the afternoon’s meeting, running through the team’s requirements of a User Researcher (we are running a team without one) with the Lead UR of my department.
Meeting went so well, really liked her opinion and approach and certainly feel supported in our next steps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aim next week is to forge a working relationship with the team in London, and hopefully share work and get their answers (if you know me.. you’ll know I believe in “if the work has done before.. dont re-invent the wheel”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finishing the prototype and everyone being on board with it proved that the process we have decided on (so far) works, and works well. It led from user feedback, hard questions of “is this the best thing we can do” to “I’m unsure about this design” to “lets whack this into a prototype!” to finally everyone agreeing its good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I believe, as a team we have learned together we can improve the service so much more by working together. We are such a close-knit team that any issues, or even “feelings” that the service isnt as good as it should be - it shouted out and tackled together.&lt;br /&gt;
This is how design should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding User Research resource! I enjoy having a UR on my team, so speaking to the Lead User Resarch on Friday was amazing and allows myself and the Product Owner to feel supported and it was just an ace meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I promise i’ll stop talking about it.. but as a team we did a thing, it went well, and we will be launching the changes soon.&lt;br /&gt;
This is ace.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 09:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/weeknotes-no18.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/weeknotes-no18.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.17</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sad week, losing a really strong and clever Delivery Manager but he has given a lot of education to the team which we shall keep using and take us forward.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Really enjoyed this week again, loads of “doing” and team working.
We’ve really worked well together, a healthy discussion on taking the service forward and a good understanding of what each role does. It’s less about stepping on toes, as more to understanding what-we-do.
&lt;br /&gt;
Lovely stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand-ups a plenty, standard Monday.
Running through initial “edit user” information page, following on from the team’s design session with the B.A and content design to sense check.
Upon running through, it did not really fit the service needs, this is exactly the design feedback I require and ways of working to improve myself and more importantly, the user’s service experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon was spent sketching user flows, and going through what patterns suit this page. Was great to do this, as initial planning is my favourite task of the design process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Quiet day today, running through the prototype and sketching up user flows to help the team understand the issues of what we initially planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always the way - you run away from a design workshop thinking you have all the answers, get to your desk and find out the questions do not align with the answers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early kick-off meeting - running through all the content feedback and design patterns check. Loads of little minor amends, but will add so much to the user experience - quick wins with huge value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally - after 4 months of waiting… i’ve picked up all of my hardware to be a fully-fledged DWP worker!&lt;br /&gt;
I CAN SEE MY PAYSLIPS EASILY!&lt;br /&gt;
This pick up of hardware did mean a 2 hour tutorial on how to use the Surface Pro, which I’m maybe a tad late to learn this as its basically a windows machine - BUT parts of the meeting were about how to use the internal system which I 100% need to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The bus ran late - standard, so soon as I arrived it was Sprint Planning, but this team is so smooth now and we are in the days of bug fixing and automation - the planning is done in half the time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As if coincidence, the Delivery Manager’s last week here, he has been a breath of fresh air - he has controlled the room during retros etc, and also provided a level of trust that is often overlooked as a DM. A role that is often missed is the role of keeping the team as happy as possible - whether it be work-wise or team personality clashes.. he has managed to do that very well.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Be hugely missed, but I did get his locker - so… win some lose some.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last hour of the day - ran through the prototype with the content designer (Izzy), and we nailed it - we landed the big one! Did a very simple sketch of the user journey, Izzy changed one thing and saved a wasted page.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The power of doing good content eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As normal, quiet in the office.
Stand up to confirm the prototype is ready to be written up properly in tickets on Jira (the developers know what’s coming from the previous meeting), will be doing a run-through Monday or Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great way to end the day by finishing the sprint task, and having many more lined up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Realising you are wrong, and willing to fix it from other people’s ideas.
This is a secret power that all designers should have, many people over the years have crossed my work out and come up with something much more clever - DWP has this in spades and something I try to promote and get everyone thinking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How powerful is good content on a page?&lt;br /&gt;
It saved me trying to mangle a user-flow into a longer journey, a simple phase from Izzy and the page vastly improved and cut down so much more work for both design, dev and more importantly - the user.&lt;br /&gt;
Great content makes my job so so much easier - value content more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding services is tough - there is not an easy way to get “it”, but have time and confidence to ask the easy or hard questions makes my job a lot easier and a lot more comfortable. This is a huge credit to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a team - we did a thing that will be a great time saver for the users, AND they get what they wanted!&lt;br /&gt;
So many wins, from designing as a team to making the users happy, to avoiding user risk.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 19:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/14/weeknotes-no17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/14/weeknotes-no17.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perfecting the pitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During long discussions with designers over the years, often the subject that our roles are not understood properly is mentioned as if it’s a badge to wear.
It’s changed over the years, from “they’ve no idea what I do, they’ve got me designing PowerPoint presentations” to “they just made the decision themselves” to the unacceptable “they didn’t even include me in the meeting”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Of course it does and you know why? We’ve all said it, damn it I’VE said it.&lt;br /&gt;
The amount of times over the years I’ve complained about “teams not getting it” or asking people around me “why didn’t they ask me to do it?” And they’ve replied &lt;br /&gt;
“We didn’t know that’s what you do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s taken a while to realise it was my fault, and when I knew this it was so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The turning point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever been asked at a wedding to do your elevator pitch? 
“So what do you do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you have, and in 6-seconds-you-have-between-floors to answer:
“umm I’m a… designer”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“….. that’s great”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can’t tell a stranger what I do for my 9-5 what chance does a team have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use to introduce myself as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Hi, I’m a designer, I design websites for companies. Sometimes I design emails, logos and often I build websites too”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So general, so boring, so me me me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way of introducing is “pattern fitting”, it’s forcing them down the avenue of “what you want them to want you for”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want the answer to be around them, they are the hero here - they are either looking for a solution for themselves or want to help a friend - it’s cool to send a message to someone “hey, I’ve met someone who will help you do your thing and turn it into reality”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was once told a quick tip to remember when doing your pitch:
Tell a story, it’s not about you, it’s about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break it down into three steps:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The who,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The do,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The who’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The who’s is a great one to open up, but often the toughest. A lot is relying on you knowing the answer, and being proud of it. Your audience parents of new borns? Or Dog owners? Or agencies short of staff? Whatever it is, it’s a niche, it’s your speciality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get specific on the who - if it doesn’t suit their needs, I promise you they will know someone who it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite one, this is the one which is the most fun, once you’ve got this worked out you’ll have the skills to make people believe in you, respect you and more important know what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do&lt;/strong&gt; - this is after your work, after your solution - talk about how great lives are after. If they are interested - talk more about it, if not you might need to change your approach to match them (you’ll do something they’ll need or like), find the common ground and hone in on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point of this all? 
Leading to telling them what you can do for them. 
So you design websites for start ups?
What is it you actually do for these start ups?
Help with growing their user base? Build communities?
Whatever it is, make them picture success - their success, the projects success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting this all together is no easy feat, but once mastered it’ll help integrate you into a team, sell your work, and educate anyone nearby to what you do, hopefully leaving no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve fluffed many introductions, but with this template it goes something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I’m an interaction designer for DWP, 
I (help teams) help the general public have an easier life by providing them with a simple way of using online and offline services, enabling them to take control and manage their own life and make the whole process as stressless as possible.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should warrant enough of a response to find out more, this is new territory so don’t fluff your lines now - you’ve got them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on interest, I would them dip into a bit more about the process - how do I enable the users to manage their own life with examples, then go into success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to turn this into your day to day work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can make a stranger understand your role, you can certainly make someone who is sat either a slack call or a shout over the desk away “get you”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you do not need to do the introduction routine, but you can certainly become a lot clearer on your own reason for being there, and help to remind others why you are there, and if you need to introduce yourself to a new starter - then you are prepared to start that relationship off on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this post has provided value to a tough subject, it’s not perfect but it’s a start and I would love to see and hear how you introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
