<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:46:25 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:46:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perfecting the pitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During long discussions with designers over the years, often the subject that our roles are not understood properly is mentioned as if it’s a badge to wear.
It’s changed over the years, from “they’ve no idea what I do, they’ve got me designing PowerPoint presentations” to “they just made the decision themselves” to the unacceptable “they didn’t even include me in the meeting”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Of course it does and you know why? We’ve all said it, damn it I’VE said it.&lt;br /&gt;
The amount of times over the years I’ve complained about “teams not getting it” or asking people around me “why didn’t they ask me to do it?” And they’ve replied &lt;br /&gt;
“We didn’t know that’s what you do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s taken a while to realise it was my fault, and when I knew this it was so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The turning point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever been asked at a wedding to do your elevator pitch? 
“So what do you do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you have, and in 6-seconds-you-have-between-floors to answer:
“umm I’m a… designer”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“….. that’s great”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can’t tell a stranger what I do for my 9-5 what chance does a team have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use to introduce myself as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Hi, I’m a designer, I design websites for companies. Sometimes I design emails, logos and often I build websites too”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So general, so boring, so me me me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way of introducing is “pattern fitting”, it’s forcing them down the avenue of “what you want them to want you for”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want the answer to be around them, they are the hero here - they are either looking for a solution for themselves or want to help a friend - it’s cool to send a message to someone “hey, I’ve met someone who will help you do your thing and turn it into reality”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was once told a quick tip to remember when doing your pitch:
Tell a story, it’s not about you, it’s about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break it down into three steps:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The who,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The do,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The who’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The who’s is a great one to open up, but often the toughest. A lot is relying on you knowing the answer, and being proud of it. Your audience parents of new borns? Or Dog owners? Or agencies short of staff? Whatever it is, it’s a niche, it’s your speciality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get specific on the who - if it doesn’t suit their needs, I promise you they will know someone who it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite one, this is the one which is the most fun, once you’ve got this worked out you’ll have the skills to make people believe in you, respect you and more important know what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do&lt;/strong&gt; - this is after your work, after your solution - talk about how great lives are after. If they are interested - talk more about it, if not you might need to change your approach to match them (you’ll do something they’ll need or like), find the common ground and hone in on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point of this all? 
Leading to telling them what you can do for them. 
So you design websites for start ups?
What is it you actually do for these start ups?
Help with growing their user base? Build communities?
Whatever it is, make them picture success - their success, the projects success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting this all together is no easy feat, but once mastered it’ll help integrate you into a team, sell your work, and educate anyone nearby to what you do, hopefully leaving no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve fluffed many introductions, but with this template it goes something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I’m an interaction designer for DWP, 
I (help teams) help the general public have an easier life by providing them with a simple way of using online and offline services, enabling them to take control and manage their own life and make the whole process as stressless as possible.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should warrant enough of a response to find out more, this is new territory so don’t fluff your lines now - you’ve got them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on interest, I would them dip into a bit more about the process - how do I enable the users to manage their own life with examples, then go into success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to turn this into your day to day work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can make a stranger understand your role, you can certainly make someone who is sat either a slack call or a shout over the desk away “get you”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you do not need to do the introduction routine, but you can certainly become a lot clearer on your own reason for being there, and help to remind others why you are there, and if you need to introduce yourself to a new starter - then you are prepared to start that relationship off on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this post has provided value to a tough subject, it’s not perfect but it’s a start and I would love to see and hear how you introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.16</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I did some designing stuff this week, and it was brilliant!
Leading this team into a new era of design and development working together has been such a joy, and I cant wait for more design gatherings.&lt;br /&gt;
Also happening this week, was a day of taking stock and realising that I cant carry on with two teams, so officially left a team and have concentrated my attention on one team with design backlog bigger than you could ever dream of (they haven’t had a designer since January).&lt;br /&gt;
The challenge is huge, but im happy to be knee-deep in work, deciding with the team which pieces to work on, showing value, getting everyone to design and the doing, the talking and the showing of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early discussions with the P.O. about where a project is heading, we both agreed that we should get it to a level of being able to let it go, this then started another discussion on planning “online user life improvements” - so tasked myself with checking for broken design patterns, acting on UR feedback and any feedback which is daily given to our P.O/BAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two designers from Manchester came to Leeds, great to catch up with other team members and see whats happening else where, most catch ups are not always about sharing work but ways-of-working that interests me the most.
Plenty of chats about how to deal with personalities, issues on sharing work and finding your voice within the team.
Lots of sharing and learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Backlog meeting - need to plan out future U.R with one, idea is to use a UR as a consultant as waiting time is too short as the project is winding down.
Will use U.R. to line up possible, will run through previous UR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran a design gathering, the first the team has ever had in the open - it was an honest, round table discussion with good.. no GREAT solutions and it felt totally normal and comfortable. This really felt like we’ve turned a corner and design getting the seat at the table it needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.O. also provided feedback afterwards to me, he found it brilliant, proactive and enjoyed having a solid output/actions list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning retro of the retro - a session to discuss team happiness around hot desking / lack of chairs.
I’m unsure how I feel about this retro, part of me felt really awkward and hesitant to talk, other part of me also realised that there isn’t enough seats in the area and this causes expected friction - everyone likes to have a “home” in an office. Unsure the fix, and I’m unsure everyone came out of it happier than when they went in - but time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caught up with my line manager Juliana, amazing to run through how much has changed in 3 months, from discussing lightly about design to leading a design gathering around a tv and getting others to design verbally.
Speaking of the design gathering.. rest of the day prototyping!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The day was taken up with updating the prototype, working out a system to take the prototype forward.
In short: I want to split the prototype up a little tidier, per sprint instead of doing a list of “tasks”, this way we keep focus on sections and journeys rather than the developers expecting a fully functioning prototype (that we all know will be broken!). Lowering and re-educating expectations and reasons for the prototype, whilst working at speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started also working through the existing platform, for a design run-through - with the lack of knowledge of how the user is working with the system, I am just checking the design patterns used are suitable for the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Friday is NUX day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was ace, caught up with loads of ex-colleagues from Sky Bet, and current work buddies from DWP.
In regards to the talks - I really really enjoyed &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThatGirlVim&quot; title=&quot;follow thatgirlvim on twitter&quot;&gt;Vimla Appadoo&lt;/a&gt; talk on “It’s Time to Redesign Design”, its right up my street and I love her approach and talk on showing and talking about the value of design away from the pretty stuff.
Also worth a shout was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Amy_Hupe&quot; title=&quot;follow amy on twitter&quot;&gt;Amy Hupe’s&lt;/a&gt; talk - funny, enlightening and totally interesting on “Inclusive Documentation”. My content designer pals were going crazy with notes and pictures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always forget though how long NUX is - early and late finish, but i’ll do it all again next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/weeknotes-no16.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/weeknotes-no16.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.15</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time 7 years ago I got married - so the week started off on a brilliant high!&lt;br /&gt;
I’m really excited to see what happens next week (which is strange as im doing a week notes for the past week), but we get to start seeing if the design process is going to work and how it is going to work within the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today was my wedding anniversary - so it was a well earned day off.
&lt;br /&gt;
7 brilliant years of being married, with more than I can remember years of dating before. I’ve learned so much about myself since dating Emma, she has given me self-confidence, self-worth and a drive that I could never have if it wasn’t for her.   &lt;br /&gt;Also, she finds me funny - so she’s obviously perfect..
&lt;br /&gt;
We went on a date at the cinema to watch “Hustlers” (Emma’s choice) and binge ate at a rather brilliant place called “Blue Sakura”. It was a great day and as a bonus I got to take my daughter to school and pick her up as a surprise - so she was really excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Caught up about the User Research feedback from last week, incredibly insightful when all the information is grouped together, and it’s great to see the UR team presenting and being strong about the work they do. I now await to see the next steps from the P.O.
&lt;br /&gt;
A content design catch up, explaining what I’m currently working on and how our “pre-planning” meeting went (dealing with design backlog), it turns out there is a lot of want from the team to get the design rolling and really make our users happy. I can’t really express how excited to try this new process, we can get the process wrong and it feels totally safe to, and the content design is totally onboard with it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up in “Team Two” are really good now, adding a design section to the board has really caused great discussions, the aim for me is to allow all the team to know every ticket on the board and the “why” we are doing them. 
&lt;br /&gt;After stand up, we planned additional discussions on what to work on next, felt really valued as a designer (which isn’t always the feeling) and a lot of good work ahead and plenty of opportunities to make a difference! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Attended a Retro&lt;/strong&gt; - good open session (as they always are), things needing to be shared and ownership of the issue. A lot of discussions on hot desking / seat arrangements which is causing a rift. &lt;br /&gt;
Similar trends running through the recent retro’s, actions being taken away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sprint Planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Goals set for this sprint are “focus on integration”, design work is being measured (correctly) by value (user and business) against effort. &lt;br /&gt;
Biggest conversational point from the design team (I’m happy to put my name on this) is if we should action some design amends due to one product not following GOV.UK styles, components and patterns. 
&lt;br /&gt;
I know we should change it - but.. value against effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Blinking BUS ISSUES!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Attended my other teams Sprint planning - a great round table approach. Discussed lack of User Researcher being an issue and a high risk when making design decisions (something I’m not comfortable on). Also discussed how to hand over design and content work to developers correctly (surrounding when, how and the whys).&lt;br /&gt;
Ideally, the answer is “as soon as possible”, I feel the team works best when everyone is involved in the design process (from sketching to round tables), so to avoid design decisions being tested and not being able to be implemented due to data/development issues. My ex-life as a developer has made me 100% sure this is the right ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A very quiet day in the office, Friday’s are famous for WFH or people’s non-working day. Had my 1:1 with Head of Design, discussed how my time shared between two teams is starting to have an impact on the work I do, and time spent actually working.&lt;br /&gt;
A quick look at my diary showed me - out of a 37 hour working week, I actually had 12 hours to sit at my desk and “do” work I needed to do.
The outcome was agreed that I would slowly work with just one team, which for me personally feels a great move as initially I worked closer with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Celebrating my wedding anniversary was such a fun day, and it was nice to spend a complete day with my wife, on our own doing normal couple things, which is always a struggle when you have a little one, but we should do it more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
User Research is really really good, and its key we have access to it almost as easy as it is to get access to a developer. Without one, we are struggling to get work done, as we have more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Accepting that I cannot do it all, I do not need to go to every meeting, I cannot help everyone and I need to realise that I have a limited time per-week and is it better to give 50% on two projects or 100% on one? I personally feel one project, and many others have agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First time in a while, I feel this week was a flat week. Some highs, but a couple of lows in there too - not a terrible week, just felt the week ran away from me before I caught it up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/03/weeknotes-no15.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/03/weeknotes-no15.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.14</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Testing all day in Harrogate.&lt;br /&gt;
I love going to Harrogate to see the team and more importantly check in with the users, Speaking to them means we are listening to their needs, and taking their feedback on board - which is why we are doing this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was no different, going in with assumptions and the user totally blowing them out of the water - standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today, early doors was a pre-pre-planning. Simply put, team two works their way through the backlog with designers, BA, dev, PO and DM and we work out when we need it, what do we need, and why we need it. &lt;br /&gt; 
Makes sense? It really does, it’s a new thing that we are testing out, and it feels a huge step forward for my complete squad. I hope it makes a difference. &lt;br /&gt; 
Also we discussed how to work together better and get the developers in the process quicker, something I am deeply passionate about - design shouldn’t be run silo, it’s a team sport, as is UX.  Definition of ready: how to ensure tickets are ready to play - really good meeting, we ended up with 7 points that we all decided (as a team) to be the right ones (for now), a strong design presence in the room (and it wasn’t me!), others involving user and business needs, and development / QA requirements.  &lt;br /&gt; 
Also needing to be put on the table is a “success criteria” and how do we measure. One for the future, but again, one I’m passionate about - I love celebrating wins, but also finding out about losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Caught up with content designer and ran through the 2 meetings I had yesterday.
U.C.D meet up - ran through my tasks at current, strong discussion on types of prototype tools we use, I didn’t even know we used most (any) of them, I always thought DWP worked with coded prototypes, but a lot were included in the list - from sketch to marvel to axure!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Afternoon - white board session..YES! Ran through a page to edit user information - so many scenarios and possible outcomes, made a lot clearer by working with a BA and PO who are willing to make it as simple-to-understand. Finished the whiteboard session with sketches on a whiteboard (as a team I’m trying to use processes in everything and this is one) and actions to be done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This. Is. How. It. Works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH day - every now and then I like to get out of the office and work on things without noise. This allows me to catch up on emails, write prep notes for the week/sprint after and to just catch my breath.&lt;br /&gt;
Today was exactly this - digest what i’ve worked on, tidy up my computer desktop and files, plan my next tasks, read and reply to emails, slack people who I need to arrange meetings with and other general admin.&lt;br /&gt;
This is promoted often in companies, and is one of the first questions I ask at interviews: &lt;br /&gt;What is the work/life balance like?&lt;br /&gt;
Answers can vary - but it’s easy to work out quickly if it’s suitable to match your own needs.&lt;br /&gt;
(All my previous perm jobs have ALWAYS matched my need for space and to work on my own and cater for childcare issues).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Spent time using the internal system to gain access to benefits and pension information - in the past couple of years I’ve really started to take care of this side of work, and having a good pension is a great start!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Started to prototype the design work required from the whiteboard session, using Sketch to produce flat jpgs before going near a prototype - I design as a team, so it’s always discussions first then upon agreement, we then go into prototypes to test, this enables sign off within the team for: 
&lt;br /&gt;What data is available, &lt;br /&gt;Can we build it, &lt;br /&gt;Is this the right thing to do, &lt;br /&gt;Is the design right, &lt;br /&gt;Why are we doing this.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I always want honestly in my work, and providing an open table gathering means you have to be honest and open about questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday. We worked as a team to get an outcome we all agreed to, and it felt so right. It was a room full of respect, intelligence and the want to succeed. &lt;br /&gt;I cannot stress how much I enjoy working in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not necessary a learned thing, but remembering how Sky Bet was when I first joined and the struggles, the learnings and the success we had as a team to provide a smooth design and delivery process has spurred me on endless to really get it right here. It’s not perfect at the moment, but there is always hope and incredible potential to get there - working with a team of high achievers wanting to do the right thing is a benefit that I appreciate.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have a plan in mind and an end goal that I’ve shared often with my line managers, and it’s close to getting there, and I’m proud of the team that has helped me correct, change, and vastly improve my plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working within a team that is busy often leads to poor communication, and we’ve felt that over the past couple of weeks, and this week was the conclusion of that. It’s not easy to feel overlooked, and it’s hard to not take it personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The whiteboard session was brilliant, I’m so happy to see how great we worked together getting to a possible solution quickly, and as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 21:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/02/weeknotes-no14.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/02/weeknotes-no14.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Confidence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lacking confidence was a problem I hid for so long, it embarrassed me, it held me back and it ruled my career for so long. &lt;br /&gt;
As you rise through the ranks you are looked upon and expected to lead from the front - to present, to protect, to persuade and to be comfortable to challenge in a room full of 2 to 200.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Shit.
&lt;br /&gt;
Why did I struggle so much with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had words to say&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it out of my Comfort zone? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comfort zone is the wrapper that’s found on a burger to keep it warm, it’s that feeling you get when you stay in bed an extra hour, it’s the moment you disagree with something in the room, whilst stood at the back leaning on the wall but say nothing - nodding your head.&lt;br /&gt;
I had to get out of it, I still have to get out of it, it’s not easy but becoming the best version of myself is not meant to be easy.
In short - you can’t get things changed and influenced from the back of the room. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting out of this zone meant breaking rules, my own rules, changing the flow of meetings and more importantly – standing up for my own beliefs and knowledge, never wanting to leave a room wishing I had said something.
It’s a constant work-in-progress, pushing myself and reminding myself that to go further I must do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently attended a “Speak like a leader” course, this is far out of my comfort zone, standing at the front of the room and talking about topics I either knew in advance or was dropped last minute.
It made me anxious, waiting to talk - my heart beating so loud I couldn’t hear anyone else in the room. My talk going through my mind over and over again - worried I’ll mess it or or worse.. be boring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t always like this - I presented to stakeholders all the time, I had a business, I needed to do the peacock dance so often I couldn’t even guess the amount of times I’ve had to stand up and own the room.
Recalling the exact moment I knew I had lost all my confidence - I was running a workshop, it was to last 2 hours. I had it all planned out, I had bullet points, I had a playlist (of course!) - it was set up perfectly.
I also had some stakeholders in, I wanted to and had to land it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t. I really didn’t.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all walked in, I didn’t stand up, I fluffed my words, I didn’t command the room and it felt unplanned and out of control. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I feel so awkward just writing this, knowing how I felt during and after. It’s a constant memory that I try to tuck away, but it’s there - always there ready to sing and dance in my head whenever I’m in a similar situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then on, it went down and down and down hill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was 4 years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it happened, I woke up one day, found an offer of a new job, handed my notice in at work and decided I never want to be stuck in the same rut again. 
I had people telling me I had all the potential in the world, but wasn’t using it, I didn’t deliver.&lt;br /&gt;
All I ever wanted to do was inspire not only work colleagues but my family - my daughter specifically is my inspiration to change, therefore I needed to change, I need to lead by example. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the “speak like a leader” course, the first day was terrible, but something happened, I remembered that I MUST do this - not because anyone told me to do it, I MUST do this to push myself further because if I didn’t, that feeling of failure would creep in again.&lt;br /&gt;
I got on the train home and had a talk, a stern talk to myself.&lt;br /&gt;
I remembered the joy of presenting to clients trying to land that contract, leading a workshop, or the best feeling - getting a standing ovation at my wedding when I did a random(ish) talk and it landed (yes.. the groom did a talk..if you know me it won’t surprise you).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day arrived, I wanted to talk - I wanted to make everyone in the room listen to me, I had no idea what I was going to talk about, but I didn’t care.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Im unsure if you have ever suffered from this, but the feeling of frustration is one I am now using as a drive to power me forward, I want to get better, I want to perform at a level that amazes people and I want to lead, I never want someone to tell me I didn’t fulfil my potential ever again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my tip if you are in this position is to give yourself a chance, stand up and just do it, take yourself to one side and take time to evaluate what you actually want to do - have that talk and remember why or what your drive is.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am making a change, so you can make that change.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I honestly would love to hear how you have changed and what you said to yourself to get to there (or if someone else gave you THAT talk you needed), or even if you are wanting to change but unsure how.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/22/breaking-confidence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/22/breaking-confidence.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.13</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A really heavy week of meetings - planning for the future, and being open and transparent as possible.&lt;br /&gt;
I enjoy these type of weeks, everyone wanting to improve (as I do), and this means only one thing - motivation, which is brilliant.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t believe there is a lot to do - improving communications is key, and I fully believe this would of happened organically, but having these meetings means it’ll happen quicker and be more open and share responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First thing is a pre-planning where we run through what we expect/want in the next sprint.&lt;br /&gt;
Heavily discussed was the previously broken-communication issue amongst one project, the best ways of working and going forward.&lt;br /&gt;
I fully believe no one wants to be in this situation, and with the support of everyone we can learn a lot from this and will. We have a very strong team of people - one im very proud to be amongst, and I don’t doubt for a second that the reasons for doing the work were for the right reasons, we just didn’t let them know the “proper” process of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
9am meeting (without coffee) was a open table meeting with “team two” to discuss the best ways of working. It’s impressive that this was instigated by non-designers and their need for a smooth process and also their trust in trying out something that might be wrong is inspiring.&lt;br /&gt;
Two boards together - one is current “flight” board and on the left side is tickets “in prep” - which can be design, bugs etc - tickets to work on to be ready for “whatever sprint in the future”.&lt;br /&gt;
The output will be a constant “check in”, talking throughout the process to see if everyone is on-board with the design process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems to make sense - will be interesting to work this way, as it feels it could really make design a talking point during stand-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up in the morning where we get straight into testing the design area of the board - seemed to be really nice to talk about design and allowed others to have a say. More of this, please!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A full day of sprint reviews, retros, and planning - for the retro I HAD to mention how I really love how the chair move (designers sitting with good developers and good QAs) and how it will work out (and already showing signs of it being the best decision).
&lt;br /&gt;
Also, today is Show and Tell, since joining DWP, these have improved, but this week was the best one I’ve attended - it was clear with a great direction with good questions and even better answers.
&lt;br /&gt;
Quick note: discussions on prototype future - should we keep doing them etc, a good decision but one that will have to be cleared up eventually (but not a great rush at the moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Another sprint planning session, but this time with the “team two” team - plenty to work on for the future and a concentration on improving things for the user “life improvements”. Really excited to work on these things - as I know from speaking to the users directly they will love the soon-to-be-done fixes.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the afternoon, 1:1 catch up with one of two line manager, always good to catch up and provide updates whilst getting feedback on improving it for the week after.
&lt;br /&gt;
Followed by a leaving-do for a special person who was one of the two User Researchers in the team I worked in. A really funny and good person who helped support me during my early days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning - Sprint retro. Great to run through these again - honest feedback, loads of good conversations on taking the team further and it’s completely open.
Retro’s like this remind me of how important they are, facilitated well and working with a team that is good at communicating and comfortable knowing whatever is said in the room is for the good of the team and more importantly - is a safe room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Having a team as open as the two I’m in, makes me feel really excited for the future. Nothing can’t be said (within reason), and it feels like we are all going in the right direction.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I also want to give a shout out to the PO and DM calling a “ways of working” meeting, we spend 1 hour 30 minutes to discuss how can we work as a design team better (including Devs, BAs, QAs etc) - this happened, went well and I’m VERY excited by this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How great is a place of work when the team wants to be better? Every sprint we strive to be better than the last - it not only makes us better as a team but it drags me along and makes me chomp at the bit to be better.&lt;br /&gt;THIS is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding time to work. Every two weeks the week includes a day that is pure meetings - sometimes its busy and other times its a great reminder of the work we’ve done. I must remember that it’s actually a good thing to enjoy the end-of-sprint moment, showing off our work, celebrating all work done and getting together in a room to, as mentioned before improve and cheer each other on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had to think about my past experience to discuss how I wish our design-process to be, and I didn’t use any of it - instead of making the team work together and discuss how they want to work with the design team then working back.
I love getting the answer by including everyone in it - I’m not at my best working silo, so getting everyone involved is good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/weeknotes-no13.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/weeknotes-no13.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.12</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A week of self-learning, awkwardness and totally taking over my fears.
It’s been a week of really asking myself what do I want to do, and why aren’t I doing it. The answer as it is for everyone else is fear - so I took one step towards realising fear was taking over and kicked it away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today, work-wise was wild.
A range of emotions spread out all through today - from pure dread to pure disappointment. Something I use to love doing, that I now dread - I did a “public speaking” course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day was honestly one of the worst days - I was so nervous, to the level my heart was beating out of my ears. I’ve never had nerves like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to talk for a minute and I was mumbling, standing still and awkward. So awkward.
Before, I use to love speaking in public (I do - just not work related), but then I got feedback that knocked me completely and the thought of standing up in front of people it was terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So.. thats Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Roll on the second day of training.
After yesterday, I honestly thought on my way home of 105 excuses to not go, I’m i’ll, I need to paint the door, my garden needs doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEN, when I arrived at home, I had a word with myself, I needed too.
I know this course is a positive, I knew it was going to make me a better designer, I cant harp on and on about being a designer now is more about relationships and comms then ever before and not “do-what-I-preach”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned fear into excitement. I wanted ppl staring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went first, spoke for approx 3 mins (actually the course tutor lost track of time) and made people stand up to start with, I walked around the room, paused, gestured and got the crowd to shout a swear word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took control, I could of spoken for much longer and I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excitement instead of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Returning to Leeds, after Monday and Tuesday offsite-training, straight into 4 meetings and a lot of “can I just ask you a quick question?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One meeting stuck out - discussing the project from last week that went a bit awry. The B.A. I’m working with is really top notch, and she realises it was not done correctly and has let design take lead on changing the work (step by step), and i’m incredibly grateful for this, and will also highten the teams confidence, happiness and ability to share ways-of-workings easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My first Interaction Meet -up, hosted in Leeds (which is handy).
I love gatherings like this, plenty of group learnings shared and exciting opportunities mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I took away:
Be more active on Slack,
Option to attend a Service Design course,
Improving design and its understanding - in the wider business,
It’s ok to be wrong, and it’s ok for your team to be wrong (yes - more of this!),
My line-manager has my back, not that I needed reminding of this, but he really has and that has powered me through the tougher times,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above, AND we had Vic Bell in for the guest speaker.
I’ve followed Vic’s work for years, weirdly I knew her work before I knew her. We’ve chatted plenty on twitter for the past 3 years (we both had a nipper around the same time). Check her work out - it’s incredible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her talk was amazing, it really touched a nerve. 
Having someone who suffers from depression in the family means its a very sensitive subject and her openness, honestly and down-to-earth reminded me of the positive sides of the illness, as well as coping mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Vic, it was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of catch-ups (again), and a meeting with the BA to discuss future tickets on Jira for next sprint and how best to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to discuss better ways of working together - but it’s certainly a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really rate the BA and PO on the team - they have the user, team, and ways of working always in mind and the direction they are going in is one im 100% on-board to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Speak like a leader course on Monday and Tuesday was eye-opening.
I have often wanted to speak in a public place, and really feel comfortable doing it, and now I feel ready. Now I feel worthy of filling a stage.
It is not just for the “expected” public speaking, I need to up my presentation skills and leadership in meetings, and this course spoon-fed me what I needed and a very timely reminder of the skills needed.
We all have the skills - I just needed to be reminded!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes, people do things for the best reasons but they do not match your expectations.
In the past - I use to be so firey it would lead to broken relationships and emotions running a little wild in meetings.
As I’m in a new work-place, I decided to improve my communication skills and more importantly, UNDERSTAND other people’s expectations and reasons why - this is massive in my own happiness (and theirs), and has led to some really interesting conversations and different outcomes.
Things might not be perfect - but everyone is trying their best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That pesky comfort zone caused me havoc at the start of the week, it really did.
But, having the ability to “hold myself accountable” is an amazing turn - I had that chat to myself, I had the realisation that this course is not going to harm me, but improve me.
If possible, get out of the comfort zone as much as you can - it’s a great / terrible / enlightening / frustrating learning curve - but the secret is.. you never fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Turning the corner and feeling comfortable again in speaking in front of people. Having tools to turn a point, into a detailed conversation with structure and without heavy lifting.
I can’t thank the team in assisting in this enough - as I grow in my role, it’s becoming more and more obvious being a good designer is not about how well you design, it’s how well you understand the problem and talk to others about the problem AND presenting the solution in a manner which is understandable by all and not exclusive to designers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 20:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/weeknotes-no11.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/weeknotes-no11.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.12</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 11 of my time at DWP, this time has passed so quickly.
The learning curve has been exactly what I’ve wanted, it’s been tough at times - times I felt so out of my comfort zone, sometimes its been frustrating, but other times its been amazing.&lt;br /&gt;
The amazing times outweigh the frustrating times easily, we launched services, have 100% team support and more importantly I’m constantly learning in a very fun environment - and the people are incredible, proper people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways.. on to the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up as normal in morning, decided to work on the prototype but really simplify it to get it done quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afternoon - meeting on future design needs for product and sprint planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admin: emails are fun to work through aren’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ceremonies day for one of my teams - this involves sprint review and retro, the mighty show and tell and then finally (next) sprint planning.&lt;br /&gt;
The other team - the project owner and I discussed sprint tickets and getting blinking access to Jira (a real pain).
&lt;br /&gt;
Worth noting, today was an interesting one, a huge miscommunication for one project led to work being done that wasn’t made public, leading to a shocked room of designers. &lt;br /&gt;
This is frustrating, but it’s also worth seeing as a learning experience - maybe we weren’t as open as we should of been with all the teams - many things to be taken away and to be chewed over from this:&lt;br /&gt;
I need to communicate more about what I’m working on,&lt;br /&gt;
Share UR feedback more often,&lt;br /&gt;
Get access to Jira as a matter of life or death.&lt;br /&gt;
Personally speaking - this experience jolted me and reminded me that all the hard work is still to come, we need to educate the power and cost of good and bad design, and also why we are here. The only way to do this, is to speak out correctly, and allow others to learn as they go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sprint planning in the morning, a lot of design tickets in for this sprint (and next) ranging from “life improvements” to feature-led. Working with this product owner is totally refreshing, as his experience working with designers is low, so he’s more than happy to “just go along with it”, and learn ways-of-working as we work more and more together.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following on from yesterday’s learnings, the design team sat down and discussed taking the new build to the users for testing, what to test, how to test, shall we change anything before testing - many more but all leading to “what will we learn”.
&lt;br /&gt;
Jira update: still awaiting access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first message on Slack this morning = access to Jira boards activated!&lt;br /&gt;
Wfh today - meeting on slack, confirming how to work on the previously mentioned project going forward, I listed all the potential changes initially found to the group and we all agreed on these (found from testing) and uploaded on to Jira!&lt;br /&gt;
My mission, and learning is to work in the open more on this one, let everyone know every step and avoid any “design and dump” approach. Basically, be loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Realising I haven’t been working-in-the-open enough has been eye-opening, and a good lesson to learn. Thinking a small circle knows what i’m working on is not enough - so spreading the net wider will be great for the team and again, take me out of any comfort zone i’ve settled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Having a new routine of writing notes everyday has helped massively in backing up any design decisions - I can easily look back in my book and read out some user-feedback (in this case) upon request, also a side-effect has been a better memory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Getting set up on systems within DWP is a complex process, I’ve been waiting for Jira access since day 1, and this is the week i’ve finally got it - it can be a little disheartening if your work isn’t being tracked like others but one I expected (it never goes smoothly!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This week, we planned ahead - far ahead. I now know what the goals of my work is, I know what i’m working on for the next 3 months which helps with work-anxiety. I never have liked “asking for work”, and I’m unsure I even know how to (without finding work myself).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/weeknotes-no12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/04/weeknotes-no12.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tuesday I got frustrated, Wednesday I learned loads and Friday I drove 350 miles.
Not an average week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning routine starts with a Design stand up with the wider team, aims of the week are:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rebuild prototype (including scenarios to assist with testing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;plan a hypothesis board and possible whiteboard for tickets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sit down with the content designer to discuss some much requested design work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the day we have a workshop, running through the ideas for the next period of the year (P8) - coming up with ideas that we want to all concentrate on (pushing towards the idea that helps all teams and squads have the shared aim of all being UCD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today was a no-meetings-and-pure-get-down-to-it work day! Getting my head around the prototype tool (building from scratch) was great, frustrating and incredibly rewarding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been many many years since I used it - but not its like I never went away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it works - its a brilliant little tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Had a round-table with a subject specialist - brilliant gathering and took so so many learnings from her, she started the journey that my team is on all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An afternoon spent discussing future UR plans and conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
UR again in Harrogate, nice to get away from the office and listen again to the users as much as possible.
Also bonus of being out of the office is having time to arrange (more) meetings for next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH in the morning and worked on tallying up questions for a meeting with the PM to influence the roadmap session planned (to fill the gaps if design isnt included).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wednesday, speaking to a past designer of the service was amazing, and reminded me that it can be so easy to find someone who has been there before, and learn learn learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Realising that so many differing projects have the same patterns of “issues”, is enlightening and also motivating - the chance of teaming up with other designers is exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I need to start planning better for stand-ups, unsure if this means starting earlier (finishing earlier), or speaking less time checking on the team in a morning - or just being more dedicated to scribbling something down and planning better (if I am honest.. I know the answer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not work related - but I worked Flexi-time on Friday afternoon, and had the best weekend away in Cumbria with my wife and 3 year old. I loved this and reminds me over and over again to take more breaks and use Flexi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/27/weeknotes-no10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/08/27/weeknotes-no10.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be a troublemaker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I can remember, I’ve always had an opinion, the unwritten benefit of having cockney parents means I’m very ok to communicate my disapproval or if I disagree with everything.&lt;br /&gt;
I class this as a skill, a gift - the ability to have the confidence and comfort of speaking my thoughts and challenging on what I believe to be wrong or right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honestly, this confidence has not always been there, this happened and evolved over time - learning when to speak, when to listen and when to support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to this point meant breaking it all down into simple chunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to listen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a skill I always teach, it’s this one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Just stop talking.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at Sky Bet, it was important that I listened as much as possible to people who were not designers, letting them have the power of the room, empowering them to have opinions on something they don’t have much knowledge on and allowing the sense of comfort in the room.&lt;br /&gt;
This (right) approach means fantastic decisions can be made by the non-designers who are just-as creative - which is where I always want the teams I work in to be, and do everything in my skillset to get them there.
Getting this trust is not an easy task, you need to be a different type of designer, one that is not precious about design, one that is approachable and more importantly one that educates. &lt;br /&gt;Personally opinion alert: this skillset splits up the good designers to the brilliant designers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Here at DWP, it’s no different - the need to hear the SME’s, or PM’s, BA’s, PTO’s (I made that last one up) is so important to learn what the actual problem is and to put distance between the problem and the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did I/we get the team to this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have found so many techniques; giving each person a sharpie and a handful of post its is a big step for many designers, at first only a handful will speak and the rest will resort to writing it down - but eventually, a domino effect will happen and before you know it everyone is speaking, challenging and finding solutions that a single designer would never have thought of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some rules to this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I have never &quot;picked on&quot; the quietest person in the room - this is not a fair approach and its unfair to assume they have anything to add to the meeting (or want to).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I have never told anyone to stop talking - unless they have spoken over others or are going off the script.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I have never started a workshop or meeting without putting down &lt;em&gt;room-rules&lt;/em&gt;, things like take turns to talk or (depending on numbers) hands up, write everything down, don't be a dick (work this one correctly to the tone of the room!), you have to stress its a safe-place - once you have simple rules in place - everything should and will flow better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 08:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/25/be-a-troublemaker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/08/25/be-a-troublemaker.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
