<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 16:06:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.33</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally missed a couple of days’ updates, so let’s start fresh &lt;em&gt;insert smack head emoji here&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
This contract feels so different to the previous months, I don’t feel dread when 9 am or sometimes 8 am comes around, I feel a surge of excitement and challenge (in a good way) and am energised by the team. The challenges so far are usual run-of-the-mill expected things and I would describe the team as being in control of the problem space AND the solution space.  &lt;br /&gt;
As a bonus, I’m sleeping better, nicer, having time to think and enjoying life instead of letting work ruin/run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sun is shining, coffee is flowing (if you need recommendations, look no further than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taylorsofharrogate.co.uk/house-blends/lazy-sunday&quot; title=&quot;a link to taylors sunday blend coffee&quot;&gt;Taylor’s Sunday blend &lt;/a&gt;)
Today, we met as a design and talked ONLY design tickets and the forthcoming work - this is so refreshing and it’s a welcome discussion when developers, BAs, and QAs discuss user needs and the design team just let it flow. I mentioned challenges in the header of this post, this 100% isn’t a challenge, it’s a breath of fresh air and I’m all for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working closely with the excellent design team (content designer and a User researcher) on part of the journey around verifying your ID (using phone, email or HMRC app) and updating the prototype. Busy morning, lots to take in and plenty of understanding and “ahh” moments coming from me, grateful I’m sat on my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote a handful of LinkedIn recommendations for those nearest and dearest, suddenly a well-worth task that, in a time when people are job searching gives them a boost and knows that others out there are helping out (if you have any outstanding, please write one - including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelcattell/&quot; title=&quot;link to my Linkedin profile&quot;&gt;one for me!&lt;/a&gt;).
Also during my lunch hour, had another run at using ChatGPT, it’s such a powerful “thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The set-up on this team is next level, this morning was refinement - where.. if I ever doubted that they trusted the interaction designer, today was the day it was wiped out - they asked me all the right questions, hung on my words of experience and listened and agreed to my points of view - LOVE IT!&lt;br /&gt;
We also have a lot of DAC items in our backlog, that, due to my experience on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/designsystem-2022.html&quot; title=&quot;linking to my DWP design system case study&quot;&gt;design system team&lt;/a&gt; I can easily work on (I know the backlog of the Gov design system like the back of my hand), I also know from previous experience that sometimes the DAC reports are always 100% correct - mostly around comments to the design system (one example would be making all labels for input boxes as bold and bigger, which varies between each service).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Managed to work a ton of tickets yesterday, all centered around my bread and butter - accessibility.&lt;br /&gt;
Feels like an interesting clash between what the design system is, and how the design system is being used and understood by its users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is purely 100% reading the DAC report and working on those issues, as mentioned before - some of the reviews are quite interesting, they lean towards more what the design system says to do, in a “look and feel” manner than what’s happening on screen. Interestingly - it’s not correct either, I’ve had many DAC reports and they’ve always differed almost exclusively on one pattern, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.service.gov.uk/components/details/&quot; title=&quot;click here to see the GDS details pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;details pattern&lt;/a&gt; not being able to be read correctly by Dragon (but.. many times it’s been found to be a false report).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I really enjoyed the podcast with Ross Clark / Rylan on the fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/6J4vrilAtR8wEzj9j4PFTu?si=a240f3513e0348df&quot; title=&quot;a spotify link to the High Performance Podcast&quot;&gt;High Performance podcast&lt;/a&gt;. It was really insightful into his life, but also interesting to see little snippets of coping mechanisms. &lt;br /&gt;
“Don’t sweat the small stuff” really landed with me, it’s an old saying that has been used time after time, but I needed to hear this and actually HEAR this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/06/weeknotes-no33.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/06/weeknotes-no33.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.32</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here it is, the long-awaited return of weeknotes (said no one), I cannot believe it has been nearly 2 years since I wrote anything. &lt;br /&gt;
Things have changed a heck of a lot since my last post, I joined Hippo Digital on the 12th January 2022, and left on the 12th January 2023. It was an adventure that I will write about, but first, I have a new journey to go on and look forward to
&lt;strong&gt;life as a contractor (the sequel)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the old and tested fashion, I’ll keep the format the same as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is my first day at HMRC as an Interaction Designer and it was all I wanted it to be, it was easy, nice, warm and structured. A huge hat tip to Sam Manzi for just being amazingly welcoming and just being in control of a situation that is never easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of contracting isn’t a shock or surprise to me anymore, after a year of leading and landing teams into contracting or consulting positions and seeing their anxiety rise due to piss-poor onboarding or more-than-likely lack of preparation from the resource team, I have a couple of quick wins under my belt (which I should write about one day), but not beating myself up and thinking others are expecting me to hit the ground running and know what I’m working on just isn’t real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is a full meet and greet with the team and the wonderful Jean, she reached out almost instantly when I joined and that is a great sign of it being a good place to work.&lt;br /&gt;
The community seems to be a huge thing here, which is exciting as I’ve missed the “help each other out” during design crits and attending one already felt natural, even giving me space to talk about my experience with a problem I had faced previously.
Great day for onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Reading, reading, reading, confluence, confluence and a bit more confluence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today started as a cracking day - woke up, fed the kids and it was my turn to take them to school.. only today was different - I thought it was Wednesday. No big deal - most school days are the same, except Robyn has a booster class at 8:30 am, whilst I’m strolling in at 8:45 am telling Robyn it’s 100% Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;
Being corrected by a 7-year-old is a fresh kick that coffee never provides, and then pushing a pram at the speed of light to get her in the lesson is a vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Forgot to write this one - doh! What a wonderful start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Usually I would place podcasts, blogs and people to link to, but as i’ve just re-started it - feel free to send some over for me to read or listen or do introductions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/25/weeknotes-no32.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/25/weeknotes-no32.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.31</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(for the week of 31st August)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mannnnn a weird weekend, turns out my perfect little dog has diabetes which is tough to handle and was incredibly tough to hear - but then real life kicks in and we just have to accept it and manage it. Tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussed the final amends to the design system re-vamp, really light stuff like content etc, and today I will be sending it out for testing and feedback. Looking forward to this so we can see exactly what’s what - I’ve kept a ton in the loop but we finally have a prototype of sorts to show off that isn’t sketches or conversations.&lt;br /&gt;
A day of admin (again) and doing the small stuff that I’ve not looked at for a while, painful but needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Online training day, decided to help out DWP with the hiring process properly by taking the sifting course (this is where we read cv’s etc) and being on the panel in interviews, that’ll help me get more insight into the process properly and also if needed, help me hone my interview skills for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteered to speak at the Content Community day, having a 15-20minute slot to discuss all things design patterns and content patterns, I’ll be covering off my favourite - contribution but also going for investment from the community into future patterns and seeing if there are blockers to providing feedback (every presentation needs a workshop right?), excited for this one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Today’s work is lead by the presentation to the community, which goes side by side with my work in leading the change of contribution model - we have outlined a skeleton shape to the presentation and now the fun bit, working out the words stuff…&lt;br /&gt;
Collating feedback on the design system from approx 20 people ranging from differing roles within DWP, really excited to see the feedback and amend, we are using and trialling Github discussions still, as there were hints people were nervous about using GitHub issues - but so far people seem to be fluent and fast in using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took some time out today to take the kids swimming midday, was so much fun to break the day up with this and a nice and welcome break from a hectic work week. And also, who doesn’t love dunking their kid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Arranging a gathering of work colleagues finally, this feels good to be seeing people I work with and having a quiet (..yeah right) drink sometime next week, it’s been so long since I’ve been in a public place with a group of people so fingers crossed my social skills are as terrible as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washy week this one, prob my most boring set of week notes tbh, but it’s all the admin/must do work at the moment (I’m sure you don’t want to know all the digging I’m doing in confluence!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mega-mentor.com/&quot;&gt;https://mega-mentor.com/&lt;/a&gt;  - This website doesn’t need an introduction, if you are looking above your level and want a design lead to help motivate, advise and help you on the next step, this is the place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/08/weeknotes-no31.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/09/08/weeknotes-no31.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.30</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(for the week of 23rd August)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A new fresh week at work after a nice weekend of playing with the kids, having a lovely dinner out with my wife and brill nippers and terrible weather!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t, I would recommend you read this &lt;a href=&quot;https://stamanfar.medium.com/just-say-it-3c43a83c1ea9&quot;&gt;brilliant blog post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stamanfar?lang=en&quot;&gt;@stamanfar&lt;/a&gt;, written with such honesty that many of us face sometime in our career - in her words: A blog about flunking, maybe, and new beginnings. This post alone has made me turn up AGAIN and do week notes, it was really impactful and I’m so glad it was written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On other news, I also returned from holiday - a week on a farm is this family best holiday and since lockdown has been here and gone, we’ve holidayed around England a lot and… wow this country has got some beautiful gems that I might have missed in the past but making up for it now!&lt;br /&gt;
A timely break for us all, work has been hectic - both home life (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt;) and work work, but it’s nice to turn the MacBook off, recharge, re-assess thoughts and energize again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve been busy updating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.dwp.gov.uk/index&quot;&gt;DWP’s first design system website&lt;/a&gt; over the last week (at the time of writing this is not updated), really feeding off user needs that we collected (first hand) from our users, things around updating them on what we are working on, what’s in the backlog and also providing a clearer understanding of what we are doing and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also be working alongside this launch presenting back to the different communities within DWP to provoke a discussion around contribution to the design system, allowing much more freedom and “chat” around patterns and, I guess - getting them to do the work alongside us (the way it should be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was around fixing issues and bugs that I’ve noticed within the design system site, easy lists (light work to get back into the swing of things).
Then straight onto working on our backlog item (today was &lt;strong&gt;toggle welsh&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;keybar details&lt;/strong&gt;), gathering as much data as possible and speaking to those who have given us information using GitHub discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard work when making patterns is certainly the start - knowing where to start feels different for each pattern depending on what arrives, how it arrives and what the users want first. As we are short in numbers of staff members, it means having to lean into User Research areas and not letting personal opinion kick in (I’ve used the patterns I’m gathering before so forgetting bias is always a tricky thing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have huge questions around how we agree on a pattern and launching it - whilst I certainly don’t want to wait around pleasing everyone, I certainly don’t want to launch something just because I think it is ready - I think its key to have a group of people to ask “Is this what you want/good enough” and if not - tell me why with data.
The afternoon meeting was to support a community-led pattern exploration piece, I’m super excited to see this in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This morning I am trying to be a lot more productive and focused, as the last couple of days / and week has been a rush of getting the work done as quick as possible (due to our deadlines), whilst I’ve enjoyed it a lot, I need to get my focus back now the rush is over. The easiest way to do this is to target THREE things I want to do today, I usually do TWO workpieces and ONE for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping to arrange the workshop the community are running by giving some tips on making it as effective as possible, but remember I shall be taking a back seat here, and letting them work their magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I was invited to speak to the Content Community, centring around gaining a level understanding of the value, purpose and shared vision of the design system, so discussed my presentation with the organiser, and anyone who knows when I do a presentation - I always want to get something from it - selfishly for the project I am on - an interactive presentation, so I’m squeezing in a mini-workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today’s hectic, poor Ralph isn’t too well so taking part of my lunch hour to visit the vets and doing dad duties in the morning with my other boy, he’s 5 months old now and has found out how to wave!&lt;br /&gt;
Also, today is the planned community workshop (which I have to miss due to Ralph) but I know it’s in safe hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ran through content and design ideas with Helen (content designer on the design system) to nail down what we could do even more to improve the process of providing feedback to a pattern/component and also discuss bloody terminal commands!&lt;br /&gt;
I’m pleased and proud of the team as to what we will deliver, it will answer a lot of the questions to user needs and also provide a level of transparency that wasn’t there before, and set us up for a strong future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Work work workkkkkk, loads on with finishing the build and fixing mishaps that we find (of course it’s perfect first time…).&lt;br /&gt;
Tying up a lot of ends that will align parts of entry for the design system is consistent and very much up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ran through the feedback from the workshop yesterday, due to missing it, it was nice to see something happening that was led by want and need and not by must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing really to update but doing admin work, and loads of it 🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How did it get to Friday this fast? Is this the day we launch the new design system? Fingers crossed we are near… but it is at that point of, there could be a bug or content error anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/leading-service-design/asking-the-right-questions-to-frame-the-problem-4df95a317983&quot;&gt;https://designdetails.fm/episodes/292309&lt;/a&gt; - Revisiting Ben’s brilliant post about “asking the right questions to frame the problem”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UkvOlE8qDB0&amp;amp;list=PLMC49V9zeXbGQwEM-my5XLiTWzy4-vf7j&amp;amp;index=67&amp;amp;t=1663s&quot;&gt;Slopes Game Room - KickScammers: The VEGA+ Scandal&lt;/a&gt; - I am massively into retro-gaming, and this documentary about the Spectrum Vega+ has me gripped from start to finish, usual brilliance from Slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/02/weeknotes-no30.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/09/02/weeknotes-no30.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.29</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s back… my long-awaited week notes return.&lt;br /&gt;
Now felt a good time than any to write again, hopefully kickstart my writing again as it’s taken a huge slip recently, whilst I have plenty to say I also have little motivation to write it but since working on the Design System at DWP I’ve become incredibly heavy with design thoughts and wanting to write (missing out on the time due to other duties (see the 2 kids, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble website&quot;&gt;wife’s business&lt;/a&gt; and a constant battle against the weeds in the garden)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This morning we had our usual stand up, but I decided that I needed to discuss my distaste for getting served crepes when I was originally offered pancakes (this was heavily linked to me cooking breakfast pancakes for my daughter).&lt;br /&gt;
But back to work - today is the day we have agreed on the design of the “new” design system for DWP, something more streamlined and catered to provide more of an easier service to the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am starting the journey of getting more interaction between the design system and the design community - we all want the same thing and I have a great relationship with the team so I don’t see many challenges, the joys of having a prior relationships with the wider team eh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Evaluating the outcomes from the brilliant Design System’s day that GDS ran last week. Whilst, I feel we were on top of quite a lot (thanks to the team’s prior knowledge and know-how before I joined) I still took away quite a lot, especially around community things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking into running sessions that will unite, bridge and help us get talking freely - less about work and more about THE work, specific work that helps us all.&lt;br /&gt;
There is always a need around showcasing the work we do, the design doesn’t automatically come with a value output, and always promoting and showing the point of the work we and I are doing is key and showing it’s totally worthless without working for them, my users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the community vibe in mind, I decided to trial the following:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Office hours&lt;/strong&gt; - where we share an hour of the week/month and explain what we did (i guess its similar to design community show and tell)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Power hour&lt;/strong&gt; - where we open a slack channel for drop-in calls, and discuss their patterns and talk openly (a show and tell for them, lead by them)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Brown bag&lt;/strong&gt; - we get folks who do not want high-level talk but a deep dive (optional attendance) into a pattern - bring your lunch!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A survey&lt;/strong&gt; - find out how to find how the design system is working for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll be an interesting test to see which sinks or which come through as a shining light - plenty of work to do in this area but, all projects have challenges and all projects need the work, I’m just glad it’s this kind of work where I can control and have a lot of input in the outcomes (whilst trying new things and learning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This morning, we ran through the design and future planning of the design system site. The dev-lead has really smashed through the design we agreed on (it’s a light build and MVP) and is running at parity with the design team (there is 2 of us!) and it’s good to work at pace and just get-stuff-done for launch and testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also implemented a mural board (a whiteboarding tool) where we track designs, versions, conversations against versions and feedback (post-it note heavy stuff) - somewhere to document decisions, reasons and all that stuff that we often don’t do as designers that slips through the cracks.. or worse ends up on a jira ticket!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a mural board of truth - within my first week I ran a workshop to discuss who are the users, what are their needs, how we measure success (this also includes KPI’s which is often missed within public sector), then I will often revisit this board to check we have hit the needs, and challenge the team to align to the needs and see if we are still doing the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 11 am meeting to run through a much needed contribute model - even if only to make it clearer for senior stakeholders. It’s been said many times, and I will keep repeating this - design systems live and die with the contribution, we need to find out what’s working or dying on its feet within the current process - we use GitHub issues at current but more recently we’ve moved to use GitHub discussions with a small testing group and it has been brilliant. &lt;br /&gt;
To initially kick off a pattern, we don’t need much - its more of an eye, an awareness of the work, this means screengrabs, a paragraph on why you went for it, how and did it test/work well and what team you are on (we ask team/service so if needed we reach out for more info to get a wider understanding not just interaction design but content, UR, PM, business needs - you name it we want it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound simple eh? Anyone who worked on a design system knows it isn’t - I need to get the community to feel it’s part of their role, their need, and to find time to provide us with the goods - I also need to remember this is key in solving any contributing issues, many Systems in the past fall into the styleguide where it becomes one person leading the charge and making decisions - I see myself as the person who puts the jigsaw together, not the jigsaw maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working on learning “stuff” today, reading blog post after blog post to see what others did - but there is still a whiff of design systems still not being crystal clear in the how-we-do-the-do or getting it into a team sport.
I’d love any help on this - so get in touch if you can talk through what you did (good or bad!).
Ran through the current version of the design-to-developed site and ripped it apart in Mural as a team, all agreed changes were not to big but incredibly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com&quot; title=&quot;visit bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt; update, today we (re)launched our brilliant new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/collections/ikea-klammig-pyttig-antilop-high-chair-wipeable-cushion-covers&quot; title=&quot;bobbin and bumble&apos;s new line and designs of ikea highchair covers&quot;&gt;Ikea highchair cushion covers&lt;/a&gt; - these items were our original sellers and have been so popular and I couldn’t be as proud of Emma as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful links this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://designdetails.fm/episodes/292309&quot; title=&quot;click here to listen to a podcast on designdetails.fm&quot;&gt;https://designdetails.fm/episodes/292309&lt;/a&gt; - Linzi Berry, a manager on Lyft’s design system talking about the design system, the struggles and I found some gems in here.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/collections/ikea-klammig-pyttig-antilop-high-chair-wipeable-cushion-covers&quot; title=&quot;view bobbin and bumble&apos;s new launch of ikea highchair covers&quot;&gt;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/collections/ikea-klammig-pyttig-antilop-high-chair-wipeable-cushion-covers&lt;/a&gt; - Our chair covers are made for the IKEA highchair, these help your baby during those fun moments of mess-free-weaning (I know far more about baby products now than I could ever dream of).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 11:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/02/weeknotes-no29.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/08/02/weeknotes-no29.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life update 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a while since I wrote on my website - life has certainly been busy in the past 3-6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot has changed and I guess that’s the point of this post - to act as a reminder to myself in a year of where I was and hopefully where I am going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big one:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a haircut - thank the fine lords I got a haircut.&lt;br /&gt;
JUST JOKING!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;My family got bigger&lt;/strong&gt;, it grew by one and it grew with a little boy called Jasper. He is all I wanted without knowing what I wanted, we, again decided to not find out the gender and it was put upon me to deliver the news to my wife during the birth… whilst compared to her role it’s barely anything, but this time I wanted to tell her (last time with my daughter Robyn I couldn’t speak), during all of the pregnancy we, for some unknown reason decided we were having a girl, so it was a little bit of a shock. Having this assumption caused issues - such as not concentrating on names for boys, or getting clothes for boys (leaning more the “neutral girls” if that’s possible) so when I said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Emma…. you won’t believe this… IT’S A BOY”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when it all changed. 
Whilst Robyn looks just like her mother, poor Jasper looks like his dad - blue eyes for bonus points but THAT look on his face still makes me laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s the big reveal, that’s the life-changing moment to add to the current list of big life moves (all happening in the backdrop of a bloody pandemic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve never really openly said - but my past year or so I’ve been heavily involved in supporting the Government’s program of welfare reform, where my role was to drive forward a key part of one of the biggest and highest-profile digital transformation programs in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the current climate, this role has changed a lot, I was in a lot of teams, almost exclusively consulting on design, presenting to very high-up stakeholders and upskilling at speed. I designed, I persuaded and I levelled up my communication skills as well as leading design and its value through a wider reach. 
It was enjoyable, testing and satisfying but an opportunity came to move to another team and a team I’ve often been earmarked for so many times - I can’t tell you the names but very often people have told me point-blank&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are IDEAL for this role as it needs working on and it’s screaming out for you”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new role needs leadership and a voice from an Interaction designer point of view and this feels like a challenge that I could not turn down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I decided to join the Design System for DWP.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took on their advice, I listened to them and myself, the need to help other designers grow and we, as a Government department deliver something as best we can, within time, within budget and, from my own first-hand experience, see improvements in accessibility, performance, and shared knowledge across the team.
I want to provide and show there is value in these tools, these processes and I want designers to feel in control of THE design process but still with the ability to make situational decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will not be easy, we have a lot of work and hurdles ahead, it might not even be sexy - but it’s the right side of challenge and the rewards will be massive for us, as a department but also for my self-worth, a legency piece (if you will) - just having an impact is the driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new role also allows more time to mentor designers within the organisation, which is what gets me out of bed on a morning - this is massive to me and I hope I can show value in doing this and hopefully inspire others to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a heck of a month or two, I haven’t even touched on my wife and her brilliance, whilst having a baby and being a brilliant mother to two kids, Emma is also doing better than we could ever imagine with the family business down at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;see more products at bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt; - but that’s another post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also decided to start posting more on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/mikeycattell&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt; account, as I’m starting to design more emailers, leaflets, websites etc all around my wife’s growing business, I have a vast amount of design work that feels like it might end up lost - so keep an eye out for that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/07/life-update-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/05/07/life-update-2021.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cheering the designer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past year was the year I started teaching, it was the year I learned more about myself than ever before and it was a time I learned more about others and their situations, their cultures, and their problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spoken to people from Dubai, to San Francisco to Leeds and more and the lessons I’ve learned have been one of the best in my career and personally.
But this post isn’t about me, that’s for another time - what I wanted to share was my process of teaching and how I learned to talk to a room of designers and make everyone feel like they were the only one, or how I empowered them to feel at ease at feeling silly, asking that question without the preface “this is probably a silly question..” and feel confident in presenting work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I cheered for the designer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started back in 2010, working in America - I was the lead designer of a company, and enjoying it - I had more work than I could handle, the work I was doing was interesting and helped companies and people provide a service. BUT I needed help, I was working on 3 companies all within a parent company - whilst they weren’t 100%, they needed some love and care.
This is where it all changed for me, my line manager came up with the idea of hiring 1-2 students to work alongside me, as well as promote internally a person to work as a junior designer, this would serve two purposes - one to help work “get done”, and secondary - it would grow my skill set managing and the students.
And it did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I learned more than I could write in one blog post within those three years, I worked hard on giving these new designers confidence, we would work together on understanding briefs, working out how to get more out of the stakeholders to allow us to replay the vision and problem back - we worked harder on presenting back our findings and early completed work to gain more of an insight into if we were going in the right direction (user research, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The one huge thing I did learn and have remembered from my own harsh experience is to never expose a designer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never call a designer (or anyone for that matter) out in front of the team, never ridicule, if the design or the presentation isn’t a smooth one, or a good one, as a design lead I must use this as a learning tool to help grow that missing skillset.
Exposing a designer in front of a crowd can lead to many things - loss of confidence, embarrassment, loss of the support of a colleague/team member, and with that a potential issue with the team environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have been exposed many times by self-titled design leaders, passing comments such as “No, don’t do that yet - you need to ask me first”, or “No, this isn’t any good, that’s not what we do here” or a personal favourite “What Mikey is trying to say but for some reason isn’t…” - I wish I had never experienced these moments, and I wish it never happened in public in front of my team, but to take these negatives and turn them into a positive is the only thing I can do and I will not allow anyone on my team to feel the way I did during those moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you stop exposing a designer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let’s pick a scenario, you are a design team manager, and one of your team is about to present their work back to the company - this, if it goes right makes your team look brilliant, makes the person look brilliant but also allows the design process to show its value.
The presentation goes bad, the person loses their way, rushes through and doesn’t mention anything about the process, and shows work off in a bad light - what do you do?
Calling them out would ruin their confidence to ever-present work again (which is in the top 3 skills I look for in a good designer), it would also cheapen the trust in the team - is there the possibility that you could ask questions that help open the conversation to allow the designer to “fill the gaps”, something along the lines of
“can you share more about the design process at the start of the project as I know you did some really good work with the team?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach will completely change your team’s ways of working, it will bring a different way of critiquing the teams and completely build trust amongst the wider business, it also allows you to take the designer aside (1:1’s) and help grow their skills privately, whether as a manager or (even better) as a leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we empower other designers, the more they can pass it on and make our jobs a lot easier by making other designers around us better and feel more confident and safe to “just” design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/02/cheering-on-the-designer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/01/02/cheering-on-the-designer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.28</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a great one - Robyn turned five, FIVE - how this happened is so crazy, it’s been an interesting journey being a father.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve learned so much from her, and my wife - learning to be patient, learning to coach my daughter to make her own way in life, giving her confidence, an opinion, and control… I’ve enjoyed it so much I’ve got a second one on the way! Keep an eye out for how tired I look in March…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This morning I was welcomed by 16 emails from over the weekend, all with deadlines - not the best way to start your Monday morning but it’s becoming a habit. I’ve learned to start working out what is actually urgent and more of panic by the person writing it, of which I then discuss this with them and it becomes a lot easier and clearer and calmer to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home update: the house has become good, really good - we have done a complete empty of every room (and trust me… when you have a 5-year-old running around who is a toy tester (don’t ask), a self-employed business (bobbin and bumble) and working from home full time it suddenly starts to add up.
BUT, we’ve done things over the past month to really make it homely again, and also ready for a baby in advance! Who’d of thought you can sort yourself out 3 months early and feel pretty ready for the baby?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning stand up, so glad I write notes from the day before to discuss as mornings as sometimes a rush due to doing the school run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, we discussed a change in our working process, co-working with another team - I always find discussions around things like this interesting and incredibly valuable learning tools, hearing opinions from developers, BA’s to PM’s. It’s an interesting time for our team, and having this external help from another team is invaluable to deliver something even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon meeting was brilliant - regrouping with Leeds based Interaction designers for a catch-up, really good chance to moan, cheer, and share work which I love doing!
A lot of us thrive on the communities we have, but also some slip through the gaps so it’s a timely reminder that often some designers do not have designers in their area of work due to (especially at current) the way it’s all set up. Time to support our colleagues and fix this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
School day (every day but Monday), I still wonder why the school sometimes insists on masks and social spacing in the morning, then other mornings don’t.
BUT I will say - Robyn’s school has been amazing, they have really changed Robyn in a good way, during lockdown she was fine and fun etc, but I know her learning was stalling - I can only do what I can do, but since school she now reads, writes, adds and now I know what to do from her telling me. Schools are possibly one of the most unappreciated and unspoken about heroes during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we had an important ways of working meeting, I love these type of conversations as it leads to fixes but also airing of “why it doesnt feel so smooth” chats. We discussed design not getting in to the ticket early enough and why we need to be in these chats sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 After our ways of working chat, today was a new day, and starting to fix processes, we all attended the road mapping session. This is the first time I’ve seen the vision and future of the product I am on, whilst it looks heavy - it provides me with an overview of what’s coming, and also anything I can task myself or the design team with prep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate moment happened… I realised this team is missing an updated user journey map and we need one pretty sharpish as it’s getting out of control to keep track. In my true style of anti-gatekeeper, I’m going to start it all off using Mural and motivate and engage the team to keep it a living project to show off when/if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A strange day of catch-ups before everyone goes off on leave during Christmas time, on and off time to work but plenty of work to keep me busy during the week before the break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great way to end the week, a show and tell with the wider team of my “area of work”, with a huge show of thank you from those on the frontline of the “thing we’ve built”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well earned weekend again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/21/weeknotes-no28-copy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/12/21/weeknotes-no28-copy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.27</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week might be the busiest week I’ve had ever at DWP, is it overwhelming, stressful, or a pleasurable workload? More than likely it’ll feel terrible in the moment, but incredibly positive in a week or two’s time due to “the thing I am doing”.
&lt;br /&gt;
It’s been an incredible couple of weeks, something I would not want to do again - but the outputs have been really good, some barriers on the way but what we have achieved in a short space of time has yet to be bettered in my career so far.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
BUT a huge highlight of the week is running a workshop for designers to assist in helping our communities come back together after a time of solo working and out-of-office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Started at 8:30, before meetings and requests come in to arrange and prioritise my workload for the day (and possibly week), early doors is meetings, meetings, and meetings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workload has ramped up over the past 3 weeks, due to holidays, people leaving, and just general needs for the country, it means a lot of context switching - but needs must at the moment, everyone s putting in a heck of a shift to make things better for people.
The afternoon was a run-through of a new project, it’s early doors but totally mind-blowing due to, again the context switching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today is the day I finally plan the (interaction designers only) workshop to discuss if/why/what and how we make community meet ups better. Working remotely can give the risk of the design community the excuse to not “get together” at the risk of us all feeling silo, lonely, and possibly feeling like are not being supported by fellow colleagues - which isn’t the case at all, but sometimes it’s just good to vent to a person “who gets it”(!).
I am REALLY into aligning things as a design team, having a constant and similar vibe throughout the hubs, and the way we talk to each other is a good way to keep our values the same and also allow cross-team working and more importantly - sharing and learning.
I have no idea what the answer is, but working remotely isn’t as easy as you read - it’s a lot of hard work to get communication good, honest, and often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I decided against putting in a well-placed swear word in the deck, but… I cant promise this will always happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First thing, stand up in the new team (I’m very popular at the moment - I’m collecting more teams than Robbie Keane - football reference FTW).
I hinted at it on Tuesday, but the context switching is tiring, it’s also exhausting and one thing I can take away and won’t ever do again (unless a must) when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:1’s planned this afternoon, good to talk about progression, etc, and catching up with other designers - seeing how they are getting on and ready to be that ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The day I unleash a 30-40 workshop upon other designers in the wider team. Finding out about how valuable communities are, how we can (if needed) to improve them - PROPER excited as I love this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, huge day for one of my teams - first time a team outside of a certain location has commited a huge design change to a platform (sorry for talking in tongues… but ya know… somethings I cant talk about too much), it’s been a while to get work to this level - earning trust, respect and alignment but we are here and arrived to deliver something brilliant that will help A LOT of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review of the workshop - went well, LOADS of great post its, really happy with how comfortable the team felt entering in their feelings, I hope I personally made them feel at ease.
Now to do the write up… who doesn’t love a deck?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning 1:1 with Gavin (Head of Design), who else can I spend serious time with to talk about gaming?
The rest of the day is to discuss some design changes to a team I’m working on (recently) about a very important project (possibly one of the most important one of my career) and updating a prototype that blows my mind (it’s not too complex, just been a heck of a lot of context switching and I think my brain is done for today).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bobbin and Bumble update:&lt;/strong&gt;
Friday evening is to discuss the launch of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/products/adjustable-ikea-highchair-footrest-bamboo-timber&quot; title=&quot;introducing bobbin and bumble&apos;s IKEA Highchair footrest&quot;&gt;wicked new product&lt;/a&gt; (that I can link now its live) for the IKEA highchair which helps your little one eat a lot better and be less wriggly - something I can promise you is a thing (hence the invention of the splash mat!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 11:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/03/weeknotes-no27.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/10/03/weeknotes-no27.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.26</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a little time off doing weeknotes as it didn’t feel right sharing the work I was doing due to it being so fast, needed, and also so important right now for the country.&lt;br /&gt;
Since my last update, I’ve worked in multiple workshops, made many service views, enjoyed some challenges, hated some challenges, and felt overwhelmed with life in general.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s also worth noting that dealing with work demands, and family demands have also been a challenge - one that many has spoken about, and one &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/2020/04/20/living-and-working-at-home.html&quot; title=&quot;my blog post on living and working at home&quot;&gt;I wrote about previously&lt;/a&gt; (to a lot of positive feedback too which I’m really grateful for).&lt;br /&gt;
I have also started to post to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/mikeycattell&quot; title=&quot;click here to see my dribbble account&quot;&gt;@dribbble&lt;/a&gt; with timeboxed design exercises to push my visual skills and also keep me fresh, on trends and to put any creative need to output in action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the past couple of weeks, I’ve really deep-dived into the Service Design role which I’ve really enjoyed and found it really helpful to one team in particular.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve also spent a lot of the last couple of weeks aligning the team to be User-centered and trying to remove barriers of discomfort not knowing the answer, it’s been a great challenge - helping me to really stretch my communication skills amongst many differing job-types and really selling the value of design and knowing it actually was effective is great feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first test of this was to educate to a team the value of design using a simple method I do that is along the lines of “process mapping”, so getting the team to split into two, getting them to “invent” the service journey from start to end - not a user journey but a service journey.&lt;br /&gt;
Along the way, they MUST write down who does this task, how they do this task, any risks, and what questions do we have about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output is always the same (so far) - the team on the same knowledge level, it’s a quick way to get the team co-design (and to show the value of co-design), and we have invented “discovery” backlog - the questions, the risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy peasy? Kinda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Realising my workload of recent times has been far too much, I decided to step down from a service team I was on (thankfully we have just hired an additional designer, so I managed to on-board him whilst working alongside him).&lt;br /&gt;
My last meeting with the team was to help direct them through their Discovery process - it’s a good feeling to know that people see you have a helper and (possible?) leader, we spoke through the point of discovery, what the (possible) point of their discovery is and what/how to deliver (thinking about presentations to stakeholders and what to share).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today felt totally different, my workload has halved and my happiness, therefore, has doubled.&lt;br /&gt;
This means more time to think, more time to reply to emails and more time to mentor a couple of people within DWP that I’ve had to park for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fortunately for them, I’m back with time - so they can expect plenty of direction!&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve even had time and motivation to write weekly notes again - finally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Back to my original (and in my opinion best obviously) team, working on decommissioning a service that we all worked hard to get up and running, but now it’s time to close it down due to completing its task. It’s been a great learning curve for the team to build it, and now to close it down is an even great one - thinking about all touchpoints, data storage, any user requirements and confirming the overall need to actually stop using the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working alongside one of my favourite PM’s means this is an easy task to run through, and I also get to dust down my interaction design chops - which I’ve left to go a little rusty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A quick catch up with the brilliant Content Designer whilst we discussing closing a service down, and how do we do it to actually help not hinder the end-user and inform them what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A presentation to one of the new starters about what we’ve been working on for the last year or so, and then early finish to go for a lovely walk with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B_aRxcQpTiI/&quot; title=&quot;a link to my instagram account&quot;&gt;fluffy dog&lt;/a&gt; and chatterbox daughter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Something I’ve missed a lot of the past year has been line-management duties or mentoring consistently.&lt;br /&gt;
This is about to change as I was picked to be on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outofofficehours.com/may-2020/volunteers&quot;&gt;Out of office hours month of mentors&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m so excited to start. I’ve already got a lot of requests to help new starters to the industry and also people just feeling in a rut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mentioned previously, it’s just been a good learning curve to know when to step back, give tasks to others, and realise I have other priorities. I feel a lot calmer now the rush of work needed has gone (for now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The lack of control at the moment of my own life and work has me in a spin. I had feelings of anxiety, anger, caged in, boredom, and just general stress.&lt;br /&gt;
The power of having GOOD people around you - whether to take work off you or people just having a normal conversation is brilliant and really not spoken about enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Feeling relieved my workload has halved and now I have time to think, to recover, and spend time with my family in the sun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 11:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/07/weeknotes-no26.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/05/07/weeknotes-no26.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
