<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 11:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 11:47:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.54</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, so it’s been a while hasn’t it?&lt;br /&gt;
Nevertheless, it’s lovely to see you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the space of not writing weeknotes, I have changed roles from working within DEFRA (which I loved) to working on Bobbin and Bumble for a month(ish) to now, leading the design charge at FCA (Financial Conduct Authority) and implementing their first ever Design System AND Prototyping kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I touch on my time at DEFRA, it was lovely, I enjoyed it there, and will forever remember the support and the friends I made (I still speak to them now even when I left so you know it’s the real deal!). It was fun, challenging and all the right stuff that I love when working on projects, I even managed to squeeze in presenting and passing an Alpha assessment(!), but I felt it was the right time to leave, especially when there was a need back home, working on the family business that I have not touched since going back to freelance/contracting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobbinandbumble.com/&quot; title=&quot;click here to view bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble is the family business&lt;/a&gt; in case this is new to you, it’s a real living fixture in our lives, my wife started it from our dining room table with a £5 sewing machine, and it’s now a fully breathing and living thing, and knowing her products are in people’s houses (and sometimes, the people are colleagues that do not realise I’m the owners husband!). My workload varies, from building emailers to content reviewing - tracking keywords (long and short tail) and just doing general website updates, all measurable, all enjoyable and all worthwhile!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to now, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fca.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;click to see FCA website&quot;&gt;Financial Conduct Authority&lt;/a&gt;, what a change of pace from working for myself to having deliverables, stakeholders (that isn’t my wife) and working from scratch. It’s the challenge I have been searching for a while, and it’s so enjoyable. From stakeholder meetings to presentations of the work done and what’s up and coming to writing code and shaping the future of the design within a huge organisation and taking along as many people and supporters as possible (and there are many cheerleaders here). It’s a great fit, and it keeps me and my brain busy, which is certainly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in the past week, we went to see a pantomime at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradfordplayhouse.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;visit bradford playhouse&quot;&gt;Bradford Playhouse&lt;/a&gt; and it was so funny, Peter Pan has never been as funny and the cast were brilliant, my kids loved it and there was a slight smothering of naughty jokes (which the cast told me off for laughing A LOT at).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seemed to have obtained a kitten, which was a shock to me and the children but I’ve been assured that it will support me in my mission to rid of any farm mice that seem to think it’s okay to camp out in the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2xvq7CLlEkw&quot;&gt;Amy Hupe: Your design system contribution practice is doomed to fail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
I watched this before starting at FCA, and I just thought it was a great reminder of what to do or not in this case in and around contribution to a design system. It’s one of the toughest parts of implementing a design system, and something that we are parking upon launch, and working with pilot teams closely for their direct feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon launch, I see contribution as just getting the users to use the thing, getting buy-in and also growing the list of pilot teams, which seems so easy when you clumsy write it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/20/weeknotes-no54.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/20/weeknotes-no54.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.53</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A fortnightly version of weeknotes, thinking this might be easier to maintain at the moment - this family lark is busy!
All the kids are back to school, meaning I get to work in silence again - which, on reflection feels very much like working from home, unsure that is a good thing.&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve covered a lot of ground over the past 2 weeks, While I felt like I wasn’t contributing much, I started to showcase the work covered and it’s a lot, and very much leading into our next phase (private beta) - which is just as exciting as alpha when you find out you need to change everything (jokes).&lt;br /&gt;
Mentoring again this week, from various ex-colleagues or direct reports which is just brilliant, it’s not only a warm fuzzy feeling but also confirmation that maybe I’m okay at this thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks have been nothing but busy at work, we have finalised (to a point) the prototype and all feel comfortable that it’s at the level we can say &lt;br /&gt;
“yep.. this could be the thing, let’s go forward” &lt;br /&gt;
And presenting this is no mean feat, questions arise as expected and hoped, and I then use these questions (which I always write down, group into themes and present back to the core team to showcase what we haven’t made clear as of yet or answered these over the past show and share’s), to help judge where we are in regards to stakeholder or users of the service (internally) acceptance and the general temperature of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far.. so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended an internal talk at the DEFRA community meet-up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craigabbott.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;visit craig&apos;s website to learn much more&quot;&gt;Craig Abbott&lt;/a&gt;, who is the master of all accessibility. He cleared up and educated the room on a lot of the mysteries and new requirements, and it was so good to see him. He has grown from our public speaking course many years ago, where we were both nervous little whispers, to now nervous loudspeakers, who I imagine are both quite comfortable presenting.. or we pretend to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led a workshop (surprise!) around, again finalising the full journey, but future-planning - what the heck is the final thing going to look like (balcony level), including things like touchpoints, decision points, workflow(of course) risks etc. The normal run-of-the-mill, but essential - whilst we all know this, we have never had it written down in an easy-to-read flow.. so here we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Listening to Craig’s talk, here is a link to his latest post:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craigabbott.co.uk/blog/making-microservices-accessible/&quot; title=&quot;read Craig&apos;s informational post about making microservices accessible&quot;&gt;Making microservices accessible&lt;/a&gt; on craigabbott.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being much more hands-on doing the design-doing, whilst I’m the type of designer that isn’t all head-down-in-the-prototype, I love getting into the weeds of the work after all the talking, presenting, workshopping and trading of notes and post-its happens (ironically, led by myself…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing my daughter being written to personally, insisting that she join a Synconised Swimming class, as she is years above her expected ability - this isn’t a surprise, due to her insistence that she swims at least 2-4 times a week, but it’s amazing to see her grow and improve in the things she loves to do - amazing what happens when you do things that you enjoy.. schools and companies take note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Google bloody merchant centre! Fudge meeee that’s a minefield. It’s a skill set I didn’t know I needed, but one I love having.
Being on top of this side of Bobbin and Bumble, means I get to see the results of our reach and add KPIs in for ourselves to measure against failure and success (hopefully the latter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am slowly coming to the end of this contract, and the unknown is starting to get near.. contracting is a murky world at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finalising the future of the service, and concreting the roadmap with the P.O. It feels like this project is taking shape and becoming very clear in it’s next steps and that is down to the team cutting back on workload and nailing presentations, risks etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being present in most of the user research sessions is enlightening and a stark reminder that this project has only just become in becoming the solution the business and the user wants. Exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending an assumptions workshop, (which we should have done weeks or even months ago, but better late than never) will allow us to finally have measurements of success or failure. This will link nicely to our design and service assumptions, but we haven’t had business assumptions for a while - I feel this was a mature step in finalising this project and helping assure the stakeholders and sponsors of the service that we are thinking of everything going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have not listened to this yet, but this podcast could be very interesting around Design Systems and their implementation of them, I’ve been there, done that and worn the very washed t-shirt, and always want to hear other people’s stories around this and how they succeed, but more importantly, where they failed (if there is such a thing in the world of iteration..).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/7hQgsv1QBRwFtMvITuipr0&quot;&gt;Getting buy-in for your design system - Design Systems WTF | Podcast on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/29/weeknotes-no53.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/29/weeknotes-no53.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.52</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lonnnnng week. &lt;br /&gt;
Work-wise I’m in the phase of being unsure what to work on, there are bigger things to look at, but immediate work to do - one of those weeks!
News around schools in Leeds being threatened and having them put in a “lockdown”, was shit, the world my kids are growing up within needs to look long and hard at its-self and have a talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I gathered all of the user journeys from our 1st week to this a week or so before the end of alpha - showing vast iterations powered by user research sessions, presentations to subject matter experts (SMEs) and wider team(s) input and we find ourselves at a good point.&lt;br /&gt;
Seeing the above work laid on in Mural, and seeing the changes we have done from initial thoughts (we all need a starting point) to where we are now is great and reminds me of the shift we’ve all put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listing all our assumptions, some we’ve found out, some still unanswered, and a handful we’ll look at during private beta - love this part where we start to measure against good vs. not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being asked to present “how I settle into teams” is great, just need to remember what the heck I do and write a thing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally left the house and met a pal that I hadn’t seen for years, in fact he once hired me when he overheard me mention at a bar (whilst ordering a drink) that I just left a project styling out a Magento theme (remember those days?).. cue me walking into his office the next day on my first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My daughter’s school issued warnings about being held in lockdown due to some idiots putting threats into schools. The world is fucking mad when kids are under threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working out what to work on first, it’s been tricky to prioritise, whilst it’s not a huge mass - it’s tough to work out what to do first and whether I need to do it at all. The difference between working as a consultant and a freelancer is the challenge here, as a consultant I would be expected to do everything, here I am expected to deliver high-end interaction outputs - which is much easier, but…I do not work slowly so I’m ahead of schedule!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am presenting to the design community next week on how I settled in, and I’m looking forward to that, taking any questions and seeing if my process is right if there are places I could work, and gaps I could fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Decided to reach into the vault and start to listen to one of my favourite speakers - Mike Monterio. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intercom.com/blog/podcasts/mule-design-mike-monteiro/&quot;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt; is his usual hard-hitting, direct speaking way, which I’m a huge fan of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Found a band that screams, plays violin and is VERY good - Imminence, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HNAD360Op_8&quot;&gt;this track&lt;/a&gt; is a complete banger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/19/weeknotes-no52.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/19/weeknotes-no52.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.51</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, it’s been a while, but the school holidays have also taken over my life (and a week away with friends in Turkey) and work being knee-deep in an Alpha phase that needs full-on concentration levels. 
It’s nice to be back, tracking my working week and reminding myself that it’s been going well, and whilst a tough project, an enjoyable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have made it, to the end of alpha with really great insights into users’ behaviours, not just using the prototype but their WHY, which is just as important as usability testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have validated our hypothesis’, not all positive - but that’s the point.
&lt;br /&gt;We have found things that the previous discovery team didn’t, which meant working at speed and learning very fast (it felt like an undiscovered discovery)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all our previous workshops, we have “invented” a new tagging location, which tested so well it was scary. We shall be sharing this with the design system team when the findings are written up.
Speaking of design system teams, there is a whisper I might be involved in that again.. so I’m certainly looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Whilst working at speed, it’s tough to keep on top of admin - tracking changes, tracking screen grabs and journeys - which means that I am now retro-screen grabbing previous journeys, I’m just grateful that the prototype has been structured properly and we also tracked changes, hypothesis against these changes and the reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working on a new portfolio site, nothing heavy, in fact much simpler as it is just me who updates it. Therefore it makes no sense to put the thrills, fills and fireworks on it - whilst I will be keeping my case studies (and adding more), it will be clear as to what I do, where I do it and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m looking forward to sharing the work that I did at HMRC on the Government Gateway, It was a great project and something I am very proud of, so keep an eye out for that.. like &lt;a href=&quot;/hmrc-security-console.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
More recently, I’ve been cutting my podcast list right down - less fluff and more educational which has changed my mindset completely.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve started to revisit Presentable, which is full of designer-led tips which are very timely, and I enjoyed Steve Parish on the High-Performance podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Enjoying James Parson this week, thinking of doing a monthly playlist as it changes so regularly on tastes, would be interesting whether the music matches work or mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I recently wanted to refresh my mind with what actually do an Interaction designer do during alpha. As an ex-consultant, I am use to being an all-rounder, doing anything and everything to get the goal done, and this post helped hugely to ensure that my worries of not doing everything was removed: &lt;a href=&quot;https://designnotes.blog.gov.uk/2017/04/07/things-to-consider-when-designing-in-alpha/&quot;&gt;Things to consider when designing in alpha&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/10/weeknotes-no51.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/10/weeknotes-no51.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.50</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What a week, busy, long and tiring and ending in rubbish weather, but you didn’t come here for the misery, you came here for the fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is a &lt;s&gt;crap&lt;/s&gt; joke to open with:&lt;br /&gt;
I tried to catch fog yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, with that out the way, on to this week’s action..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working alongside a good content designer (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/onetommyadams/&quot;&gt;Tom Adams&lt;/a&gt; hi ), is worth so much to me, pushing me constantly to do better - he has high standards and so do I, so it’s a must that we deliver something solid, useful with a heavy dollop of cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love seeing my friends push themselves and seeing them trying something, seeing the ever wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuahealey/&quot;&gt;Josh Healey&lt;/a&gt; post on the NHS website is a huge thing and I love seeing him doing some really good work (spoiler: link below in read of the week)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modest warning&lt;/em&gt; - f’ing smashing it at work with a prototype that I think might be the start of a potential solution within the huge-problem-with-maps arena. But let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentoring, I mean - is there anything better than seeing someone you mentor doing what you have recommended and them doing it above and beyond your expectations and them putting a spin on it and it is mega?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a moment waiting for the kettle to boil where I realised I am not the same person I was when presenting work, in the past I was too nervous to share work, too nervous to present what work was done and show confidence in the outputs and was even worse to large numbers.&lt;br /&gt;
Roll on today, I want that audience, I want the numbers, I want the challenge of presenting and I feel confident in myself, my presenting skills and I am interesting enough to listen to! I have to thank many people for this, but a huge help was a course I did with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jodarbyvoiceintheroom/&quot;&gt;Jo Darby&lt;/a&gt; who I cannot recommend enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That prototype I was speaking about above, was tough work, it’s a bodge-job but it was hard going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migrating my work computer to their new system.. fuuuuuuu… you know the rest.
Thinking about the future of the project, it’s now time I start planning for the private beta phase, backlog building.. it’s about time!&lt;br /&gt;
The faff around inside and outside IR35 is blowing my mind, it feels like such a bodge job (on par with my prototype) and makes zero sense sometimes, just like our tax system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Dealing with the outputs from users during the UR sessions, I am hoping there are tons of goodies and we have loads to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it’s tough to think about, it is a bit of copy and paste, but I’m looking forward to planning for private beta, and even the assessment that awaits us, I love me some admin stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelcattell.com/2023/07/11/weeknotes-no49.html&quot;&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt;, I posted a much softer genre of music, but I’m back with a twist, I insist you try out &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4EFb9FhLyFiDbYKwBwDZre?si=06cb42cbe4ed4114&quot;&gt;Electric Callboy&lt;/a&gt;, as a taster I would recommend We Got The Moves and I dare you to not nod your head to the beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On the NHS website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2023/why-accessible-design-is-good-design&quot;&gt;Why accessible design is good design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
I think we should all read this, it’s from a good egg Josh (two mentions in one post..) on the right side of design, who does everything in the interest of the user and is willing to go against the grain to get all users included.&lt;br /&gt;
Give it a read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/17/weeknotes-no50.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/17/weeknotes-no50.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.49</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are now fully in the swing of things here, the design process is happening and even the prototype kit is finally out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer workshop adventures and more time spent in Visual Studio Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time in York was fun, a full day of walking, eating, talking, laughing and even learning (thanks to Jorvik Viking Centre) was a timely reminder of why I contract, and why I should take more time away from work to look around and hang with my kids during teachers training days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working with a team of designers (and I often include BA’s etc in this, UX is a team sport) is bloody great, those who say working silo is better and quicker just are lying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusting down my brain for the prototype kit, it’s been a while but I am hoping you never lose it, as it may get complex later on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may have invented something within the Government around mapping, it’s a wait-and-see moment, all fed from last week’s workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a day off to take my beautiful daughter to York for the day, we have arranged to go to Yorvik Viking Center, eat whatever and everything and just have fun and chill together - cannot wait!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/robyn-york-july.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a photo of my lovely daughter in York on the shambles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Personally, it’s been a tough week, one I won’t forget and barely even want to talk about - so I won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work-wise, cramming in as much as possible within a week for the prototype is a little heavy, but also realising that you do not need to over-engineer something is easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We are finally talking to “external” users, or users - depending on how you wish to prioritise, I tend to go default and assume all other users have different titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are down to about 10-12 weeks left now, so it’s all happening - whilst I feel we are way on track, always that little doubt at the back of your mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best news of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not a watch of the week, but I’m delighted to read that Hype Park Cinema is back in action, it’s one of my favourite cinemas ever and it is back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am a huge fan of Matthew Syed, I even own one of his books which I plan to read with my daughter very soon called You Are Awesome, so of course, I would recommend you listen to his time on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/5n4eSRSjdHa3yEBxJcmbWZ?si=ab3a3da6679c46cf&quot; title=&quot;listen to Matthew Syed appearance on Performance Podcast&quot;&gt;Performance Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, as usual, it was full of great insights and examples of, I guess high performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A bit of a change of pace this week, naming artists that are not screaming down a mic - this time it’s the smoother tones of Sam Tompkins, guessing many might not know about him yet, but if you do not.. he’s on his way up. Great singer and song writer, great on Instagram too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
BBC iPlayer is great, but it’s even better with shows such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/iplayer/episode/p0fjnmbz/the-diary-of-a-ceo-series-1-5-gary-neville?at_mid=a8aj6E0RhS&amp;amp;at_campaign=TheDiaryOfACEOGaryNeville&amp;amp;at_medium=display_ad&amp;amp;at_campaign_type=owned&amp;amp;at_link_origin=discovery_cards&amp;amp;at_link_id=gr02&amp;amp;at_product=iplayer&amp;amp;at_ptr_name=bbc&amp;amp;at_ptr_type=media&amp;amp;at_format=image&amp;amp;at_objective=consumption&amp;amp;at_link_title=TheDiaryOfACEOGaryNeville&amp;amp;at_bbc_team=BBC&quot;&gt;The Diary of of a CEO&lt;/a&gt;, and this week’s turn is Gary Neville’s turn.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/11/weeknotes-no49.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/11/weeknotes-no49.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.48</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying out something new is tiring, exciting and nerve-wracking at the same time, and I honestly believe it’s the best way to learn and push yourself.&lt;br /&gt;
This week was a week of firsts, whilst delivering and once again - leading direction and scope to help meet user needs and business needs (or requirements) slap bang in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love it.&lt;br /&gt;
Now we lean heavily into iterate, test, fail, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi prototype kit, great to see you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While travelling on trains isn’t my favourite bit of the day, doing workshops is, leading rooms is something I enjoy and directing a room to keep them honest and the work flowing is a great challenge that I enjoy.
Trying out a new technique (mission impossible) during the workshop was a great experience that came off, and the outputs prove this, will certainly add that to the bag of tricks!&lt;br /&gt;
Seeing the team writing the post-it (as a project need) Accessibility is a great step forward, and something Defra seem to be on top of compared to previous public sectors. Less drum banging and just baked in from the start as a must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting colleagues, sharing knowledge of work and discussing future collaborations that will save the country money and time is an amazing feeling, and part and parcel of working at the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Reading people’s handwriting on Post-its..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working away, it’s tricky during a time of my life when I haven’t left the house during a working week for longer than a handful of hours, but it shakes the kids and seems to put the house into a state, I’m the one that is home, the consistent one so it’s a learning curve for us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Alpha always being hectic, it may creep into the overwhelming area, deadlines looming, assessments are incoming and my own standards are high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am hoping now, it’s time to do the prototypes, use all of my experience working within the design system teams and knock prototypes out that are useful, align with our UR goals and design requirements and meet all needs sooner than later - this is what I’m here for right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best news of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not a watch of the week, but I’m delighted to read that Hype Park Cinema is back in action, it’s one of my favourite cinemas ever and it is back&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/04/weeknotes-no48.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/04/weeknotes-no48.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.47</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hayfever has been awful this week or two, surely there has to be a cure for it by now?
It’s been a hard couple of weeks, really intense in regards to work we are doing whilst planning for work we need to do, all before the impending end-of-alpha deadline.&lt;br /&gt;
Life is great right now, spending loads of time with the kids and wife, making our house our own… slowly but surely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still can’t believe I leapt to contracting, but it feels good right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Presenting, I love showing the work we did as a team and selling, or should I reword that - SHOWING the value of having a designer in the room to facilitate and bring together knowledge sharing and problem solving under one roof, all tied up into a handy output (in this case an Experience map).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week is the first week we spoke and got deep with the SMEs, again - having more heads in the room (especially those who do the do) and providing that knowledge is key, and such a valuable key to delivering a successful service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, my old directs (from months, and years ago) all got in touch coincidently to discuss their careers, life at home and balancing it all. Suddenly, with two kids, my wife and I being self-employed have them believing we know what we are doing.. but aside from that, the feeling they give me when they get in touch is huge thumbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hayfever. Fuck hayfever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have all these outputs from the workshops, planning what next, what to do with the outputs, who to show, and why to show it (usual questions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Settling down, getting into the work without distractions of.. dare I say - workshops (although we do have one incoming which I will be leading!).&lt;br /&gt;
Prototyping some basic journeys to provide shape and context for review, and more mural flow diagrams for feedback.
Sounds much like an earphones-in-and-get-shit-done week to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Depression has played a part in my life, not directly affected but very closely in contact with it, and this one-off tweet by Stan Collymore was the tweet that helped me understand and, I guess, at the least respect (and by respect I mean - I don’t know what I mean) depression during my early days of learning about the illness. It had a great effect on me and I’m grateful, for what is just a long tweet from someone coming through it and getting on the other side.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitlonger.com/show/ecoqm1&quot;&gt;Stan Collymore’s tweet about what he is going through&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My film intake has halved whilst I’m in full-on work and dad mode (kids holidays last week!), but I am looking forward to working through my list of films, and maybe putting a web page live listing films and my short take reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I love Full Disclosure with James O’Brien and the episode with &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/23F1a3Me9bj0toeQkjtSjf?si=be342a5c6e9245ae&quot;&gt;Adrian Chiles&lt;/a&gt; was brilliant. It made me look at my habits with alcohol, I am not a heavy drinker but his throwaway quote “We are all trying to just get the high of the first pint” is a keeper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/21/weeknotes-no47.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/06/21/weeknotes-no47.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.46</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week has been workshop planning and doing, and I’ve bloody loved it. Put me in front of a team and let me facilitate the session and I’m the happiest. &lt;br /&gt;
Also, to top off a great week, my wife also appeared inside many newspapers these (and it’s been a heck of a week for news), showcasing her fantastic business she has worked so hard to go, from scratch and on her own. Cue the proud feelings and look of awe. The article appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesun.co.uk/money/22301224/savvy-mum-250000-5-sewing-machines/&quot;&gt;The Sun&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.express.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/1768186/side-hustle-success-money-making-business&quot;&gt;Daily Express&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leeds-live.co.uk/news/leeds-news/leeds-mum-two-grew-250000-26887972&quot;&gt;Leeds Live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We planned what we needed to deliver during alpha, and it was pretty intense, whilst it always feels an uphill challenge, I have been here so many times that it’s almost a script at this point. I tend to use the framework of the CDDO assessment as a guide and use that to keep the team keen, and the work honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led a UCD-led workshop around the as-is user experience, including risks, opportunities, and pain points, which was a first for many team members!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, I enjoy Mural, so getting back into mapping, strategising and facilitating is my thing.
I feel a full grip on the project, I might not need to know everything (and I am ok with that), but I know what needs doing when it needs doing and what it’ll end up being, which ensures I stay a lot more focused and also ensures the team that they will see value from the UCD team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Doing workshops remotely is a challenge, it’s certainly doable, but it isn’t accessible to all - a huge challenge to ensure everyone is heard, can even attend or just feels comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiredness, this week has been heavy in regards to workload - not all weeks are the same, but this one is heavy on the UCD team (as alpha should be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding time to do things outside of work, has owned me this week (not a huge issue), but my windowsill won’t paint its-self!
I am working on a project that might need to use maps, but finding good findings on maps is proving to be a tricky task, whilst we know they are drenched in accessibility issues, there isn’t much written about what is done/being done, so if you do know - shout me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Running through the first workshop face to face (in Birmingham) with the team and evaluating what we did, I am looking forward to doing the outputs and getting the future documents shaped (including doing a How Might We session with the pain points, risks etc gained from this week’s workshop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is not the first time I’ve read this article, but as a team (led by the brilliant Tom) we ran a How might we session, and if you need guidance on how we did this - look no further than this brilliant post by Ben Holliday.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/leading-service-design/asking-the-right-questions-to-frame-the-problem-4df95a317983&quot;&gt;Asking the right questions to frame the problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch of the week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My film intake has halved whilst I’m in full-on work and dad mode (kids holidays last week!), but I am looking forward to working through my list of films, and maybe putting a web page live listing films and my short take reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/09/weeknotes-no46.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/06/09/weeknotes-no46.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.45</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The weather is sparkling, everyone’s mood is 100% brilliant and the BBQs are fully in motion.
Work is busy, deep in thought, deep in workshop planning and deep in reading documentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s get onto what the week was like, sharpies and Post it’s at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did I enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The sun is out, I’m averaging a bbq a day and spending evenings either in the garden or out and about locally surrounded by cows, sheep, green hills and just niceness&lt;br /&gt;
Did I mention I love Alpha, it really gives me a chance to build relationships and shape the team in their understanding AND value of UCD-led workshops, but more importantly, it allows me to throw outputs out there that people can use, rip apart and improve and get under-the-skin of the project - I am just a facilitator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the team has just been a joy, a really enjoyable experience. We’ve cheered each other on, asked questions, joined up working and given feedback to one another and it’s just worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have mentioned this before, but the community here at Defra is much different to other places, its a little smaller than what I’ve worked in, but a lot more togetherness and understanding of challenges AND there isn’t a lot of sugar coating issues/problems that we all know exist in the public sector (it’s the same everywhere!), and I just feel sharing wins and struggles and failures is the way forward and whilst doing that, cheering people on as they express this is amazing - a healthy COP (Community of Practice) experience and one that I always attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What challenged me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Knowing where to start, this is always tricky. Often it’s easiest to just start doing a handful of things to just get the ball rolling, and this project has been no different.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve run off in directions and realised, hold up - this is silo working and I’m not doing the best I can do with that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I looking forward to next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kickstarting the workshops, owning the problem and facilitating the team to be the best with outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it - a ton of workshopping and leading design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 08:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/weeknotes-no45.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/weeknotes-no45.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
