<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 22:12:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonky week of WFH and in the office.&lt;br /&gt;
Having your house smashed to bits is not how to prepare for a relaxing Christmas, but hopefully it’ll run so smoothly I wont even realise I’m filing the kettle up from the bathroom tap, washing up in the shower and having sandwiches for each dinner. Barely noticable..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plus points was Monday - worked so well with the wider team, having a U.R. touch point for help, and he’s been great - so helpful.
Working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/robynandmimi/&quot; title=&quot;my wifes instagram account - Robyn and Mimi&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt; has been a huge highlight as well, I’ve shared all I know about managing projects, building emails to writing (hopefully) interesting posts, reminds me of the old days of contracting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Catch ups as normal at work with the wider design team.
Also, working alongside a User Researcher for advice, its been an interesting learning experience working without a User Researcher in the team and filling in the gaps.
Doing a discussion guide, finding out assumptions/questions, getting the team to see what they class as possible issues look for trends in the pile of issues that the users have sent in (using Jira as a base to post these issues to).
I’ve enjoyed this, always great to learn more when possible and the level of support received from the team and business in this resource shortage has been good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, my evenings are taken up working on Emma’s business website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://bobbinandbumble.com&quot; title=&quot;click here to see bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt;, reworking the site to v2 to add more content to the home page, it’s been an interesting journey getting the site live, we’ve had minor issues along the way - which, back in my contracting days I would have caught instantly.. but the rust is showing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH - builders are in!&lt;br /&gt;
Anxiety is on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of loud terrible noises, and pure panic from myself. Ahh - who’s idea was this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finalising the discussion guide in preparation for tomorrow’s run through with the content designer.&lt;br /&gt;
Day of doing the admin jobs, as it’s nice and quiet.. well its nice.. well i’m at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Another WFH day, quiet days like this are perfect for learning - which means for me… reading up on discovery processes from pages such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/service-manual/agile-delivery/how-the-discovery-phase-works&quot; title=&quot;gov.uk discovery guide&quot;&gt;Gov.UK Discovery guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a while since I was part of the early days of a project (4 years), so it’s great to have a refresher and to share my findings with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Morning stand up, as I’ve been out of the office for two days these are useful so I know what others are up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick chat through on the UR plans for visiting and conducting interviews, and then confirming the discussion guide - just a date and location to decide on now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the project is nearer an end - I’m looking forward to the health check that I have needed to instigate, hopefully it shows everything is running as smoothly as hoped, but also to let them feel listened to and do any fixes that need doing instantly to the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workload has lightened up, allowing me to work on the “community” things that DWP does so well. Speaking to other team members, seeing what I can take from my previous experience working with other design teams and share and just “be in the same room and listen” to how the team is functioning and check for any patterns.&lt;br /&gt;
This is the stuff I love doing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Somehow.. the team is all WFH (including me) - so a morning chat on Slack is needed. You can tell this team is a healthy pack of friends and colleagues by the fact we take turns when talking, wait for the conversation to end, and comment. And proudly - if there is a problem we all swarm around and help, if needed we down tools and assist. It might be one of the friendliest and most helpful teams i’ve ever worked in. It’s amazing and a real joy to spend my working hours with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are soon to go into Discovery, and I’ve given myself the task of lining up some meetings with colleagues who have gone through the discovery “adventure” before, and see what they are doing, done and find out how they found the whys and do the hows and to share to the team the findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sharing issues with London and Manchester shows that as a team - we can really work well together. In our time of need (we are under-resourced in User Researchers at the moment), we could call upon one and he instantly offered his help and understood our situation. He may not be able to do “field work” (being onsite to speak to users), but he can and is assisting us in doing it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Great to work outside of work, and remind myself I can launch a product. Working with my wife on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bobbinandbumble.com&quot; title=&quot;click here to see bobbin and bumble&quot;&gt;Bobbin and Bumble&lt;/a&gt; has been a highlight - its reminded me of ways to prioritise work, wider thinking, and building emails (that one I would happily forget).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tough to keep motivated sometimes when house / building issues arise, work gets busier, and I also promised to deliver on my wife’s website. Thankfully, I’ve been here before and learned to say no in the past, but its always tough when I have promised on things that NEED to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I read up on onsite SEO, I built emailers, I planned campaigns, I somehow managed a team of builders, I stayed motivated and I managed to keep positive. &lt;br /&gt;Thank god the week is over!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/05/weeknotes-no19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/11/05/weeknotes-no19.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ego or Self Esteem?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use to be ok describing myself as “having a big ego”, it felt it was the right description to share how I felt, and it’s taken a good number of years to realise it’s not ego, it’s self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego has its stigma, who wants an ego? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve all worked in teams where the room is jam packed of egos, all shouting, all pressing, all wanting their point of view to be THE point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ego doesn’t back down though, &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ego doesn’t listen, &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ego can kill other people’s esteem, it can take over a room, it can dictate a room and you become the person everyone doesn’t like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that me? &lt;br /&gt;
Is that you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between ego and self-esteem is tricky to work out, purposely fooling us that both are the same, yet outwardly they are so different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ego is - envy, greed, anger, power, control, loud. &lt;br /&gt;
Self-esteem is - joy, peace, love, kindness, empathy, less powerful. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ego says I know everything. &lt;br /&gt;
Self-esteem wants to learn from everyone. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-esteem wants to grow and not settle, ego drowns in knowing and switching off, why learn when you know it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard the saying “leave your ego at the door”, you certainly can’t make others do this but you can check your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve mentored for the past 10 years, and line managed for vast amounts of my career and I’ve seen that ego has cost so many people opportunities, relationships or job promotions. Ego provides short quick gains but it’s a marathon not a 100m sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combating this mentality is tough, if you can manage to differentiate the two, you can teach it forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I break it down to these two (hopefully simple) points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego is a comparison tool&lt;/strong&gt; - you compare yourself to them and either justifying your growth via someone else’s failure or your ability to get the praise you need.&lt;br /&gt;
Simple comments such as “I launched a business and sold out in days” is a statement you should be proud of, but it’s also a comparison statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-esteem is also a comparison tool, but so different,&lt;/strong&gt; it compares yourself to yourself. It compares you to a previous milestone “this time last year I wanted to start a business, well I did it” or
“I started a business and I can’t believe it compared to where I was last year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is huge and quite obvious. Having a competitive edge against yourself is far easier to track, and it’s 100% honest and more importantly - a lot healthier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself unsure which side you are on - try a day of writing up “what you did” in bullets, and see which points stand out and what the feeling was behind them. Was it a positive “thing” that built up everyone else or yourself, or did it affect others in a negative way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if this post was useful by getting in touch &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikeycattell&quot; title=&quot;follow me on twitter at mikeycattell&quot;&gt;@mikeycattell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 21:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/24/ego-or-self-esteem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/24/ego-or-self-esteem.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.18</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve said this before, but I have really landed on my feet with the team I’m in. Being able to lead on the design, and the bit that excites me the most - lead on how we “do” design is so much fun and where I see my strengths.
Along the way, the team has learned that we all have a “design say”, and you should not be scared of getting involved in designing with me, after all they play a huge part in the overall User Experience of the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has really felt great and handing over my first “big” design piece went so smooth, no shocks, no surprises and certainly no friction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll on next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning stand-up with the rest of the wider team - technology means we can discuss the weeks work with teams from London, Manchester, and obv including us Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thing we never discuss is how many e-learning courses you HAVE to do upon joining a new company. This morning to the afternoon was a complete write-off due to learning about Health and Safety.
E-learning done in flash? YES PLEASE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afternoons on Monday are reserved for show and tells, we managed to show off one of the projects I’ve worked very lightly on. It’s a project I’ve been amongst, seeing it climb heights and hit lows - but the consistency has been a great design team behind it.
A big discussion point from the show and tell was unexpected - a Design System issue, is it up to date? are we using the correct one? do we need to work closer together and get it updated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally believe our design system is a good one, and you can use styles and patterns from either of them (if they work.. they work), but consistency is important and I’m unsure we talk enough about using it in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Worked from home in the morning, i’m sure i’ll look back at today and think this seemed so long ago but.. I will ask this question over and over again:
“WHY IS IT SO HARD TO GET A NEW KITCHEN PUT IN A HOUSE?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to work.. in the afternoon I returned to the office to handover the prototype Izzy and myself have been working on. The meeting involved Product Owner, Business Analysis and a Developer / QA.
Started off with the “why we are doing it”, followed by current implemenation, to a sketch of user-flow and finally showing the world (avoiding at all cost the “real estate tour”), explaining why we did this pattern etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype didn’t surprise anyone due to us all designing the flow, and pages together - so it was a piece of cake. Minor amends to parts of the page needing to be elsewhere (It was a misunderstanding on my part).
Out of this meeting, my actions were:
Finish prototype with minor amends, update Jira ticket and.. job done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how design should be done, i’m sure there will be harder pieces of work but it was a brilliant issue to pick as the teams first design walk-through and really showed the value of team designing, and also letting me “do my thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A busy day finishing off the prototype, which is a lot easier than I ever expected.
Handover to the developers will be a piece of cake too, as they have no surprises coming - they helped design it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handing over the prototype means, discussing (a lot) with the Product Owner and Business Analysis on how to write up tickets, if we can split any user flows up and what outcomes need to be viewed and accounted for.
Lots of Jira stuff, that I always try and hide away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 On leave.
Spent the day with my daughter going pumpkin picking and going to a farm with tons of Halloween activities!
Heck of a muddy day, but a fun fun day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH today, working heavily on the future of the product I am on.
Morning used to dial into the morning stand up with the team - worked really well and reminded me of my Sky Bet days!
Preparation for the afternoon’s meeting, running through the team’s requirements of a User Researcher (we are running a team without one) with the Lead UR of my department.
Meeting went so well, really liked her opinion and approach and certainly feel supported in our next steps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aim next week is to forge a working relationship with the team in London, and hopefully share work and get their answers (if you know me.. you’ll know I believe in “if the work has done before.. dont re-invent the wheel”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finishing the prototype and everyone being on board with it proved that the process we have decided on (so far) works, and works well. It led from user feedback, hard questions of “is this the best thing we can do” to “I’m unsure about this design” to “lets whack this into a prototype!” to finally everyone agreeing its good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I believe, as a team we have learned together we can improve the service so much more by working together. We are such a close-knit team that any issues, or even “feelings” that the service isnt as good as it should be - it shouted out and tackled together.&lt;br /&gt;
This is how design should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding User Research resource! I enjoy having a UR on my team, so speaking to the Lead User Resarch on Friday was amazing and allows myself and the Product Owner to feel supported and it was just an ace meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I promise i’ll stop talking about it.. but as a team we did a thing, it went well, and we will be launching the changes soon.&lt;br /&gt;
This is ace.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 09:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/weeknotes-no18.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/weeknotes-no18.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.17</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sad week, losing a really strong and clever Delivery Manager but he has given a lot of education to the team which we shall keep using and take us forward.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Really enjoyed this week again, loads of “doing” and team working.
We’ve really worked well together, a healthy discussion on taking the service forward and a good understanding of what each role does. It’s less about stepping on toes, as more to understanding what-we-do.
&lt;br /&gt;
Lovely stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand-ups a plenty, standard Monday.
Running through initial “edit user” information page, following on from the team’s design session with the B.A and content design to sense check.
Upon running through, it did not really fit the service needs, this is exactly the design feedback I require and ways of working to improve myself and more importantly, the user’s service experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon was spent sketching user flows, and going through what patterns suit this page. Was great to do this, as initial planning is my favourite task of the design process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Quiet day today, running through the prototype and sketching up user flows to help the team understand the issues of what we initially planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always the way - you run away from a design workshop thinking you have all the answers, get to your desk and find out the questions do not align with the answers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early kick-off meeting - running through all the content feedback and design patterns check. Loads of little minor amends, but will add so much to the user experience - quick wins with huge value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally - after 4 months of waiting… i’ve picked up all of my hardware to be a fully-fledged DWP worker!&lt;br /&gt;
I CAN SEE MY PAYSLIPS EASILY!&lt;br /&gt;
This pick up of hardware did mean a 2 hour tutorial on how to use the Surface Pro, which I’m maybe a tad late to learn this as its basically a windows machine - BUT parts of the meeting were about how to use the internal system which I 100% need to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The bus ran late - standard, so soon as I arrived it was Sprint Planning, but this team is so smooth now and we are in the days of bug fixing and automation - the planning is done in half the time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As if coincidence, the Delivery Manager’s last week here, he has been a breath of fresh air - he has controlled the room during retros etc, and also provided a level of trust that is often overlooked as a DM. A role that is often missed is the role of keeping the team as happy as possible - whether it be work-wise or team personality clashes.. he has managed to do that very well.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Be hugely missed, but I did get his locker - so… win some lose some.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last hour of the day - ran through the prototype with the content designer (Izzy), and we nailed it - we landed the big one! Did a very simple sketch of the user journey, Izzy changed one thing and saved a wasted page.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The power of doing good content eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As normal, quiet in the office.
Stand up to confirm the prototype is ready to be written up properly in tickets on Jira (the developers know what’s coming from the previous meeting), will be doing a run-through Monday or Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great way to end the day by finishing the sprint task, and having many more lined up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Realising you are wrong, and willing to fix it from other people’s ideas.
This is a secret power that all designers should have, many people over the years have crossed my work out and come up with something much more clever - DWP has this in spades and something I try to promote and get everyone thinking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How powerful is good content on a page?&lt;br /&gt;
It saved me trying to mangle a user-flow into a longer journey, a simple phase from Izzy and the page vastly improved and cut down so much more work for both design, dev and more importantly - the user.&lt;br /&gt;
Great content makes my job so so much easier - value content more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding services is tough - there is not an easy way to get “it”, but have time and confidence to ask the easy or hard questions makes my job a lot easier and a lot more comfortable. This is a huge credit to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a team - we did a thing that will be a great time saver for the users, AND they get what they wanted!&lt;br /&gt;
So many wins, from designing as a team to making the users happy, to avoiding user risk.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 19:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/14/weeknotes-no17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/14/weeknotes-no17.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perfecting the pitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During long discussions with designers over the years, often the subject that our roles are not understood properly is mentioned as if it’s a badge to wear.
It’s changed over the years, from “they’ve no idea what I do, they’ve got me designing PowerPoint presentations” to “they just made the decision themselves” to the unacceptable “they didn’t even include me in the meeting”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Of course it does and you know why? We’ve all said it, damn it I’VE said it.&lt;br /&gt;
The amount of times over the years I’ve complained about “teams not getting it” or asking people around me “why didn’t they ask me to do it?” And they’ve replied &lt;br /&gt;
“We didn’t know that’s what you do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s taken a while to realise it was my fault, and when I knew this it was so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The turning point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever been asked at a wedding to do your elevator pitch? 
“So what do you do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you have, and in 6-seconds-you-have-between-floors to answer:
“umm I’m a… designer”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“….. that’s great”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can’t tell a stranger what I do for my 9-5 what chance does a team have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use to introduce myself as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Hi, I’m a designer, I design websites for companies. Sometimes I design emails, logos and often I build websites too”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So general, so boring, so me me me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way of introducing is “pattern fitting”, it’s forcing them down the avenue of “what you want them to want you for”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want the answer to be around them, they are the hero here - they are either looking for a solution for themselves or want to help a friend - it’s cool to send a message to someone “hey, I’ve met someone who will help you do your thing and turn it into reality”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was once told a quick tip to remember when doing your pitch:
Tell a story, it’s not about you, it’s about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break it down into three steps:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The who,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The do,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The who’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The who’s is a great one to open up, but often the toughest. A lot is relying on you knowing the answer, and being proud of it. Your audience parents of new borns? Or Dog owners? Or agencies short of staff? Whatever it is, it’s a niche, it’s your speciality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get specific on the who - if it doesn’t suit their needs, I promise you they will know someone who it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite one, this is the one which is the most fun, once you’ve got this worked out you’ll have the skills to make people believe in you, respect you and more important know what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do&lt;/strong&gt; - this is after your work, after your solution - talk about how great lives are after. If they are interested - talk more about it, if not you might need to change your approach to match them (you’ll do something they’ll need or like), find the common ground and hone in on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point of this all? 
Leading to telling them what you can do for them. 
So you design websites for start ups?
What is it you actually do for these start ups?
Help with growing their user base? Build communities?
Whatever it is, make them picture success - their success, the projects success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting this all together is no easy feat, but once mastered it’ll help integrate you into a team, sell your work, and educate anyone nearby to what you do, hopefully leaving no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve fluffed many introductions, but with this template it goes something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I’m an interaction designer for DWP, 
I (help teams) help the general public have an easier life by providing them with a simple way of using online and offline services, enabling them to take control and manage their own life and make the whole process as stressless as possible.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should warrant enough of a response to find out more, this is new territory so don’t fluff your lines now - you’ve got them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on interest, I would them dip into a bit more about the process - how do I enable the users to manage their own life with examples, then go into success stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to turn this into your day to day work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can make a stranger understand your role, you can certainly make someone who is sat either a slack call or a shout over the desk away “get you”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you do not need to do the introduction routine, but you can certainly become a lot clearer on your own reason for being there, and help to remind others why you are there, and if you need to introduce yourself to a new starter - then you are prepared to start that relationship off on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this post has provided value to a tough subject, it’s not perfect but it’s a start and I would love to see and hear how you introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/perfecting-the-pitch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.16</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I did some designing stuff this week, and it was brilliant!
Leading this team into a new era of design and development working together has been such a joy, and I cant wait for more design gatherings.&lt;br /&gt;
Also happening this week, was a day of taking stock and realising that I cant carry on with two teams, so officially left a team and have concentrated my attention on one team with design backlog bigger than you could ever dream of (they haven’t had a designer since January).&lt;br /&gt;
The challenge is huge, but im happy to be knee-deep in work, deciding with the team which pieces to work on, showing value, getting everyone to design and the doing, the talking and the showing of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early discussions with the P.O. about where a project is heading, we both agreed that we should get it to a level of being able to let it go, this then started another discussion on planning “online user life improvements” - so tasked myself with checking for broken design patterns, acting on UR feedback and any feedback which is daily given to our P.O/BAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two designers from Manchester came to Leeds, great to catch up with other team members and see whats happening else where, most catch ups are not always about sharing work but ways-of-working that interests me the most.
Plenty of chats about how to deal with personalities, issues on sharing work and finding your voice within the team.
Lots of sharing and learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Backlog meeting - need to plan out future U.R with one, idea is to use a UR as a consultant as waiting time is too short as the project is winding down.
Will use U.R. to line up possible, will run through previous UR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran a design gathering, the first the team has ever had in the open - it was an honest, round table discussion with good.. no GREAT solutions and it felt totally normal and comfortable. This really felt like we’ve turned a corner and design getting the seat at the table it needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.O. also provided feedback afterwards to me, he found it brilliant, proactive and enjoyed having a solid output/actions list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning retro of the retro - a session to discuss team happiness around hot desking / lack of chairs.
I’m unsure how I feel about this retro, part of me felt really awkward and hesitant to talk, other part of me also realised that there isn’t enough seats in the area and this causes expected friction - everyone likes to have a “home” in an office. Unsure the fix, and I’m unsure everyone came out of it happier than when they went in - but time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caught up with my line manager Juliana, amazing to run through how much has changed in 3 months, from discussing lightly about design to leading a design gathering around a tv and getting others to design verbally.
Speaking of the design gathering.. rest of the day prototyping!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 The day was taken up with updating the prototype, working out a system to take the prototype forward.
In short: I want to split the prototype up a little tidier, per sprint instead of doing a list of “tasks”, this way we keep focus on sections and journeys rather than the developers expecting a fully functioning prototype (that we all know will be broken!). Lowering and re-educating expectations and reasons for the prototype, whilst working at speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started also working through the existing platform, for a design run-through - with the lack of knowledge of how the user is working with the system, I am just checking the design patterns used are suitable for the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Friday is NUX day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was ace, caught up with loads of ex-colleagues from Sky Bet, and current work buddies from DWP.
In regards to the talks - I really really enjoyed &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThatGirlVim&quot; title=&quot;follow thatgirlvim on twitter&quot;&gt;Vimla Appadoo&lt;/a&gt; talk on “It’s Time to Redesign Design”, its right up my street and I love her approach and talk on showing and talking about the value of design away from the pretty stuff.
Also worth a shout was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Amy_Hupe&quot; title=&quot;follow amy on twitter&quot;&gt;Amy Hupe’s&lt;/a&gt; talk - funny, enlightening and totally interesting on “Inclusive Documentation”. My content designer pals were going crazy with notes and pictures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always forget though how long NUX is - early and late finish, but i’ll do it all again next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/weeknotes-no16.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/08/weeknotes-no16.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.15</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time 7 years ago I got married - so the week started off on a brilliant high!&lt;br /&gt;
I’m really excited to see what happens next week (which is strange as im doing a week notes for the past week), but we get to start seeing if the design process is going to work and how it is going to work within the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today was my wedding anniversary - so it was a well earned day off.
&lt;br /&gt;
7 brilliant years of being married, with more than I can remember years of dating before. I’ve learned so much about myself since dating Emma, she has given me self-confidence, self-worth and a drive that I could never have if it wasn’t for her.   &lt;br /&gt;Also, she finds me funny - so she’s obviously perfect..
&lt;br /&gt;
We went on a date at the cinema to watch “Hustlers” (Emma’s choice) and binge ate at a rather brilliant place called “Blue Sakura”. It was a great day and as a bonus I got to take my daughter to school and pick her up as a surprise - so she was really excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Caught up about the User Research feedback from last week, incredibly insightful when all the information is grouped together, and it’s great to see the UR team presenting and being strong about the work they do. I now await to see the next steps from the P.O.
&lt;br /&gt;
A content design catch up, explaining what I’m currently working on and how our “pre-planning” meeting went (dealing with design backlog), it turns out there is a lot of want from the team to get the design rolling and really make our users happy. I can’t really express how excited to try this new process, we can get the process wrong and it feels totally safe to, and the content design is totally onboard with it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up in “Team Two” are really good now, adding a design section to the board has really caused great discussions, the aim for me is to allow all the team to know every ticket on the board and the “why” we are doing them. 
&lt;br /&gt;After stand up, we planned additional discussions on what to work on next, felt really valued as a designer (which isn’t always the feeling) and a lot of good work ahead and plenty of opportunities to make a difference! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Attended a Retro&lt;/strong&gt; - good open session (as they always are), things needing to be shared and ownership of the issue. A lot of discussions on hot desking / seat arrangements which is causing a rift. &lt;br /&gt;
Similar trends running through the recent retro’s, actions being taken away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sprint Planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Goals set for this sprint are “focus on integration”, design work is being measured (correctly) by value (user and business) against effort. &lt;br /&gt;
Biggest conversational point from the design team (I’m happy to put my name on this) is if we should action some design amends due to one product not following GOV.UK styles, components and patterns. 
&lt;br /&gt;
I know we should change it - but.. value against effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Blinking BUS ISSUES!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Attended my other teams Sprint planning - a great round table approach. Discussed lack of User Researcher being an issue and a high risk when making design decisions (something I’m not comfortable on). Also discussed how to hand over design and content work to developers correctly (surrounding when, how and the whys).&lt;br /&gt;
Ideally, the answer is “as soon as possible”, I feel the team works best when everyone is involved in the design process (from sketching to round tables), so to avoid design decisions being tested and not being able to be implemented due to data/development issues. My ex-life as a developer has made me 100% sure this is the right ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A very quiet day in the office, Friday’s are famous for WFH or people’s non-working day. Had my 1:1 with Head of Design, discussed how my time shared between two teams is starting to have an impact on the work I do, and time spent actually working.&lt;br /&gt;
A quick look at my diary showed me - out of a 37 hour working week, I actually had 12 hours to sit at my desk and “do” work I needed to do.
The outcome was agreed that I would slowly work with just one team, which for me personally feels a great move as initially I worked closer with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Celebrating my wedding anniversary was such a fun day, and it was nice to spend a complete day with my wife, on our own doing normal couple things, which is always a struggle when you have a little one, but we should do it more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
User Research is really really good, and its key we have access to it almost as easy as it is to get access to a developer. Without one, we are struggling to get work done, as we have more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Accepting that I cannot do it all, I do not need to go to every meeting, I cannot help everyone and I need to realise that I have a limited time per-week and is it better to give 50% on two projects or 100% on one? I personally feel one project, and many others have agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First time in a while, I feel this week was a flat week. Some highs, but a couple of lows in there too - not a terrible week, just felt the week ran away from me before I caught it up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/03/weeknotes-no15.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/03/weeknotes-no15.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.14</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Testing all day in Harrogate.&lt;br /&gt;
I love going to Harrogate to see the team and more importantly check in with the users, Speaking to them means we are listening to their needs, and taking their feedback on board - which is why we are doing this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was no different, going in with assumptions and the user totally blowing them out of the water - standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today, early doors was a pre-pre-planning. Simply put, team two works their way through the backlog with designers, BA, dev, PO and DM and we work out when we need it, what do we need, and why we need it. &lt;br /&gt; 
Makes sense? It really does, it’s a new thing that we are testing out, and it feels a huge step forward for my complete squad. I hope it makes a difference. &lt;br /&gt; 
Also we discussed how to work together better and get the developers in the process quicker, something I am deeply passionate about - design shouldn’t be run silo, it’s a team sport, as is UX.  Definition of ready: how to ensure tickets are ready to play - really good meeting, we ended up with 7 points that we all decided (as a team) to be the right ones (for now), a strong design presence in the room (and it wasn’t me!), others involving user and business needs, and development / QA requirements.  &lt;br /&gt; 
Also needing to be put on the table is a “success criteria” and how do we measure. One for the future, but again, one I’m passionate about - I love celebrating wins, but also finding out about losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Caught up with content designer and ran through the 2 meetings I had yesterday.
U.C.D meet up - ran through my tasks at current, strong discussion on types of prototype tools we use, I didn’t even know we used most (any) of them, I always thought DWP worked with coded prototypes, but a lot were included in the list - from sketch to marvel to axure!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Afternoon - white board session..YES! Ran through a page to edit user information - so many scenarios and possible outcomes, made a lot clearer by working with a BA and PO who are willing to make it as simple-to-understand. Finished the whiteboard session with sketches on a whiteboard (as a team I’m trying to use processes in everything and this is one) and actions to be done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This. Is. How. It. Works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
WFH day - every now and then I like to get out of the office and work on things without noise. This allows me to catch up on emails, write prep notes for the week/sprint after and to just catch my breath.&lt;br /&gt;
Today was exactly this - digest what i’ve worked on, tidy up my computer desktop and files, plan my next tasks, read and reply to emails, slack people who I need to arrange meetings with and other general admin.&lt;br /&gt;
This is promoted often in companies, and is one of the first questions I ask at interviews: &lt;br /&gt;What is the work/life balance like?&lt;br /&gt;
Answers can vary - but it’s easy to work out quickly if it’s suitable to match your own needs.&lt;br /&gt;
(All my previous perm jobs have ALWAYS matched my need for space and to work on my own and cater for childcare issues).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Spent time using the internal system to gain access to benefits and pension information - in the past couple of years I’ve really started to take care of this side of work, and having a good pension is a great start!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Started to prototype the design work required from the whiteboard session, using Sketch to produce flat jpgs before going near a prototype - I design as a team, so it’s always discussions first then upon agreement, we then go into prototypes to test, this enables sign off within the team for: 
&lt;br /&gt;What data is available, &lt;br /&gt;Can we build it, &lt;br /&gt;Is this the right thing to do, &lt;br /&gt;Is the design right, &lt;br /&gt;Why are we doing this.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I always want honestly in my work, and providing an open table gathering means you have to be honest and open about questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday. We worked as a team to get an outcome we all agreed to, and it felt so right. It was a room full of respect, intelligence and the want to succeed. &lt;br /&gt;I cannot stress how much I enjoy working in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not necessary a learned thing, but remembering how Sky Bet was when I first joined and the struggles, the learnings and the success we had as a team to provide a smooth design and delivery process has spurred me on endless to really get it right here. It’s not perfect at the moment, but there is always hope and incredible potential to get there - working with a team of high achievers wanting to do the right thing is a benefit that I appreciate.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have a plan in mind and an end goal that I’ve shared often with my line managers, and it’s close to getting there, and I’m proud of the team that has helped me correct, change, and vastly improve my plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Working within a team that is busy often leads to poor communication, and we’ve felt that over the past couple of weeks, and this week was the conclusion of that. It’s not easy to feel overlooked, and it’s hard to not take it personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The whiteboard session was brilliant, I’m so happy to see how great we worked together getting to a possible solution quickly, and as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 21:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/02/weeknotes-no14.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/02/weeknotes-no14.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Confidence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lacking confidence was a problem I hid for so long, it embarrassed me, it held me back and it ruled my career for so long. &lt;br /&gt;
As you rise through the ranks you are looked upon and expected to lead from the front - to present, to protect, to persuade and to be comfortable to challenge in a room full of 2 to 200.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Shit.
&lt;br /&gt;
Why did I struggle so much with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had words to say&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it out of my Comfort zone? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comfort zone is the wrapper that’s found on a burger to keep it warm, it’s that feeling you get when you stay in bed an extra hour, it’s the moment you disagree with something in the room, whilst stood at the back leaning on the wall but say nothing - nodding your head.&lt;br /&gt;
I had to get out of it, I still have to get out of it, it’s not easy but becoming the best version of myself is not meant to be easy.
In short - you can’t get things changed and influenced from the back of the room. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting out of this zone meant breaking rules, my own rules, changing the flow of meetings and more importantly – standing up for my own beliefs and knowledge, never wanting to leave a room wishing I had said something.
It’s a constant work-in-progress, pushing myself and reminding myself that to go further I must do it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently attended a “Speak like a leader” course, this is far out of my comfort zone, standing at the front of the room and talking about topics I either knew in advance or was dropped last minute.
It made me anxious, waiting to talk - my heart beating so loud I couldn’t hear anyone else in the room. My talk going through my mind over and over again - worried I’ll mess it or or worse.. be boring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t always like this - I presented to stakeholders all the time, I had a business, I needed to do the peacock dance so often I couldn’t even guess the amount of times I’ve had to stand up and own the room.
Recalling the exact moment I knew I had lost all my confidence - I was running a workshop, it was to last 2 hours. I had it all planned out, I had bullet points, I had a playlist (of course!) - it was set up perfectly.
I also had some stakeholders in, I wanted to and had to land it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t. I really didn’t.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all walked in, I didn’t stand up, I fluffed my words, I didn’t command the room and it felt unplanned and out of control. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I feel so awkward just writing this, knowing how I felt during and after. It’s a constant memory that I try to tuck away, but it’s there - always there ready to sing and dance in my head whenever I’m in a similar situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then on, it went down and down and down hill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was 4 years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it happened, I woke up one day, found an offer of a new job, handed my notice in at work and decided I never want to be stuck in the same rut again. 
I had people telling me I had all the potential in the world, but wasn’t using it, I didn’t deliver.&lt;br /&gt;
All I ever wanted to do was inspire not only work colleagues but my family - my daughter specifically is my inspiration to change, therefore I needed to change, I need to lead by example. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the “speak like a leader” course, the first day was terrible, but something happened, I remembered that I MUST do this - not because anyone told me to do it, I MUST do this to push myself further because if I didn’t, that feeling of failure would creep in again.&lt;br /&gt;
I got on the train home and had a talk, a stern talk to myself.&lt;br /&gt;
I remembered the joy of presenting to clients trying to land that contract, leading a workshop, or the best feeling - getting a standing ovation at my wedding when I did a random(ish) talk and it landed (yes.. the groom did a talk..if you know me it won’t surprise you).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day arrived, I wanted to talk - I wanted to make everyone in the room listen to me, I had no idea what I was going to talk about, but I didn’t care.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Im unsure if you have ever suffered from this, but the feeling of frustration is one I am now using as a drive to power me forward, I want to get better, I want to perform at a level that amazes people and I want to lead, I never want someone to tell me I didn’t fulfil my potential ever again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my tip if you are in this position is to give yourself a chance, stand up and just do it, take yourself to one side and take time to evaluate what you actually want to do - have that talk and remember why or what your drive is.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am making a change, so you can make that change.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I honestly would love to hear how you have changed and what you said to yourself to get to there (or if someone else gave you THAT talk you needed), or even if you are wanting to change but unsure how.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/22/breaking-confidence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/22/breaking-confidence.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes No.13</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A really heavy week of meetings - planning for the future, and being open and transparent as possible.&lt;br /&gt;
I enjoy these type of weeks, everyone wanting to improve (as I do), and this means only one thing - motivation, which is brilliant.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t believe there is a lot to do - improving communications is key, and I fully believe this would of happened organically, but having these meetings means it’ll happen quicker and be more open and share responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First thing is a pre-planning where we run through what we expect/want in the next sprint.&lt;br /&gt;
Heavily discussed was the previously broken-communication issue amongst one project, the best ways of working and going forward.&lt;br /&gt;
I fully believe no one wants to be in this situation, and with the support of everyone we can learn a lot from this and will. We have a very strong team of people - one im very proud to be amongst, and I don’t doubt for a second that the reasons for doing the work were for the right reasons, we just didn’t let them know the “proper” process of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
9am meeting (without coffee) was a open table meeting with “team two” to discuss the best ways of working. It’s impressive that this was instigated by non-designers and their need for a smooth process and also their trust in trying out something that might be wrong is inspiring.&lt;br /&gt;
Two boards together - one is current “flight” board and on the left side is tickets “in prep” - which can be design, bugs etc - tickets to work on to be ready for “whatever sprint in the future”.&lt;br /&gt;
The output will be a constant “check in”, talking throughout the process to see if everyone is on-board with the design process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems to make sense - will be interesting to work this way, as it feels it could really make design a talking point during stand-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up in the morning where we get straight into testing the design area of the board - seemed to be really nice to talk about design and allowed others to have a say. More of this, please!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A full day of sprint reviews, retros, and planning - for the retro I HAD to mention how I really love how the chair move (designers sitting with good developers and good QAs) and how it will work out (and already showing signs of it being the best decision).
&lt;br /&gt;
Also, today is Show and Tell, since joining DWP, these have improved, but this week was the best one I’ve attended - it was clear with a great direction with good questions and even better answers.
&lt;br /&gt;
Quick note: discussions on prototype future - should we keep doing them etc, a good decision but one that will have to be cleared up eventually (but not a great rush at the moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Another sprint planning session, but this time with the “team two” team - plenty to work on for the future and a concentration on improving things for the user “life improvements”. Really excited to work on these things - as I know from speaking to the users directly they will love the soon-to-be-done fixes.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the afternoon, 1:1 catch up with one of two line manager, always good to catch up and provide updates whilst getting feedback on improving it for the week after.
&lt;br /&gt;
Followed by a leaving-do for a special person who was one of the two User Researchers in the team I worked in. A really funny and good person who helped support me during my early days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Morning - Sprint retro. Great to run through these again - honest feedback, loads of good conversations on taking the team further and it’s completely open.
Retro’s like this remind me of how important they are, facilitated well and working with a team that is good at communicating and comfortable knowing whatever is said in the room is for the good of the team and more importantly - is a safe room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Having a team as open as the two I’m in, makes me feel really excited for the future. Nothing can’t be said (within reason), and it feels like we are all going in the right direction.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I also want to give a shout out to the PO and DM calling a “ways of working” meeting, we spend 1 hour 30 minutes to discuss how can we work as a design team better (including Devs, BAs, QAs etc) - this happened, went well and I’m VERY excited by this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learned things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
How great is a place of work when the team wants to be better? Every sprint we strive to be better than the last - it not only makes us better as a team but it drags me along and makes me chomp at the bit to be better.&lt;br /&gt;THIS is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding time to work. Every two weeks the week includes a day that is pure meetings - sometimes its busy and other times its a great reminder of the work we’ve done. I must remember that it’s actually a good thing to enjoy the end-of-sprint moment, showing off our work, celebrating all work done and getting together in a room to, as mentioned before improve and cheer each other on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had to think about my past experience to discuss how I wish our design-process to be, and I didn’t use any of it - instead of making the team work together and discuss how they want to work with the design team then working back.
I love getting the answer by including everyone in it - I’m not at my best working silo, so getting everyone involved is good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 21:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/weeknotes-no13.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/16/weeknotes-no13.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
